A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day remold
the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 2      Gush Forth
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
Kurobane Station
Toya Railway
Nishinasuno Station
Tohoku Main Line
"A ravaged country still has
its untouched nature.
Spring has arrived in the capital and the grass is lush and green."
This poem really hits home for me.
Sensei, a little further down this road is the Ryogo Village.
We're looking for Masuda-san's house,
the son of the Nasu Mountains.
September 1946
Ryogo Village, Nasu County, Tochigi Prefecture
The missionary work in post-war rural Japan had begun.
Toda, with a group of his followers, traveled to Ryogo Village in Tochigi Prefecture.
Oh! Look at this!
"Toda Josei is coming!
Toda Josei is coming!
Grand Lecture on the Lotus Sutra
Time: September 22nd, 2 p.m.
Location: Ryogo Public School
Grand Lecture on the Lotus Sutra?"
Nobody here would know who Toda Josei is.
At best, the locals would be wondering,
"Now, what kind of bum is that?"
Thank you so much for coming here all the way from Tokyo.
We've been waiting for you
They say you can't fight a war if you're hungry.
Now, please help yourselves.
Thanks a bunch! We will!
This is good!
Seki-kun!
We didn't just come here to eat.
We'll be meeting the people soon,
we need to be fully prepared by then.
Okay, got it!
Ryogo Public School
At the Lotus Sutra Grand Lecture
held at the public school in Ryogo Village,
Main Hall
Lotus Sutra Grand Lecture
as many as 80 residents
of all ages and origins, from here and the neighboring villages, gathered.
It was an extremely successful lecture.
Even though people
were very confused to hear about Buddhism for the first time in their lives,
everyone was listening intently.
Finally, I would like to ask Toda Josei-sensei to conclude the lecture.
'Tis that old pops dey call Toda Josei?
I heard there was a sect called Soka Gakkai or something, who revere him as the great teacher.
Never heard of those Soka Gakkai coots.
How can our nation, crushed in battle, revive itself as a truly peace-loving nation?
The only path towards achieving that
is by grounding our way of life
in true religion and correct ideology.
It seems to me that the teachings and philosophy of Nichiren Daishonin fit that bill perfectly.
Dear friends, it appears to me that our lecture today was your first introduction to Buddhism.
But now that you know what it is,
for the happiness of your families and yourselves,
as well as for the peaceful future of Japan,
I pray that you waste no time in letting the great mercy of Buddha into your heart!
Think they'll come?
Hm... Old habits run deep in these parts...
They'll definitely come!
Think of the reaction we got from this audience.
Good evening.
Good evening!
See? They did come!
Pardon the intrusion.
Nichiren Daishonin's Scriptures
So, did you decide to give Buddhism a shot?
Yes. I want to try it.
I see. That's good.
Sensei,
this person also wishes to join.
I see. Congratulations!
We can achieve a lot together.
Thanks for having me.
Nihon Shogakkan
Man, it's hot.
It's unbearable.
Excuse me.
Oh, Izumida-kun?
Izumida Hiroshi was finally repatriated from abroad three months ago.
He was Izumida Tame's husband,
dispatched as a soldier
to the battlefields of the Southern Pacific.
It was a strange experience -
returning home without firing a single bullet,
or seeing a single man die in combat.
What's wrong? You look unhappy.
Did you quarrel with your wife again?
Y-Yes, that's what happened.
So what did you fight over?
I still haven't found a job.
And when I come home, she reproaches me for "dawdling around all day."
Not very encouraging...
And you resorted to violence?
Yes.
No, Hiroshi, that won't do.
It's simply unacceptable.
When a man is cornered by a woman,
he's immediately compelled to use violence.
But it's not the path of a Lotus Sutra follower.
I am making every effort to find a job.
But she doesn't seem to recognize that at all...
I see. But let's not forget that women also have to face the harsh reality.
She can't treat you as a real man unless you can give her a sense of security in life.
Now, more than anything else, we need to revolutionize our way of life.
Our fight only starts after we achieve that.
Don't you agree?
Yes.
Before long, Izumida got a job at a small publishing company.
At the time, people all across the country were destitute.
Food was still in very short supply.
Even getting a bowl of simple  broth was extremely difficult.
Rationing center
Meanwhile, labor disputes triggered by the announcement
Protest against layoffs!
of 130,000 layoffs by Japan National Railways
Strikes at Toshiba
gradually intensified,
plunging society into a turmoil.
Control of national media
November 17, 1946
Kanda Education Hall
Education Hall
On November 17, 1946,
Memorial service for the third anniversary of the first president Makiguchi's death
for the third anniversary of the first president Makiguchi's death, a grand memorial service
was held at the Kanda Educational Hall.
It was like an organization-wide funeral.
It was through your vast
and boundless mercy,
that you lead me to the imprisonment.
Thanks to that, I was able to read this passage from the Lotus Sutra,
In all the planes of Buddha's existence, the bond between mentor and disciple is eternal
"In all the planes of Buddha's existence, the bond between mentor and disciple is eternal."
It was what inspired me to devote my life entirely to the Common Path.
As you can see,
I, a worthless idiot,
am still going strong on your path
of fulfilling the mission of Soka Gakkai.
I am determined to become worthy of your praise by the time we meet at the Vulture Peak.
Your loyal disciple Toda Josei.
After an hour's break,
at that very same venue,
The first Soka Gakkai General Meeting
the first postwar Soka Gakkai general meeting was held.
When it comes to rewards or punishments,
it's unreasonable to think that only Buddha has the privilege to grant them.
Take, for example, humans, who live their whole lives expecting rewards or punishments.
Toda used familiar examples to provide simple and humane explanations.
He preached the great merits of Buddha
in a way that anyone would understand.
He talked about the mission of the Common Path
to build a land of peace and happiness.
I dedicated my entire life to Buddha
and to the great cause of the Common Path.
My hope is that those who share my determination
will follow me to the end of the Earth.
What do you think, gentlemen?
Yes! We'll do it!
We'll follow wherever you take us, Sensei!
We've got a great future ahead!
Soka Gakkai's operations are going to speed up tremendously now.
No matter what happens,
we'll be fearless!
Yes!
This concludes the first general meeting of Soka Gakkai.
Sensei!
Oh! Look at how you've grown, kid.
Toda-sensei!
Oh? The beautiful Nasu sisters.
I'm counting on you!
Sensei, thank you for
the wonderful meeting!
Starting today, my faith is unshakeable!
We'll fight tooth and nail
for the Common Path!
Today marks a new start for Soka Gakkai.
Makiguchi-sensei would have been happy too.
After the first general meeting, Toda's lectures on the Lotus Sutra and Nichiren's writings
on Mondays, Wednesdays, and Fridays
were growing ever more popular.
In addition to roundtable discussions held on Sunday,
extra discussions were also regularly held on Tuesdays, Thursdays, and Saturdays.
Therefore, the true nirvana
is only achieved by attaining the Buddhahood, the highest state of life.
The implicit faith in Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism is instrumental for that.
It's also very important to pray to the Great Buddha.
Those two key steps are our plan for turning Japan into a Buddhist land of happiness.
A load of bull!
You're all charlatans!
Building a Buddhist country?
Your sweet talk won't work.
I'm not buying this bullshit!
Hey!
It's okay.
Let him talk. Let us hear
everything he has to say.
What do you think is a lie and what isn't?
We'd all like to know that.
Quit shitting me!
We, the common people, have been tricked for as long as I remember myself.
"Emperor’s Army."
"Invincible Navy."
"Divine right."
"I want nothing but victory."
Humph. How sweet.
I also fell for it,
joined a pilot school
and ended up in the kamikaze corps.
We sincerely believed that if our homeland of Japan would benefit from our death,
then we should go meet our death happily!
But what do we see now?
Despite our best efforts, it lies in ruins!
When I came to my senses and reflected calmly on what I was doing,
I realized everyone had been bullshitting me!
When we were young, we'd dance to just about anyone's merry tune!
You keep saying that you were fooled.
But before you opened your eyes, you sincerely believed it all, didn't you?
I did believe it.
I believed it with all my heart.
That's what angers me the most!
As your experience demonstrates us,
blind faith may become a terrifying weapon.
Scarier than anything we've seen before.
People who believe faulty notions
are bound to fall into the depths of despair.
These are not my own words.
A Buddhist monk
Nichiren Daishonin spelled out these universal truths 700 years ago.
Now you are scared of the very thought
of believing in something.
And I understand your heart's drive to never be fooled again very well.
However,
what you also need to consider now,
is whether or not there exists something worth believing with all your heart at all.
In conclusion, I'll say that Nichiren Daishonin
worked to make people happy
by building a peaceful nation and society, grounded in rightful convictions and religion.
He preached the Buddhist teachings of Nam Myoho Renge Kyo with great conviction.
So what will Daishonin-sama gain by deceiving you?
What is worth believing at all,
if not this Dharma?
To save one young man...
To save a single common man,
Toda and other Soka Gakkai members worked hard to preach Daishonin's Buddhism.
As Toda was running around town from one roundtable discussion to another,
the society...
Strikes!
All go on a strike!
Toshiba union strikes
Joint Struggle to Begin Next Month
Establish a unification committee
All government and public sector labor unions declare joint struggle
Ultimatum expires by the 7th
Yoshida-san, stop it!!
That's all for today.
If you have any questions left,
feel free to ask. Any questions at all.
May I?
Sensei, I was recently elected
as a member of the conflict resolving committee of my company's labor union.
People are struggling to make ends meet.
With inflation raging,
and living standards deteriorating,
I believe, a direct social reform
is the most pressing issue
at the moment.
Hm. Maybe he's right.
I think so too.
Without a doubt, faith is important for our ultimate happiness...
Do you believe it's me who doesn't understand how you feel?!
My sweet disciples are fighting hard for their lives.
And if you, my dear ones,
say that you need me to be there for you,
I'll be at the forefront of demonstrations and strikes, waving red flags and whatever.
But if you think that will solve everything, you're mistaken.
If we look at it from the perspective of the Mystic Law,
this is only a fraction,
a hundredth part of the problem.
Whether it's an economic battle
or a political battle,
in the end, a compromise will be reached.
But there are more serious problems that cannot be resolved like that.
Human destiny and karma,
the flaws and shortcomings of an individual,
domestic strife,
physical and mental illnesses.
There are far more problems
that cannot be solved by a settlement.
Even if we look at society, the public,
we would subdivide them into workers, bosses, and employers.
In the end, it all starts with an individual,
and ends with one.
My point is, we must approach this problem fundamentally, focusing on the individual.
Which brings me to the importance of the law
for solving this problem as a whole.
That can only be achieved through the great religion which emphasizes the truth.
Our fight had only recently found its comfortable pace.
But a time of tremendous
turmoil is coming.
The people have yet to learn
to appreciate Daishonin's Buddhism on a profound level.
That time will come for sure.
Until then, let's all keep going strong!
Yes!
The new secondary school system will start on the 17th
Designated schools are now co-educational
Private schools with prestigious schools too
April 1st: The 6-3 system is implemented
New junior high school system begins as compulsory education
Society was becoming increasingly anxious
about inflation spiraling out of control.
A new movement toward democratization was also actively budding.
May 3rd: The Constitution of Japan comes into force, ushering in a new era for Japan
Even at the Soka Gakkai meeting led by Toda...
Okay, that's all for today.
Sensei,
I would like you to come to Kamata for a roundtable discussion in July.
In July? Hmm...
I'd love to go,
but my schedule is already packed.
How about August 14th?
That's when I'll be free.
Yes, sounds good.
Thank you very much.
Let's tell him about the roundtable discussion today, shall we, Sakata-san?
Yeah. But I gotta say, when I look at those books at Yamamoto-kun's place,
I'm always at a loss for words...
It's Carlyle, Nietzsche, Byron, and Heine, you mean that?
I was completely overwhelmed
when I first went there.
It's even more so for me.
I've heard the names before, but...
His shelves are full of books
that I've never read before.
Yamamoto
Ah, you came to see Shinichi?
Please wait a moment.
I believe he should be home now.
Hello. And welcome.
Hello, here I am again.
Certainly. Please come in.
Did you really manage to hold on to all those books throughout the war, Yamamoto-san?
Not at all.
Like I said the other day,
everything burned down in the air raid,
only the dolls survived.
I collected all these by making the rounds at used bookstores.
I see. But it must've cost a fortune, didn't it?
Sort of.
I hear these "Notes on the Theory of Life"
gained a lot of traction lately.
Yes. It seems that the news of the author, Miki Kiyoshi, dying in prison put it in the spotlight.
Yamamoto-kun seems to be a huge philosophy buff.
You can't talk to him about anything else.
But I've never studied philosophy.
What clever quip can I offer?
This pile of books
seems outright intimidating...
Ah, there are also my classmates Morishita-kun, Yamada-kun, and Ishii-kun.
All lost their homes in an air raid.
Maybe you know where to find them?
I'm sorry, I don't really know.
After my home burned down, I ended up sponging off my aunt at Magome.
Once this place was finally vacated, I returned.
That's right. Back then, everyone had to occupy themselves with their own survival.
Oh my, would you look at the time!
I need to return and help prepare dinner.
Sorry for bothering you for so long.
Ah, by the way, Yamamoto-san.
We'll be discussing philosophy
at my house on the night of the 14th.
Won't you join us?
Philosophy?
Yes, we'll talk about the philosophy of life.
Bergsonian, then?
Bergsonian?
What does that mean?
Who is the guest lecturer?
Sensei Toda Josei.
He's amazing, so make sure to come.
Toda Josei...
Is he a philosopher?
He's will talk about a philosophy that fundamentally clarifies the phenomenon of life.
I'll come pick you up.
Come on, join us!
I suppose...
I see no harm in that.
You gotta see it.
I'll come to get you too.
Okay... I'll be waiting, then.
August 14, 1947.
The time of the first meeting between Toda Josei and Yamamoto Shinichi came on this day.
Mikawa
"Rather than perform ten thousand prayers, we should eliminate this one..."
Yes, thank you.
It takes a legendary amount of courage to say something like that to a ruler.
From shogunal regents of all ranks
to the common people,
everyone respected and worshipped Amitabha during the Kamakura period.
Nichiren Daishonin alone vilified this blind faith in Nenbutsu prayers.
If anything, he determined those Nenbutsu prayers
to be the prime source
of people's unhappiness.
It seems he is talking about Buddhism,
not the philosophy of life.
How deep are these people's convictions?
Daishonin concluded his work on Rissho Ankokuron 700 years ago.
You could say it's like he left a note for the present day us, the defeated nation.
First as an individual,
then as a family,
and eventually as a country, unless we solve this by returning to the Buddha Dharma,
we'll never start on our path to Buddhahood.
Why does he look at me so much?
I want to eliminate all misery and tragedy from this world.
My way of achieving that is the Common Path.
So, will you join me on this path?
Yes! I will!
Yes!
I will!
This is amazing!
Why does it resonate with me so much?
Sensei, I brought Yamamoto Shinichi-san with me.
He was my classmate
in elementary school.
Good. Come closer, young man.
What's the good of being all the way back there?
Okay.
How old are you, Yamamoto?
I'm 19 years old.
I see. 19, huh?
Sensei, I would like you
to explain something to me.
Oh? What is it?
Sensei, what kind of life
would you describe as righteous?
The more I think about it,
the less I understand.
Now this is the mother
of all tough questions.
I don't think there is anyone in this day and age who can answer this question correctly.
However...
I can at least answer it for myself.
For some reason, I've always been a lucky man.
In my life, I had a chance to read Nichiren Daishonin's great works
on the Buddhist philosophy of life.
The rather long human lifespan
presents us with many problems along the way.
For our time, it's food shortages,
housing shortages, difficult circumstances,
accidents, and disasters.
In this life, you never know
what may happen the very next moment.
However, even these worries
are like ripples on the water
and are rather easy to overcome.
There are more fundamental problems that cannot be resolved that easily.
How should we solve the problem
of life and death in order to ensure the survival of human race?
This is it!
Life and death
Birth
Aging
Getting frail
Dying
Buddhism talks about birth, aging, getting frail, and dying,
but unless we manage to resolve this question,
the truly righteous life is unattainable.
You can apologize for being born,
but you can't help the fact
you've been born forcefully into this world.
"I want to stay a 19-year-old girl forever."
I've thought about not wanting to age many times myself.
But 40 or 50 years later,
we all become those craggy old grannies.
Well, this wasn't very thoughtful of me.
Even if I say that I will never get sick,
I still have a mortal body...
With time, it'll grow frail.
And lastly, death,
which to many is the most unpalatable.
Everyone prefers to think
that they're going to live forever.
But even the young men who are present here
won’t be alive 60 to 70 years from now.
It's no use saying
that you don't want to die.
No matter your position and your wealth,
or how strong your convictions are.
There's nothing you can do.
It is safe to say that no philosophy has ever
provided a correct and concrete solution to these important problems in life.
So, even if you want to live a life of righteousness,
in reality,
you have little to no control over it.
That said, Nichiren Daishonin has taught us how to solve all of life's difficult problems.
Moreover, he has given us specific instructions so that anyone, no matter how removed
from religion he is,
can surely attain such a state of being.
Where else in the world can such a great philosophy be found?
It seems he belongs to a sect that chants Nam Myoho Renge Kyo, but he is not a monk.
What kind of person is he?
Yamamoto-kun,
it's good to ponder the question of what a righteous life is,
but if you have the time, why don't you try to study the Daishonin's Dharma
and put it into practice?
You're still a young man.
Someday, the answer to the question
of what is a righteous life will come to you naturally,
whether you like it or not.
I can tell you this much for certain.
I would like to ask you one more thing.
What do you think about the Emperor?
Hmm. That's a good one.
Buddhist law doesn't have any special provisions
for the Emperor or the Imperial System.
I don't think there is any need
to eradicate the Japanese Emperor's family,
which has existed for generations,
nor is there any need
to give it special treatment.
The times have changed drastically.
As you can see from the new constitution,
sovereignty resides with the people,
while the Emperor remains a symbolic figure,
but I think that's fine.
The question now is how can our people,
including the Emperor,
rise up from the agony
of this defeat as soon as possible
and build a peaceful, tranquil, and cultured nation?
Isn't that right?
He came up with an answer so quickly...
And without the slightest hesitation.
I feel like I can believe his arguments.
But what kind of person is he to me?
Sensei,
thank you.
There is a proverb in the Chinese Book of Rites that says, "Even if you agree, think again,"
and "Even if you don't agree, think again."
I believe in what you said about studying and practicing as a young man,
so I will study under you.
I would like to express my gratitude now
in the form of a poem.
Even if it's a clumsy impromptu poem.
Traveler,
From whence do you come?
And where do you go?
The moon has set,
But the sun has not yet risen.
In the chaos of darkness before the dawn
Seeking the light,
I advance
To dispel the dark clouds from my mind
To find a great tree unbowed by the tempest
I gush forth from the Earth.
Yamamoto Shinichi-kun, 19 years old...
"I gush forth from the Earth."
From the earth, huh...
But I think they said Yamamoto-kun
suffers from a lung disease.
No, he'll be fine. He's only 19.
Ah, the sweet age of 19.
I was still in Hokkaido.
In Mayachi, Yubari county...
Yubari, Mayachi
Mayachi Elementary School
Then, when I was 20 years old,
I moved to Tokyo.
I'm 47 years old now, Yamamoto-kun is 19 years old, almost 20 actually...
In ten more days, on August 24th,
Young Yamamoto joined the Soka Gakkai,
setting a new stage for the Common Path
at the turning point of history and time.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
Typesetting, QC
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr
Muzussawa, True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 2
The End