The great human revolution, occurring in one -
before long, it'll define the fate of the nation.
Furthermore, it could one day remold
the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 5     Sturm und Drang
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
Autumn 1949
October 1st: People's Republic of China is proclaimed in Beijing by supreme chairman Mao Zedong
In October, "The Sad Whistle" starring Misora ​​Hibari becomes an overnight sensation
November 3rd: Hideki Yukawa becomes the first ever Japanese winner of the Nobel Prize in Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
There!
Toko Credit Cooperative
Soka Gakkai Headquarters
We're finally starting this new business!
The very thought of doing it on my own
sends me shuddering!
Whoa, will you really be able to handle this?
We'll need you guys
to do your best from now on.
Right, I remember...
December 1st:
Toda's new financial business,
Toko Credit Cooperative,
begins operations.
As the executive director of the credit union,
Toda was essentially in charge of all aspects of management,
was burning with a strong determination to get the business back on track
and make it a success this time around.
March 1950
As a sales and negotiations employee at a credit union,
Yamamoto Shinichi traveled around town trying to get people to make a deposit at Toko,
but finance was never really
Shinichi's cup of tea,
and it was the one job
he couldn't stomach.
Still...
if Toda-sensei thought it necessary and decided to proceed with it,
I also have to do whatever I can.
I'll fight tooth and nail for the rebirth of sensei's business.
Around this time, the effects of the government's enforced
June
implementation of the Nine Principles for Economic Stability were evident ubiquitously.
Not only did large companies had to cut back operations,
small and medium-sized companies also saw
a stream of bankruptcies that started last year
and peaked in the first half of 1950.
How inhumane... The full burden of the recession has fallen on small and medium-sized businesses.
The companies we've lent to are becoming insolvent in quick succession.
And even those who don't are asking us for a grace period on their repayment more and more.
If things continue like this,
even if our books are in the black,
we may fall short of the critical cash needed for withdrawals.
The world is certainly strapped for money right now.
So much so nobody has any
to put into savings.
But if we can't survive through this,
then we aren't worth our salt.
We have some breaking news!
It appears that fighting has broken out
across the 38th parallel
on the Korean Peninsula early this morning!
Allow me to repeat.
It appears that fighting broke out early this morning on the Korean Peninsula
On June 25, 1950, the Korean War broke out!
all across the 38th parallel!
What's takin' you so long?!
Are you asleep?
Hurry up!
I was here first!
No way!
The hell was that?
What's going on...?
No deposits, all withdrawals!
If this continues, we'll run out of cash!
Sensei, at this rate,
a bank run seems more than likely.
Ever since the war in Korea broke out,
we've had nothing but deposit withdrawals for three days straight.
The memory of postwar bank deposit freezes
was still fresh in the Japanese minds.
February 1946: The Japanese government promulgates the Financial Emergency Measures Order
For that reason, out of fear that Japan might be drawn into a war in the neighboring country,
"Citizens' deposits are frozen"
the people were dead-set on keeping the money to themselves.
That's the thing, Sensei.
If we don't do something about it,
it'll turn real bad real quick!
We are already running low on cash on hand.
Yes. I understand.
Please take immediate action.
I'm counting on you.
But what can I do...?
I can't count on the credit union managers to handle it well.
Is there any way I can help it...
Hold up...
A merger!
That's right! That is still an option.
We have no choice but to merge with some union that found itself in a better spot.
If we manage to do that, even if it means putting myself and the union at a disadvantage,
at the very least, it'll spare our depositors any extra worry.
Okumura-kun,
in the face of our credit union's current predicament,
the decision has been made at the board meeting to merge with another union.
Huh?!
We have to proceed in secret.
I'll manage the merger myself.
Until that is concluded,
I need you to hold out no matter what.
Understood. I'll see what I can do.
All that work for nothing...
How did it come to this?
Things are making a 180 before our eyes.
What to do next?
Yes, come in.
We're back.
Oh, well done.
How did it go?
They turned us away everywhere,
no matter how many times we asked.
I see. Nobody wants to bail us out?
I'm also completely helpless.
I guess...
we'll have to resort to merger, won't we?
They wouldn't even listen to me.
We're being completely stonewalled.
Hey, that's not good!
The company's position might just be
even more precarious than it seemed to me.
I've never seen Toda-sensei so distressed.
Les Miserables
Coming home after midnight again?
Really, I didn't even realize how much it hurt sensei...
I feel ashamed that it never even crossed my mind.
I must do whatever I can for sensei.
I must stay strong for him...
When the going gets tough,
the tough get going.
Toda made every effort
to resolve the situation,
including asking the Ministry of Finance,
the regulatory agency,
to mediate their merger with another credit union.
August 22nd
This arrived from
the Ministry of Finance today.
A "cease operations" notice.
Effective tomorrow the 23rd.
Signed by the Minister of Finance himself.
Huh? No way!
What'd I tell you?
Therefore, starting tomorrow, Toko Credit Cooperative will cease all operations
and initiate the bankruptcy proceedings.
That's all I needed to tell you about.
And now, a word from the president.
As you just heard,
we have no choice, but to dissolve
the Toko Credit Cooperative tomorrow.
I'd like to apologize to everyone.
I know you all worked hard for the union,
yet I failed to preserve it.
There was nothing you could do to stop it.
Blame all the responsibility on me!
You all have done so much for me
in our turbulent times.
Allow me to thank you once again.
The next day
Sensei!
What is it?
A reporter from Toto News has come,
saying he wants to meet you.
I told him you were away,
but he just won't go home.
Very well.
Let's meet him.
One moment, Sensei. He came here after hearing about us shutting down.
I also overheard that reporter
calling his boss earlier:
"I've got a hella scoop coming,
just you wait!"
I see.
What should I do?
The board meeting is about to begin.
Sensei. Allow me to meet him
on your behalf today.
Yes, sounds good.
I'm counting on you to handle it here.
By the way, how many
depositors do you have?
I know asking to know the total amount of damages is kinda out of the left field...
But how much in debt are you now?
This man is in a hurry to meet the manuscript deadline.
I need to buy us some time...
So, what'll it be?
You're right.
I believe it to be quite a substantial amount.
It was just yesterday, so only the executive director can tell us the exact details.
But he's away, isn't he? A rough estimate will suffice. Just to know the general trend, is all.
But aren't accuracy and precision
supposed to be the essence of journalism?
Yes, I guess they are. But you know, time waits for no one. Roughs will do for now.
So what'll it be?
I guarantee you'll like my article.
That is my hope.
I must say you were quite quick to get here.
Other newspaper hadn't sent their journalists here as of yet.
That's cause I have an excellent intuition.
Shinichi's delaying strategy worked.
Eventually, the reporter ran out of time
to deliver the scoop he promised.
It was moved to the next day.
I guess I'll just come again tomorrow to ask your executive director for numbers, Yamamoto-san.
Which means, if you collect all of these unpaid debts,
you'd be able to cover all your obligations?
Correct. However, we can't do that in a snap of a finger, so we have to bid for time here.
Oh, so that's what you mean?
The world in unaware of the true state of things right now, Aoyama-san.
I don't mean to encroach on your newspaper's right to print anything they want.
Huh?
When word of the cease-and-desist order hit the newspapers, creditors rushed in all at once.
Meanwhile, debtors just thought "lucky me, I don't have to pay back my debt anymore."
When this happens,
things tend to truly go out of hand.
In the end, it's the ordinary depositors
who suffer the most from it.
It's a regrettable situation,
because we were confident that we would be able to pay our debts off.
If I go ahead and submit it now,
I could end up ruining a lot of people's lives.
Man, I'm in a pickle...
Let me put this straight:
you now wield a complete authority over the life or death of our credit union.
The rest is up to you.
What strong words, sensei!
A single sentence to drive a wedge so deep into one's soul...
What is Aoyama going to do?
Ugh, fine, I understand!
We'll wait a while before publishing this.
Today we got one journalist
to postpone his article...
But we're not out of the woods just yet.
It is highly likely that another newspaper
will also try to pursue this.
The crisis is averted for now.
But what should I do
to protect sensei from now on?
Shin!
Yes!
The sway that newspapers hold over people's minds is amazing nowadays.
They can be a real nuisance if they want to.
But that also why having even a single newspaper of your own is a very powerful asset.
Do you understand?
Yes.
I'll keep that in mind.
We also need to start a newspaper for Soka Gakkai as soon as we have the chance.
Please think it over, Shin.
Okay.
In our days, Seikyo Shimbun
rose to the position
of the world's largest religious bulletin.
The idea for its publication
was actually conceived during this turbulent period.
Police headquarters
It's here,
where Makiguchi-sensei and I
were once imprisoned for the crime we didn't commit.
Those in power will always
abuse it for their own convenience.
Underestimating the power this time around
would be a grave mistake.
No matter how much flak I personally receive for the collapse of the credit union,
no matter how much the authorities
or the law are after me, it won't stop me.
I'm prepared for anything.
However, I can't put Soka Gakkai in harm's way,
while they're busy spreading the Common Path.
No matter what happens,
I must protect the organization at any cost!
For that purpose...
In conclusion, faith, practice, and study
are our three priorities.
The combination of practice and study
is what constitutes your piety.
Let's all keep that in mind.
Well, that's all for today.
Tonight, I would like you all to listen carefully to what I have to say.
This is a personal matter that has nothing to do with you directly, but I'd like you to know,
our credit union
ceased operations yesterday.
Huh? Seriously?
What happened?
It fell to me to clean up
the mess that remained afterwards.
Again, it has nothing to do with Soka Gakkai,
but it puts me personally into a fix.
After a short consideration,
I've arrived at a conclusion.
I have to resign from my position
as the president from today on.
Huh?!
Sensei resigns? But why?
I'm going to ask Mishima Yoshizo-kun
to take over as the board chairman.
It absolutely doesn't mean
I've given up on my faith.
My resolve to devote myself to the great cause of the Common Path is still unwavering.
On the contrary, it's this very resolve
that makes me meet those tribulations head-on!
I can't believe how short-sighted I've been.
I never realized how hard it was for Sensei,
who's struggling with his business...
However...
Why must he resign as the president?
No matter what happens to me from now on,
Soka Gakkai must absolutely hold steady
and stay true to its journey.
You must not let the change of leadership
upset you in the slightest!
I have also prepared myself fully
for what is to come.
"Prepared himself for what's to come?"
What could that mean?
Is he going to do something radical?
Well then...
It's better this way.
Forgive me, everyone.
It's the only way to preserve
Soka Gakkai intact.
Sensei is Soka Gakkai itself.
Under no circumstances, can I imagine Soka Gakkai without Toda-sensei.
Yamamoto here. May I?
Yeah. Go ahead.
Well, now... What's wrong?
Come on, take a seat.
Sensei...
What is it?
Sensei... If Mishima-san becomes the next president, will that make him my mentor?
No, by no means!
I may not be the most accommodating mentor,
but I am your mentor.
That's all I needed to hear...
Now I don't have to worry about anything else,
no matter what happens.
Shin is a very noble fellow
to care about even such a trifle.
My lifelong mentor is...
Toda-sensei!
Yes. This is enough for me.
This day, August 24th, was Yamamoto Shinichi's 3rd anniversary as a member of Soka Gakkai.
Yeah! Good luck!
Toko Credit Cooperative
I'm off!
Yeah. See you, then.
Bye!
I'm counting on you, everyone.
From the next day on, Toda started working on liquidating the credit union.
At this point, several more employees left the company
and Toda had very few personnel remaining in his command.
It's 10 already... I've been to eight houses and only one agreed...
You're up so late, Sensei!
Oh, there you are.
I've been waiting.
Let's go home together.
It's late, so you can stay at my house.
Here, cider for Yamamoto-san.
Thank you.
Say, Shin, how about a match of shogi?
It's so late, what are you thinking?
Don't worry. You can go to sleep.
Shin-chan, bring out the board.
O-Okay...
Okay, let's play just one for tonight.
With pleasure.
Ugh! How about this move, then?
Looks good enough to me.
Here.
Here!
The credit union fell through, and he had to resign as the president of Soka Gakkai...
Yet here he is, completely engrossed by a game of shogi.
When I see him like this, our every predicament feels like a joke or a distant dream.
Our current distresses
are only temporary.
This might just be the Sensei's true form.
Shin-chan, thinking about unnecessary things doesn't do favors to your concentration!
When you're having fun, enjoy it wholly.
That way, when the battle comes,
you'd be well-rested.
Okay. Then, how about here?
Oh-ho! This is my answer, then!
Give me my money back!
Toko Credit Cooperative
How are you gonna settle it?!
When will I receive my deposit already?
How long do I have to wait?!
Uchiyama-kun, please bring the account books to the conference room on the mezzanine floor.
I believe, I owe everyone an explanation.
Oh... Okay.
Precisely.
If we manage to collect all these dues from our lenders, we'll be able to repay you all. However...
not right now.
I merely ask you to understand that.
No, I don't want any of that.
I just need my money, right goddamn now!
Why don't you just get the money
to pay me back in full?!
He's right!
Pay us back!
This instant!
Kishida Co., Ltd.
Toda visited Kishida, an old friend,
at his company's office.
Kishida was running
a wide range of businesses.
The two were close friends who helped each other on my occasions.
Okay, I understand.
You have my support.
I don't like the idea
of funding the liquidation,
but I'd be happy to give you money to start a new business.
Thank you, Kishida-kun.
You're one of the few men I can trust.
You can pay me back
when you start making profits.
You're a lifesaver for that.
I appreciate it, truly.
Wages continued to be delayed, and now even the employees who fought hard so far
Toko Credit Cooperative
Letter of resignation
were leaving the company one by one.
This means our sales department is just Sato-kun and Yamamoto-kun now.
I don't feel too well,
I think I got a fever again.
How was your political science exam?
Ah, aren't you asking 'cause you wound through it all?
I want to study too.
Once our current troubles are over and things settle down, I'll return to Taisei Academy.
I'm back.
How did it go?
Five families agreed to make a deposit today.
You've done well.
Sensei looks so tired...
Toda remained composed through all the hardships he endured,
but his emaciation was now impossible to conceal.
Shinichi was also thoroughly exhausted by it.
What's the matter?
You don't look so good.
No, I'm fine...
What's wrong, Shin?
Is your inner strength waning?
You can't win a battle
if your inner strength is in decline.
Come.
The emaciated and haggard Master offered an earnest prayer to the Buddha
for the sake of his haggard
and beloved disciple.
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
Although Sensei is so tired himself,
he is praying for my strength.
Sensei... I'm sorry for being such a nuisance.
And I'm deeply grateful!
Beethoven's Symphony No. 5 in C minor,
"The Fate Symphony"
Even if it's just me,
I will serve and protect Toda-sensei
for the rest of my life.
That is my mission and fate!
This should be good enough.
I'll give it to him tomorrow morning.
Good morning, Sensei!
Oh, good morning.
Shin, did you rest well yesterday?
We can't have you lose any more weight.
Yes, sir. Thank you.
But I'd rather you
take at least a brief break.
Please.
All right.
Sensei... This is for you.
Oh! What do we have here?
"Still serving an old and mystic fate,
Though others change,
I alter not.”
Still serving an old and mystic fate,
Though others change,
I alter not.
Yes. I understand.
I really do.
Thank you, Shin!
All right, I’ll write a poem too,
a reply poem.
Now then...
"Whenever I stand on fields of war,
Unfailing at my side,
You are my sword.”
I'll give you this.
Thank you.
Wait a second,
one more verse to go with that.
"Fading, failing,
At death, I the king leave to you
My crown."
There, that should be it.
Whenever I stand on fields of war,
Unfailing at my side,
You are my sword.
Fading, failing,
At death, I the king leave to you
My crown.
- Josei
Will I really be able to become his sword?
Will I ever be worthy of Sensei's crown?
Sensei...
Thank you!
Shin-chan, let's take a short walk.
Okay.
I've made a terrible mistake,
and what is happening now is my major punishment from Nichiren Daishonin.
Huh?
No, never mind that...
I am quite certain that I've made some terrible mistakes.
Firstly, while teaching everyone the Lotus Sutra, I mixed in the Tendai interpretation.
Secondly, the position of Soka Gakkai president
remained formally vacant for five years
after Makiguchi-sensei's death.
Finally, I was so single-minded
on bolstering our economic strength
that I put the advancement of Soka Gakkai
and the fundamental issue of religious revolution on the back burner.
It is only natural that I should reap the wrath of Nichiren Daishonin.
Shin-chan, I made up my mind.
I am now going to pray to the Kind Buddha for repentance and atonement of my sins.
What falls on the ground
can only rise up from the ground.
And the way to do it is through faith.
Shin-chan, I'll be tutoring you in all of your college studies, starting next Sunday.
Come to my house. We must fulfill
your academic aspirations.
Okay!
After this, Toda started his new company
and the liquidation work proceeded steadily.
There was finally an end in sight to the problems that have been plaguing
the credit union for the past several months.
It was this profound and firm master-disciple bond that Toda Josei and Yamamoto Shinichi
formed through long, arduous,
and devoted struggles for their faith,
which became the catalyst for
Soka Gakkai's rapid growth in our time
and a source of inspiration for all who work hard for its sake, continuing to live on today.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing & Typesetting
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Collectr
Muzussawa, True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 5
The End