The great human revolution, occurring in one -
before long, it'll define the fate of the nation.
Furthermore, it could one day remold
the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 9
Suikoden Oath
Original work: Daisaku Ikeda
June, 1953
Daito Trading
Introduction to Law
As it says here,
the law always has two sides to it.
What I mean is, it could either be something that constrains people
or something that keeps society functioning smoothly.
Even if the provisions are the same, various interpretations lead to vastly different effects.
Therein lies the horror of the law.
At Daito Trading, Toda would dedicate about an hour each morning before work
to teaching the few employees the fundamentals of both general and specialized knowledge.
Naturally, his lectures were directed
at Yamamoto Shinichi before anyone else.
That's because Toda considered
Shinichi's training his personal responsibility.
During the Qin Dynasty in China, the people suffered under a maze of cumbersome laws.
Understanding this, Liu Bang, the "High Ancestor of Han,"
Liu Bang, the "High Ancestor of Han"
swiftly won the hearts and minds of the people when establishing the dynasty
with his concise "Three Laws,"
which declared: "Those who kill, injure, and steal will be punished."
You could call this a perfect example of how to approach lawmaking.
Sensei seems to have everything in the palm of his hand.
Let's call it enough for today.
Any questions?
Sensei, Suikokai is meeting tonight.
I look forward to listening to your lecture.
Yes, I know.
Suikokai Meeting
Sensei!
Whether there was an occasion or not,
the heroes of Mount Liang would roast sheep and cattle
and throw lavish feasts featuring delicacies from both land and sea.
Is this a common custom in China?
You're right.
The Mount Liang band was a festive bunch,
always eating and drinking in abundance.
I can drink just as much as they do,
but there's no way I could ever eat that much.
Japanese sake is made from rice,
so it's a good source of nutrients in its own right.
In China, they drink a liquor called Liaojiu,
but it isn't fermented from rice...
A Suikokai meeting was proceeding as usual.
While answering a question, Toda happened to steer the conversation to the topic of alcohol.
At that moment, one of the new Suikokai members suddenly stood up and began speaking.
Sensei!
In China, they also have the Kaoliang liquor,
and it's a lot different from Liaojiu!
Yes, I suppose it is different.
Kaoliang seems to be a very strong drink.
I was raised in China,
so I’ve heard plenty about Chinese alcohol.
You can ferment Kaoliang
from just about anything, it seems.
What the hell is he thinking?
Does he have any idea what it means to attend this meeting?
Sensei, there's also the apple cider.
Do you know how they make that?
Oh no!
Did you...
come here to discuss how to make alcohol?
What do you think this meeting is all about?
This is my fault.
I prepared this meeting in haste.
I don't welcome it.
You should leave.
Get out!
Who do you think let Suikokai come to this?
Aren't you all responsible for it?
One of us is leaving on his own.
What a shame.
Whatever happened to your sense of camaraderie?!
This is a disgrace!
I'm leaving.
Sensei, please forgive us!
Please forgive us!
Please forgive us, if only possible!
It wasn't on a whim that Toda-sensei reprimanded him.
He must have been frustrated that the students, entrusted with the future,
let a complacent atmosphere develop in Suikokai, which led to someone
going on an escapade like that.
What's worse,
we Suikokai executives
lacked the unity and determination to protect one of our own.
I can only imagine how much it must have saddened him.
Our membership is currently going through explosive growth.
I have no doubt that Japan will embrace Soka Gakkai, and the rest of the world will follow.
To prepare for that time,
we must now train those young people
to become excellent leaders.
The ordinary young man today
may grow into a peerless leader in 10, 20, or 30 years, ensuring the success of the Common Path.
I believe this, and I look forward
to every Suikokai meeting with all my heart.
But I certainly didn’t expect to see it become so corrupted in just six months...
What on earth are the executives thinking?
Sensei had high hopes for the Suikoden, saying, "We will raise the revolutionaries of the future."
It should come as no surprise he was so disappointed by this.
Who do you think let Suikokai come to this?
I suppose no amount of apology could ever make it up to him...
What should I do?
I wonder if the others grasped why I was so harsh in scolding them.
Shinichi was there. If anyone can truly understand my heart, it's him.
Omori Station
Sensei's anger is entirely my fault.
Using my poor health as an excuse,
I failed to take the necessary precautions.
That said, how should I go about embracing Sensei's loving discipline?
How can we reshape the heart of the Men's Division?
Until we do that, everything is pointless...
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
Shinichi's apartment "Shuzanso"
What is it Suikokai is missing?
I beg you to let us know!
Yes!
It's the starting point!
Suikokai never had a clear starting point to explain its raison d'etre!
So at some point, we became complacent,
swept away by the feeling
that it was enough to just listen to Sensei's lectures and feel good.
From the very start, Sensei took a very thorough stance about our education.
However, the members attending the course
stayed unaware of or uncommitted
to the purpose and mission of the Suikokai.
It was only natural
that there would be gaps.
Sensei's dedication was so strong that the gap in awareness became glaringly obvious.
The cider question
was never the main problem...
That atmosphere of complacency was!
The fact that such an atmosphere
had been so easily accepted in Suikokai
would lead to its downfall.
Leaving Suikokai as it is now would be an affront to Sensei.
We must hurry to reorganize and restart it on a completely new foundation as soon as possible.
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
But what could form the backbone
of that new foundation?
The Great Buddha,
please show me the way!
At this time in Japan, Okinawa was rapidly being turned into a military base.
Even after the San Francisco Peace Treaty was signed,
The American Civil Government of the Ryukyu Islands issues the Okinawa Land Acquisition Ordinance
the United States continued to occupy and govern Okinawa directly.
In April 1953, aiming to further expand and strengthen their military presence,
they issued the Land Acquisition Ordinance,
which allowed the US to seize farmland one after another to build bases across various locations.
Thus, Okinawa will become one of the few massive, permanent military bases in the world.
In July, a ceasefire agreement was signed at Panmunjom
on the 38th parallel by representatives of the UN and the Korean People's Army,
bringing the Korean War—which had deeply shaken Japan—
to a conclusion after three years and one month.
Armistice signed this morning by Harrison and Nam, chief representatives of both sides
The Korean peninsula will remain divided between the North and South,
and the conflict will continue to simmer.
The biggest challenge right now is improving the resolve and mentality of the Suikokai members.
It all boils down to this.
What is needed to improve their mentality?
What qualities are required
to be a Common Path revolutionary?
First and foremost, you need to be a man of strong faith. It's as clear as day.
Secondly,
you must have a very clear idea of what it means to be Toda-sensei's disciple.
Finally...
Whatever happened to your sense of camaraderie?!
That's right!
We must bolster our camaraderie.
Yes.
These three qualities are what make someone a true revolutionary of the Mystic Law.
I will write an oath for Suikokai members
based on these three pillars.
And then we'll take this oath
before Toda-sensei!
Daito Trading
Sensei, I would like you to read this.
What is it about?
It's about the Suikokai.
Hmm...
He compiled it in the form of an oath.
Okay, I'll forgive you just this once.
Thank you!
However, I will never again
tolerate a gathering
of indifferent old men who aren't there to seek the truth!
Making the same mistake twice is something only a fool would do.
Got it!
So when will you start?
Sensei, I would like
to ask for a grace period.
I need it to select young men and women worthy of the oath.
I would ask you to wait for a week more.
Sure, I'll wait if you want me to,
but I expect them to be truly worthwhile.
Toshima Public Hall, Ikebukuro
Toda dedicated himself to promoting education to ensure that his lectures
General lectures (Friday lectures)
reached and benefited as many Soka Gakkai members as possible.
One of their study forums was the general lectures, also known as "Friday Lectures"
because they were held every Friday.
President Toda explained passages from the Sacred Scriptures,
welcoming anyone with genuine interest
to participate, whether they were newcomers or regulars.
The newly completed Toshima Public Hall,
finished this spring and able to accommodate 2,000 people, would quickly fill up.
Oh, it's getting pretty crowded in here.
Actually,
those standing around
should come up to the stage.
That way, a bit more people will be able to come in.
In his lectures on the Sacred Scriptures,
Toda endeavored to explain the complex doctrines of Buddhism in a simple way
by connecting them to social phenomena and everyday life.
At times, the lectures
turned into Q&A sessions.
Toda was at complete freedom to give his lectures in whatever form he wished.
You asked me about the relationship between science and religion.
Science and true religion
are never in conflict.
Certainly, we can't downplay the scientific advances.
Take, for example, electricity.
It powers my microphone,
or the speakers you're hearing me through.
Washing machines
are also quite convenient.
So are the TVs.
They're actually near perfect.
On the other hand, if we can't afford these modern conveniences, we feel unhappy.
When your friend buys one and you can't afford it, it makes you feel miserable.
Yes! He's right!
Moreover, when science is taken to the extreme
and employed to create such devastating weapons as atomic or hydrogen bomb,
it becomes clear that science is also contributing to the systematic suffering of mankind.
I am by no means a denier of science.
It is undoubtedly good.
But I do deny the notion
that the advancement of science alone will instantly bring happiness to humanity.
I see... That makes sense!
I do believe that we can lead science and civilization in the right direction
and develop a religion based on the philosophy of life,
by studying and practicing
the Buddha Dharma.
Only by cultivating an independent self that isn't swayed by our surroundings
can we achieve true happiness
for the first time.
Sensei, please look at this.
Yes, what is it?
Sir, I've completed selecting the Suikokai members.
Oh, it's finally here?
Yes.
Let's see...
It doesn't seem all that different from what we had before, but it'll do.
So, when do we start?
Whenever you find it convenient.
Hmm... I haven't got much free time.
If I had to choose,
it would be July 21st.
Sounds good by you?
Yes! Thank you.
July 21st, Soka Gakkai Headquarters
"New Suikokai" formation ceremony
We shall now commence the reformation ceremony for the New Suikokai.
First Manager Yamamoto takes the oath.
Okay!
Oath!
First:
we, the Suikokai members,
dedicate our lives to the religious revolution.
With unity of mind and body,
Unity of mind and body
may we complete the great mission
of spreading the Common Path in the Orient.
I hereby pledge my devotion to the Great Buddha!
Second:
We, the members of Suikokai,
have inherited the cause
of Toda Josei-sensei,
which is the ultimate salvation of humanity.
I solemnly vow to fight for the fulfillment of his vision until my last breath.
Third: we, Suikokai members,
are the trailblazers of Soka Gakkai.
We do realize that we are Toda-sensei's irreplaceable hands and emissaries.
No matter what era we live in or what battlefield we fight on,
we will never turn our backs on our comrades!
I pledge to uphold all of the above and fulfill the mission of Suikokai!
Good.
Sensei, all of us Suikokai members have subscribed to this oath.
Please accept it
All right. I will accept your determination.
Thank you!
We'll be holding the New Suikokai meetings again from today on.
As I said before, the purpose of Suikokai
is to fulfill the great task that lies ahead for Soka Gakkai: spreading the Common Path.
The Common Path
is an unprecedented undertaking,
aimed at fundamentally saving humanity and bringing it lasting happiness.
It's the humanity's greatest wish and hope.
It falls to you to be the trailblazers for the Common Path.
If you're able to commit to this,
then I can finally place all my hopes for the future on you!
I count on you to never forget that!
Okay!
Thus, Suikokai, which had once run aground,
has now been revitalized and reborn as a core force driving the Common Path forward.
They should start gathering soon...
Okay...
I'll go next door for a consultation session now.
Soka Gakkai Ichigaya Branch
Ah, Sensei! Good afternoon.
Yes, hello. Let's start now.
In the afternoon,
Toda came to this branch office
and personally counseled the members until the evening.
As always, the room was filled with people seeking Toda's guidance for their life issues.
What happened?
Please, sensei.
This is about my son.
He has hemophilia, so his mouth is always bleeding and there is nothing we can do.
Hmm...
These days, when we make bread, the white bread would sometimes turn deep red.
Open your mouth, for a moment, kid.
Hemophilia is a genetic congenital disorder characterized by an extremely weak clotting ability of platelets, making it difficult to stop bleeding without medical intervention once a patient begins to bleed.
So, what do the doctors say?
Well, the doctors said there is no treatment for this disorder.
Aw, what a burdensome disorder.
When did you join Soka Gakkai?
In April of last year, sir.
The Buddha lavished us with his grace over the past year.
But when I think about my son,
I feel really helpless...
This woman divorced her husband before joining Soka Gakkai.
She struggled with four children and recently lost her eldest son, also to hemophilia.
She lived her life to the fullest, heroically...
We should leave the curable diseases to the doctors.
But what should we do about illnesses that the doctors can't cure?
This is a major problem.
There are many diseases that the doctors simply cannot help you with.
We call them incurable, but maybe there's more to them than meets the eye.
Their cause lies in karma,
and only through piety can we as a society
get to the root of the problem.
I'm glad you've embraced the Great Buddha,
whose power is immense.
You should continue walking your path steadily.
Okay...
The more you pray to Buddha,
the more the fundamental power of life will flow into your body.
How can there be something incurable?
I can tell you were taking your faith seriously even without my counsel.
What I want you to promise me is that you will never let your faith wane for the rest of your life.
If you find that kind of resolve
within yourself,
the Mystic Law will soon manifest itself in one form or another.
Can you do that?
You must stay strong for your son.
Yes! Thank you so much.
A few days later, the joyful news of her child's dramatic improvement will reach Toda.
Thank you!
Well...
When I talk to my friends about faith,
they say, "Isn't Soka Gakkai just an almshouse for the sick and poor?"
It's so frustrating...
How should I refute it?
What's bad about being for the sick and poor?
A large portion of the problems people face today are illness and poverty.
If we can neither help people nor resolve these problems, then what kind of religion are we?
You're right...
Where else in the world today
can the sick and poor find shelter...
If not with us, Soka Gakkai?
Ask them, "What's wrong with being the place for the poor and sick?"
The joyful voices of those who have found relief from their worries and suffering through faith
will resonate throughout the country, eventually
creating a powerful wave of demand for Buddhism that will sweep across all of Japan.
I can already see it clearly!
In August, the summer regional training program, which had become an annual tradition,
was actively held in Osaka, Nagoya, Kyushu,
and, more recently, Hokkaido
was also added to the list.
Hakodate, Hokkaido
In each of the four areas, at least 415 households were converted that month,
further boosting the members' fervor for the spread of the Common Path.
Published weekly starting from this issue
In September, the Seikyo Shimbun, previously published every ten days,
became a weekly publication.
The circulation also surged to 21,000 copies,
quadrupling the number at the time of its initial publication two years earlier.
It was a great joy for the members
actively involved in spreading the teachings.
Shinjuku Ward, Shinanomachi area
Then, what happened was...
What do you think?
It's this way.
This seems like a quiet residential area.
Yes. And being only three minutes from the station, the location is great.
Yes, I suppose.
This is the building I had in mind.
My, isn't it wonderful?
Yes... Perfect for the new headquarters.
Membership surged, and the Common Path activities were constantly on the rise.
The small Nishi-Kanda headquarters
could no longer accommodate it.
The establishment of a new Soka Gakkai headquarters became an urgent issue.
That's when a foreign ambassador's residence went up for sale.
Shinanomachi suddenly became a solid candidate site for the new headquarters.
I'd like to hear everyone's opinions on whether or not I should buy
the building we went to see today.
I think you should absolutely buy it.
The location, the size,
and the appearances are ideal.
I agree, especially since it's just a three-minute walk from the station.
I see. Everyone seems to be on board with the purchase.
All right, let's do it!
Capital!
November 13th
Moved to new headquarters
Soka Gakkai
How spacious is this hall, compared to the headquarters in Nishi-Kanda!
Don't you all agree?
Yes!
But maybe that's just how we feel for now.
Soka Gakkai expands rapidly.
It won't be long before this room
starts to feel small too.
In any case, a first step in a new direction has been made.
Today, I want us all to rejoice together to the fullest.
November 17th
Memorial service for the 10th anniversary of the death of the first president Makiguchi
On November 17th, four days after moving to the new headquarters,
the 10th anniversary memorial service
for the first president, Makiguchi Tsunesaburo, was held in the main hall.
I often stayed at Sensei's house until one or two in the night.
His wife would often say,
"You scholars sure do love to talk at length."
Sometimes I'd fall asleep
before we could finish.
Makiguchi-sensei was a truly single-minded and serious man.
For example, the well-known sociologist
Professor Tanabe wrote the following in the preface
to Makiguchi-sensei's "The Soka System of Education," published in 1930:
"Makiguchi Tsunesaburo,
an elementary school principal,
dedicated his life to fighting
against all forms of persecution and adversity,
ultimately completing his groundbreaking work, the Soka Pedagogy System.
How can Japan,
a nation of culture,
ever repay this great educator,
who is truly the pride of the nation?"
Yet, the way the Japanese state chose to handle Sensei's talent was
by imprisoning him until his death!
As his disciple,
I knew it was my duty to make the world acknowledge
the great philosophy Sensei left behind.
Value Theory, by Makiguchi Tsunesaburo, revised by his follower, Toda Josei
To that end, I have decided to publish this "Value Theory,"
which I withheld from the public eye for the last ten years.
A value system of "Beautiful, Helpful, and Good"—
Beautiful, Helpful, Good
this is the philosophy we must make the world recognize as our path forward!
If my lifetime isn’t enough,
I’m relying on you to see it through!
Thank you.
Okay!
As Makiguchi's sole surviving disciple,
Toda eagerly awaited
the day when the "Value Theory" would finally be published.
Later, he would donate the book to universities across Japan
and send its English translations to institutions worldwide.
Hoshi Pharmaceutical University Auditorium in Gotanda
On December 23rd,
just before the end of the year,
December 23rd
2nd General Meeting of the Men's Youth Division
the 2nd General Meeting of the Men's Youth Division was held
at the Hoshi Pharmaceutical University Auditorium.
This was the second general meeting,
the first one took place in April of that year.
How should we proceed with our work on the Common Path?
The answer to that is
"with a diverse workforce."
Moving forward is impossible without valuable specialists
from all levels and sectors
of society on our side.
Those in their 40s and 50s today are unfit for that.
We have to let the youth take charge.
All I want is for each of you
to develop into the remarkable individuals who will serve as the pillars of society!
I won't give a winding speech today.
Let's wrap it up here.
At this general meeting, Yamamoto Shinichi
reiterated the three pledges they made when Suikokai was reestablished.
Oath to the Great Buddha and to Soka Gakkai,
Oath to President Toda,
and Oath of Camaraderie.
And now, all Men's Division members also took this Suikoden Oath.
Soka Gakkai
The year's almost over, Shin-Chan.
Yes.
We've fought well beyond our goals this past year.
With more people upholding the righteous teachings,
Japan will become a little more prosperous.
Yes.
I'm eager to build a peaceful society where everyone can live happily and in harmony.
We should work even harder next year.
I'm counting on you, Shin-Chan.
Okay!
Yamamoto Shinichi solemnly vowed to follow and protect his great, unmatched mentor,
Toda Josei, to the ends of the earth
for the sake of his fellow Soka Gakkai members and the people of Japan.
Human Revolution
Episode 9
The End