Sumida River
Kototoi Bridge
May 3rd, 1951.
May 3rd, 1951
At Josenji Temple in Mukojima,
The ceremony to elect the second president of Soka Gakkai was held.
Josenji Temple in Sumida Ward, Tokyo
Inaugural address
by board chairman Mishima!
The emergence of a leader to carry the Buddha Dharma into the future
is what we are all longing for in these times.
Seven years have passed
since Soka Gakkai was rebuilt.
With heartfelt prayers of best wishes from the 3,080 comrades who signed the petition
in support of the president's nomination,
I hereby
nominate Toda Josei-sensei
as the second president of Soka Gakkai.
Well, I know succeeding the late Makiguchi-sensei as the president
is clearly beyond my capacity,
but it is with great faith that I have decided to dedicate my worthless life to Buddha
and assume the position
of president for the first time.
Toda-sensei will finally
become the president.
At last, the march forward begins like a scorching sun.
I'll follow him to the end of the earth!
From around the spring of 1943, President Makiguchi began to say
that Soka Gakkai must become the vessel for manifestation of Buddha's true self.
Vessel for manifestation of Buddha's true self
In other words, he would often say,
as if reprimanding us,
"We must clarify the original mission
and purpose of Soka Gakkai and fulfill it."
At first, I, his unworthy disciple,
was equally perplexed about how to interpret it,
leaving me unable to take any action.
However, a profound awareness of its mission has now finally arisen
within the Soka Gakkai as a whole.
Our missionary activities are now more intense than ever before.
We, Nichiren Daishonin's followers and youngest disciples,
have wholeheartedly accepted the Daishonin's bequest.
Furthermore, we will carry on the will of the late Chairman Makiguchi
and fulfill our mission to spread the great Buddhist Dharma
of the Common Path throughout the East and the world.
May we leave this world with the name
of the Great Buddha on our lips.
However, the journey to get here
was as treacherous as walking along a steep mountain ridge.
In preparation for the day he would take office,
Toda had been quietly working over the past few months to address the issues
facing both the Soka Gakkai and himself.
Shinjuku Ward, Hyakunincho
First, Toda needed to get Daito Trading,
which he had established
Daito Trading Co., Ltd.
to rebuild his struggling business,
back on track to secure a financial foundation.
Daito Trading, a tiny company with four employees, was headed
by 23-year-old Yamamoto Shinichi, yet Toda entrusted all the business affairs to them.
Although he himself had stepped back from his business to focus on his work for Soka Gakkai,
he still visited once a day to offer encouragement.
Take a look, everyone.
Huh?
Aren't green shoots already sprouting
from that withered grass?
Wow... What a cute little sprout!
In the eyes of the world,
our company may look just like that dead grass.
But when spring comes,
new plants will sprout,
and before long, the buds
of our business's revival will bloom.
As Nichiren Daishonin wrote in his scriptures,
"Those who believe in the Lotus Sutra are like
winter, which never fails to change into spring."
We need to be patient a little longer,
so let's hold on to hope and stay strong.
Okay!
Toda began privately tutoring Yamamoto Shinichi, who had to leave his night school
Toda
to manage the entire business
on his behalf behind the scenes.
Eighteen Histories of Ancient China: Brief Summary
Every Sunday, he invited Shinichi to his home
and lectured him on a wide range of academic subjects,
including politics, economics, and history.
And Shinichi absorbed it all like water soaking into sand.
Concerned with promoting the growth and development of Soka Gakkai,
Toda made enormous efforts to launch the publication of an official bulletin.
Editorial meeting for the first publication
He started the first editorial meeting
by discussing the paper's future name.
Culture Magazine
"Culture Magazine,"
"Value Magazine," and other such names were brought up...
Value Magazine
I just had an idea.
If it's a newspaper that teaches the correct faith, why not "Seikyo Shimbun?"
Seikyo Shimbun
(Correct Faith Magazine)
Seikyo? I see.
Hm... That's it!
Seikyo - the Sacred Teachings.
Seikyo
(Sacred Teachings)
"Sei" (Saint) refers to Daishonin's holiness
and ascends upwards to Buddha himself.
A newspaper for the true teachings of Buddha, "Seikyo Shimbun!"
That should do it.
Teachings of saints = Seikyo Shimbun
What do you think, Yamamoto-kun?
I agree, it's a wonderful name.
You said you wanted to become
the leader of opinions.
For that purpose,
there isn't a more fitting name.
I see. Good.
"Seikyo Shimbun" it is, then!
Yes.
Next is the question of content. First, we need an editorial that will serve as the backbone.
I would also like a column that criticizes and cuts off the roots of social evil
from the position of Soka Gakkai.
I know!
Let's create a "Short Blade" column,
with brief but sharp epigrams piercing through minds like a samurai's knife.
I'd love to see some personal accounts in it,
describing the joy that comes from faith.
I double that. The social pages of today's newspapers are filled with gloomy news only.
Certainly, we'll include a lot of personal accounts,
but only as long as our articles are truthful and accurate.
If we write without
sufficient attention to detail,
we'll just end up being delusional and bigoted like the other sects.
Got it!
We'll fill the rest with a novel.
Huh? A novel?
Yes, a serialized novel.
A newspaper without a serialized novel
won’t have nearly the same appeal
as one that includes it.
Um... But who's going to...
Will you write it yourself?
That's right. I'll write it. And I'll make sure we don't lose face with my writing.
I've already decided on a title.
We'll call it "human revolution."
"Human Revolution..."
Awesome! I absolutely love that idea.
I'll take the pen name of "Myogoku"
and try to write it to the best of my ability.
I’m not sure how long
I’ll be able to continue.
But won't someone be able to take over
after that and keep writing it
under the name of "Hogoku" or something?
Seikyo Shimbun
Takeuchi Keisuke's sentenced to death
Communist party members acquitted
And on April 20th, the first issue
of Seikyo Shimbun was published.
The Human Revolution
Although its circulation was only 5,000, with three issues per month on just two pages,
Toda and the Soka Gakkai members were thrilled to hold the new issue in their hands,
as they were spearheading the propagation of Common Path and righteous Buddhism.
As Toda worked on publishing the newspaper,
a petition to elect him as president was launched among all Soka Gakkai members,
sending everyone into a
whirlwind of excitement.
Let's nominate Toda-sensei
as the president!
Everyone, please read and
affix your seals to that petition!
Hey, let me see it too!
All right, I'll sign it!
Write me in too!
3,080 members who believed in Soka Gakkai and respected Toda Josei signed the petition.
Their representatives are gathered here today
with pride and determination.
Signatures in support of Toda's appointment as a president
If we wish to attain the same level of enlightenment as the Buddha in this modern age,
and sincerely desire the happiness of people and world peace,
and if we are thorough in our efforts to achieve this,
there is no other way than to spread the Buddhist teaching of the Common Path.
700 years have passed since
Nichiren Daishonin established the sect.
As we think about that day approaching next year, when and where in human history
has there been a single organization quite like Soka Gakkai in the past 700 years?
Now, as we stand on the doorstep of fulfilling Soka Gakkai's mission,
I can say with my own conviction that I will sacrifice my life for the sake of the Common Path.
During my lifetime,
I will convert 750,000 households
with my own hands!
Huh? 750,000?
Didn't he mean to say 75,000?
He clearly said 750,000.
But is mass conversion on such a scale even possible?
Right now, even with our best efforts, we're only reaching 3,000 households a year at most.
Toda's got big shoes to fill...
Should I fail to fulfill this sacred wish during my lifetime,
I ask that you do not
give me a proper burial.
Instead, just throw my cold body
into the sea off the coast of Shinagawa!
Can you do that?
We're finally embarking on our active advance towards the Common Path.
Sensei, please lead us into the battle without hesitation.
And I'll have your back at all times.
Soka Gakkai song - chorus!
Like a flower that scatters all its petals overnight
I too fly in the wind, like a flag
Once I've cast away my body,
Please remember my name fondly, as a man's
Men don't show their tears, but when their hearts come in touch, they do cry
These nameless common people lined up before me now are all Bodhisattvas of the Earth.
They truly are an army of Buddhas risking their lives to spread the word of the Lotus Sutra.
The blood is red in our eyes
as we drink to each other's health...
I wish Makiguchi-sensei could catch a glimpse of this spectacle.
How happy would he have been...
Soka Gakkai President Inauguration Ceremony
The birth of the second president
was met with pride and joy.
This launched a self-propelled wave
Kamata branch roundtable discussion
of enthusiasm for disseminating the Common Path among all the Soka Gakkai members.
Roundtable discussions, previously held twice a month, were now springing up all over the place.
The newcomers began pouring in.
Tsurumi branch roundtable discussion
The Buddha Dharma was spreading like wildfire.
The number of monthly conversions,
which had never exceeded 200 countrywide,
Koiwa branch roundtable discussion
reached the record 284 in May, the month of Toda's inauguration as the president.
Then several more times with 440 converted households in June
and the staggering 735 households in July.
During this period, the organization was also actively expanding its presence in the regions,
Sendai City, Miyagi Prefecture
and immediately after Toda assumed the office,
the Sendai Branch in Tohoku and the Yame Branch in Kyushu were established.
Yame City, Fukuoka Prefecture
June 30th
Monthly branch chiefs meeting
Let's change the topic now.
On the occasion of the 700th anniversary of the Lotus Sutra in April next year,
I want to publish the complete collection of Nichiren Daishonin's writings!
With less than a year left
until next April... It's impossible.
The costs will be through the roof...
I wonder if he can handle it.
Nichiren's Scriptures currently in circulation
all contain additions or omissions influenced by the publisher's circumstances.
Some of these dilute Daishonin's teachings.
It falls to us to follow Daishonin's will to the letter and publish his teachings verbatim.
To perpetuate the Buddha Dharma,
for the sake of all future religious revolutions
and theological debates,
it is imperative
that we print it now.
I kindly ask for your cooperation.
By the way, as for the future of this project,
I want it to encompass all of Daishonin's literary remains.
All the publications up to this point
were only partial.
Moreover, with many misreadings.
All of them do not convey
the true intentions of Daishonin-sama.
From now on, we will enter an era in which the people will take the initiative in disseminating Buddhism.
A Dharma known only to a handful of people would not be able to keep up with the times.
Let's craft a magnificent collection of scriptures
that will endure the test of time,
with our own hands!
Okay!
Ichigaya Station
It's a fresh new beginning today!
In just six months,
I managed to move my office
from barracks to this
brick-and-mortar building!
Daito Trading Co., Ltd.
Good morning!
It finally feels like a proper office.
Yes! It's bright and spacious,
makes you feel so very refreshed!
This way, we'll be able
to work even harder.
Seems like we've taken
a pretty big step forward.
However, for Toda-sensei to realize all of his aspirations,
we must take the company
to the next level.
I firmly believe that it is we, the youth division—especially the men’s youth division—
who will forge a path for the unprecedented
July 11th: Men’s Youth Division Formation Ceremony
religious revolution that the Common Path will usher in.
A historic formation ceremony for the Men's Youth Division
brought together 180 young men, signaling a new era for the organization.
Yamamoto Shinichi also participated as a subdivision leader.
No one could have foreseen that this
seemingly small gathering would eventually flow into a mighty river,
uniting millions of young men
in a single endeavor.
I'm confident that the next president of Soka Gakkai
will rise from among the young men gathered here today.
It is my sincere conviction
that is already among you here.
I would like to extend my heartfelt congratulations to that person, whoever it is.
That day half a year ago...
January 6th
Shinichi, I need you to give me a serious answer to something today.
Okay...
What's important now is what comes after...
If something were to happen to me,
I'd like to leave the Soka Gakkai, the credit cooperative, and the Daito Trading in your hands.
Will you accept it?
Finally, if only doable,
my family too.
Huh?
Shinichi-kun, my mission in this world is also your mission.
If you and I live our mission together,
the time will surely come when Daishonin's legacy is fulfilled.
No matter what anyone says, let's stay strong and move forward together!
Sensei, you have nothing to worry about.
I decided long ago that if I dedicate my entire life to you, I’ll have no regrets.
And my resolve won’t waver,
no matter how many years pass.
I see. That's all I could wish for.
Sensei is in much better spirits now
than he was back then.
Nothing brings me greater happiness.
It is my solemn desire that you will fulfill this noble and formidable mission
of achieving Common Path
with your own hands.
Today, I want to greet my future successor, the next president of Soka Gakkai,
and offer my heartfelt congratulations
on the formation of the Men's Youth Division.
Next, Women's Youth Division formation ceremony was held.
I like to believe that every member of our Women's Youth Division has found happiness.
In the past, women often could do nothing but cry because of their unfortunate fate.
You are all fortunate women who embraced the Mystic Law at a young age
and no longer have to weep over your fate.
You're right!
Sincerely dedicating yourself to faith in your youth
will pave the way for a happy life
and a future family.
It is my heartfelt wish that each and every one of you finds happiness as I speak to you today.
Congratulations!
Although fighting continued on the Korean peninsula, armistice talks finally began in July.
It was anticipated that the war
would soon subside.
The Korean people don't deserve to suffer any further.
I want this war to end as soon as possible.
It's also evident that the Allied occupation of Japan will soon come to an end.
Many people long for a lasting peace with all the Allied powers.
And yet, the belligerent countries keep exchanging fire.
What's worse is that a treaty that ignores the interests of neighboring Soviet Union and China
is ultimately meaningless.
Especially China, to whom we've caused so much suffering...
In the end, even after we regain our independence,
the Japanese nation will essentially remain the same.
The Treaty of Peace with Japan, marking the end of the war
and the restoration of Japan’s sovereignty,
The historic peace is signed
was signed in San Francisco on September 8th by 49 countries, excluding the communist bloc.
Special issue: San Francisco Peace Treaty is signed
49 countries participate; Japanese flag is raised
Yoshida Shigeru's speech
Japan reestablished itself as an independent nation.
It seemed as though the era of occupation, symbolized by GHQ,
was finally drawing to a close.
Prime Minister Yoshida signs the Security Treaty
However, alongside the peace treaty,
the Japan-US Security Treaty was signed,
permitting the US military
to continue using bases in Japan and remain stationed there.
May Day protests going awry
Public order disturbance investigation
But the security treaty
was met with fierce opposition.
First May Day since independence: 400,000 people gather at Gaien Square
Civil unrest over the security treaty
will persist long after this.
Despite the signing of the peace treaty with Japan,
just as Toda had predicted,
the reality was that Japan remained essentially unchanged,
still far from being truly independent or democratic.
It all stems from the lack of a firm idea about the right ideology in this country.
The only solution is the Common Path.
And for that we require a lot more men,
aware that their mission is the Common Path
and determined to carry the future of Japan on their shoulders.
Yes, it's the youth! We must cultivate young men into the leaders of society.
Toda began composing a piece titled "Message to Group Leaders"
to clarify guidelines, and offer hope and encouragement
to the young people representing the future of the organization.
"Message to Group Leaders"
I'll try to put into words the noble goal of Soka Gakkai, its spirit, and everything in my heart.
I have to ensure that it lives on unchanged forever in the hearts of young men.
Yes. Let's start with the conclusion.
"It is the passion and energy of the youth
that will form a new century."
It is the passion and energy of the youth that will form a new century.
We can't discuss politics or intuit education, but we follow the great world philosopher, savior of the East, and the True Embodiment of Buddha who appeared in Japan in the Latter Day of the Law.
As soon as this "Message to Group Leaders" was released,
it swept through the Youth Division like a gust of wind, sending shockwaves across its ranks.
A notice is issued to the youth division leader
The president of Soka Gakkai calls on all male and female members
"Rise up, young people!
We've got a fight ahead of us, young people.
You may ask, then, who are we fighting
and what is our strategy?"
"Thirdly, it is a battle in which we must love all living beings.
That said, a lot of young people don't even love their own parents, so how can they love others?
Shinichi Yamamoto's apartment in Omori, Ota Ward
The answer is by overcoming one's callousness and attaining the Buddha's compassion
in the battle of human revolution!"
"You must unite your hearts and,
as the young flowering warriors you are,
overcome your difficulties with a sincere desire to honor Daishonin’s legacy.
Recognition from fools is the ignominy of the wise.
Recognition from Daishonin
is a lifetime honor."
What stern yet warm words...
This message is brimming with sensei's emotions.
Indeed, it's the lion's cry
for the salvation of humanity!
This "Message to Group Leaders" would later become "Instruction to Youth,"
igniting many young men with burning enthusiasm
and inspiration to lead the fight for the Common Path on the front lines.
Around that time, Soka Gakkai was gaining more and more recognition in society
as an independent religious movement with its own distinct activities.
Recognizing that any future expansion
of Common Path activities would need to be multifaceted,
Toda began preparing to register Soka Gakkai
as a religious organization
under the Religious Corporations Ordinance.
What is the purpose and reasoning behind Soka Gakkai's decision to separate from the sect
and become an independent religious organization?
First and foremost, it was to allow them
"Preaching Guidebook" published on November 18th
the freedom to independently pursue various activities aimed at spreading the Common Path,
Opinion magazine "The Third Civilization"
including propagation efforts, publishing, and public debates.
And by extension, to engage in efforts that contribute to the improvement and development
Educational theory magazine "The Lighthouse"
of peace, culture, and education in line with Soka Gakkai's unique path.
The first athletic meeting/youth festival of the Youth Division, which became the origin of today's cultural festivals
Secondly, it was to help Soka Gakkai withstand any hardships that might arise while preaching
and spreading Nichiren's teachings.
4th East Japan Athletic Meeting
President Toda's "Declaration Calling for the Abolition of Nuclear Weapons"
(September 8, 1957, Mitsuzawa Stadium, Yokohama)
This allowed them to carry out their duties of saving the laity without creating
any responsibilities or inconveniences for the sect overall.
Thirdly, in the current complex social structure
and in anticipation of the future global spread of the Common Path teachings
to countries with diverse cultures and lifestyles,
relying on a small number of priests—who already manage their own congregations—
for that goal was, at best, unrealistic.
Fourthly, it was natural for a religious organization
to center around the people and decide its activities
by consensus, reflecting the people's sentiments in light of current democratic trends.
Finally, in August of the following year, 1952,
Soka Gakkai was officially recognized as a religious organization.
As a religious organization under the Religious Corporations Ordinance,
it gained the legal foundation to conduct activities independently from the sect.
Tokyo Kasei-Gakuin University, Ichigaya
November 4th: 6th Soka Gakkai General Meeting
Determinations and aspirations
of each division's representative!
The title is “Youth's Conviction” by Men's Division Representative, Group Leader Yamamoto. Please!
Youth's Conviction
Group Leader Yamamoto
Soka Gakkai President Toda Josei!
The youth of Soka Gakkai are now engaged in a great struggle
towards a clear goal,
as outlined in the recent "Message to the Youth of Soka Gakkai" from Toda-sensei.
The speech of Men's Division Group Leader Yamamoto,
filled with determination and aspirations, was a direct response to Toda Josei's
"Message to the Group Leaders," published a month earlier.
Now, Toda-sensei is issuing a great decree as the general of the Common Path
in the Latter Day of the Law.
We, the Youth Division,
have taken his words to heart
and are ready to devote our souls and bodies to spreading the Great Law with a smile!
Spending our lives with Toda-sensei's teachings is our sacred wish!
This is the first time I’ve heard Shinichi speak to such a large audience, and he's quite good.
The task that lies before the youth division is a religious revolution!
The path to a religious revolution will be far more challenging
than that of any political or economic one,
and we must be prepared for that!
President Toda Josei!
The youth of Soka Gakkai have triumphed over every obstacle
and now stand in the world's spotlight.
Moreover, we are confident that we will see our struggle through to the end
and fulfill the expectations of Toda-sensei!
President’s Lecture
"The Great Pledge of Soka Gakkai!"
Just as Yamamoto Shinichi's announcement of his determination, "The Conviction of Youth,"
was a pledge of loyalty to Toda Josei,
Toda's speech "The Great Vow of the Soka Gakkai," was his pledge of loyalty to the Buddha.
I vow to spread the true teachings of Buddha Dharma across this nation,
where so many are afflicted
by their erroneous faith.
This is article 1.
As a follower of the Buddha Dharma, I will spread Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo
from Japan to Korea, China, and India, thereby fulfilling Daishonin's prophecy.
Such is my vow to the Common Path.
And our second goal.
Thus, friends,
we devote our bodies and souls to the spread of Buddhism,
as our measly offering
to the Great Buddha.
Let us show the religious world that Soka Gakkai is here to stay!
This and the two other articles
are my immediate goals,
that reflect the unanimous wish
of all Soka Gakkai members.
Are you with me, friends?
Yes!
Daito Trading Co., Ltd.
Hmm, I see we're finally back on track.
Yes. At this rate, we might be able to pay off our credit union debts sooner than expected.
Thank you. You did a great job
Don't mention it!
I'll work even harder to allow you more freedom and control in leading the Common Path forward!
Okay. I'm counting on you.
Yessir!
It seems that all the hard work Shin put in
has helped him grow a lot stronger...
Hmm, our preaching progress has been quite stagnant lately,
neither increasing nor decreasing.
Our conversion goal of 1,000 households
per month by October doesn't seem achievable anymore.
At this rate, the promised 750,000 households...
Sensei,
I've got a couple of places to visit now to discuss a deal.
Yes, go ahead.
You're doing very well.
I'll be on my way, then!
Hm... Is it time to put Shin
on the front lines?
Shin is already my right-hand man.
He might just be able to devise the breakthrough we need to overcome this stagnation.
Sensei announced that we are intensifying our preaching efforts.
Toda-sensei is the master of preaching,
and I am his disciple.
Converting 750,000 households
is my goal as well.
I cannot let Toda-sensei down
and allow him to break his oath.
The battle in which Toda Josei
and Yamamoto Shinichi
are engaged in an unprecedented effort to spread the Lotus Sutra to 750,000 families
and create a society filled with happiness and peace
is finally unfolding, stirring up stormy winds and dark clouds along the way.