A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 16    Steep Path
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
Spring
General
Meeting
On May 3rd, 1956, 30,000 executive staff members from across Japan gathered
May 3rd, 1956—14th Spring General Meeting
at the International Stadium in Ryogoku for the 14th Spring Headquarters General Meeting.
Buddhism is a battle
between Buddha and the demons.
In your life, three obstacles and four demons
will block your path to enlightenment,
The three obstacles
and four demons
while from the outside,
the three formidable enemies
The three
formidable enemies
will work to keep you
from fulfilling the Common Path.
As the Soka Gakkai's Director
of Public Relations, Yamamoto Shinichi
was already gearing everyone up
for the nationwide July battle,
hinting at the rise of the three formidable enemies spoken of in the Scriptures.
Under President Toda Josei's leadership
firmly at the helm of the Common Path,
let’s face the three
formidable enemies head-on,
fortify our ever-growing faith
and arm ourselves with it,
to further our cause boldly
and with unity of minds!
Shinichi's warnings that day proved true
sooner than anyone could expect.
Starting in May in Osaka, the three obstacles, four demons, and three formidable enemies
from across the country
launched a fierce battle
against the Soka Gakkai—
and even among themselves.
I've not been in Osaka for three days.
This time, though, I'm here to stay—
probably right through July.
The time has come for the decisive battle
that will determine my future as well.
Starting with today's Sakai branch executives' meeting, we'll be gathering daily.
May 5th—Sakai Branch Executive Meeting
But we also have to make time for one-on-one dialogue—that’s our top priority.
Without it, we can't keep the balance between the whole and individual.
To help our comrades in Kansai soar,
we need to spend time
giving them solid one-on-one guidance.
Soka Gakkai Kansai Headquarters
Early morning Scriptures lecture
"If the lord of the castle is brave, the defenders are also strong.
If the lord is cowardly, the defenders will also be scared."
This passage teaches us that everything hinges on the leader's determination.
With just one great person as a leader,
everyone under him becomes a hero.
Many roundtable discussions
in each district are scheduled for today.
The success of the roundtable,
regardless of the area,
depends entirely on the determination of the host, the central figure.
Keep this in mind as you inspire peace and courage in your comrades.
Can you do that?
Yes!
Then let's go over today's agenda once more
and identify the goals for each of you.
Almost there!
Yes. Thank you.
Only two more places.
That makes ten places total today.
Yeah. Ten places.
Hello!
I appreciate your daily hard work, everyone.
Won't you agree?
Life is faith, and faith is life.
Is everything going well?
You look like a busy man.
Did you take a day off today?
No.
Then... Are you unemployed?
Yeah... Since work wasn't going well,
I figured I'd earn some good karma by lending you a hand instead.
I can't trust people who don't work!
Nichiren Daishonin’s Dharma plainly warns us
not to put our trust in loiterers.
If you're hung up on work troubles, you won't be able to fully devote yourself to faith.
The true faith
is much more rigorous than that.
Daishonin had this to say about it:
"Buddhism is a body,
the world is a shadow.
Bend the body,
the shadow will warp."
And also...
"Regard your service to the lord
as the practice of the Lotus Sutra."
...among other things.
He warns us sternly, that "To believe means to value life and be diligent in your work."
The idea you can just wash your hands of it
and leave everything for faith to sort out
contradicts Daishonin's Buddhism.
Now’s the time to grit our teeth
and push forward,
giving our all to both work and faith,
no matter how tough it gets.
Won't you agree, friend?
Yes. I understand now.
I'll make sure to return to my job!
Do we have any paper and brushes here?
Yes, we do.
Let us commemorate this meeting
with a piece of calligraphy.
How about this?
Yeah!
Good evening, everyone!
Shinichi truly was everywhere at once.
He spent his days making the rounds of bases
and his evenings
attending roundtable discussions.
Wherever and whenever he went, Shinichi stirred up a whirlwind of propagation in his wake.
He won people over with his gentle,
warm and considerate tone.
At the same time, Shinichi’s words
brimmed with conviction,
inspiring most newcomers
to eagerly step up and join the fight.
Let's do a good job!
I’d love to stay and chat longer,
but sadly, I have to go now.
I really can't keep the men's division
waiting any longer.
Thank you, Chief!
Thanks a lot!
All right. Take care, everyone!
After the men's division meeting, Shinichi was on his way to the Kansai headquarters.
Oya-kun, the men's division is also fired up.
Yes! Thank you very much. They take to propagating with incredible vigor these days!
And when their efforts bear fruit, they become all the more fired up to give it their best!
Yes, so I thought.
Huh? Oya-kun,
Discussion
Roundtable
it the roundtable here still in progress?
It's probably over.
Doesn't matter. Even if it's just one or two people left, let's meet them
and lift their spirits.
Roundtable
Discussion
Okay!
Good evening!
Who might this be?
That voice sounds familiar.
Pardon the late visit.
Yamamoto here.
It's all right, Chief!
Nice work, as always.
Is the roundtable already wrapped up?
Yes, we closed it not long ago.
Was it productive?
Yes! We had six people
want to join this time.
That's great!
I expected no less from you.
Everyone, no matter how far you go,
don't stop believing in your path.
I know that one day,
you'll fulfill the lives of your dreams!
Yes!
May 15th—6 a.m.
This morning, before dawn had even broken,
an unexpected incident occurred in Osaka.
It's a corner room on the second floor.
You'll go down the hall.
You'll watch the stairs over there.
You stay here.
Okay, let's go.
Who might that be so early?
Can I help you?
South Police Station.
We have questions about
the Lotus Temple incident.
You're still investigating that?
We need you at the police station right now.
O-Okay...
Is everything all right?
Don't worry.
There's probably been a mix-up.
Ah, ma'am, please tell
Manager Sagawa what happened.
The police had some follow-up questions about the Lotus Temple incident.
Got it. I will!
Osaka—South Prefectural Police Station
What the hell? I came along voluntarily,
yet they're acting like I'm some big-time criminal!
Something's off...
Sagawa
Dental
Supplies
Store
What? The Lotus Temple incident?
Brother, that's not right!
The police probably dragged him out of his house
because of his ties to Soka Gakkai.
Let's report straight to Chief Yamamoto!
All right!
Okay, got it. Thank you. Please tell me at once
if there are further developments.
This makes six of our men... Weird.
All six were brought in for questioning
at approximately the same time.
It can't be a coincidence.
All under the pretext of rehashing
a long-resolved incident...
What's their play here?
What's worse, if the media reports
all these police roundups side by side,
it’ll inevitably hurt Soka Gakkai’s reputation.
And that's not all.
All six people taken in for questioning
this morning were our devoted champions.
With all those men in police custody at once,
the rest of the branch is bound to be restless.
"When your faith deepens,
the three obstacles and four demons
will appear, each scrambling
to throw you off course."
That's it.
The first demon has made an appearance.
Terrified by our fierce stand in the Battle for Kansai,
the demon army
finally launched its counterattack.
On this day, Toda happened to be in Osaka,
giving a lecture on Scriptures.
Sensei, I must apologize.
Six members of the Osaka Branch were taken in
for questioning by the police this morning.
What? On what charges?
Ostensibly, assault and battery.
They told one of them it's about the Lotus Temple incident a year and three months ago.
Our men's division executives
were present there.
That's the one where the head priest
of the Lotus Temple refused to meet with us,
so they intercepted him on his way to a memorial service to try and talk to him, right?
We still need to talk!
Please wait!
Do you really think I have anything
to talk about with lowlifes like you?
And then?
Right, after that...
Shinichi explained each of the incidents
that led up to the police summons...
All of these are minor incidents
that have nothing to do with assault and battery.
Yes. And yet, the authorities have set up an investigation HQ at South Police Station.
What? But isn't it completely out of proportion?
Yes, and what's more bizarre
is that this article appeared in the morning paper.
"After six months of undercover investigation,
the Osaka Prefectural Police Security Division
obtained arrest warrants for six individuals
from the Osaka District Court.
A mass arrest will be conducted,
overseen by the chief of security."
Isn't this is a warning article?
Yes.
It was only about 6 a.m.
when all six were apprehended.
This article had to be prepared in advance.
So, you think the police
are deliberately targeting us?
Yes, that's the only explanation.
Are they trying to paint Soka Gakkai
as a violent religious organization
by dredging up minor
and long-resolved incidents?
Attracting followers with violence
Hm. The unrest among members
will be a problem.
Yes, Osaka, which is in a thrill right now, cannot be allowed to fall victim to the demons' schemes.
That's right, as the saying goes,
"Follow not, nor fear the demon."
"Follow not,
nor fear the demon."
Yes. We will fight back resolutely,
as Daishonin commanded us to.
Okay, got it. We'll talk again
at tonight's Scriptures lecture.
Now is the crucial time for Soka Gakkai.
Thank you.
Have you seen today's evening issue?
Yeah, I did.
"Too much faith leads to violence"—
quite the headline.
But it's also so fishy.
Exactly. I have never seen or heard
of a Soka Gakkai member resorting to violence.
Yeah. It reeks fabrication.
As expected, everyone
brought with them the newspapers.
They're all uneasy about six
of their comrades getting arrested.
Let us get started, then.
The chapter we'll be learning today
is "On omens."
"Strange occurrences in the heavens
astound all people,
and calamities on earth disturb everyone.
When the Buddha
was about to preach the Lotus Sutra,
he caused the five omens
and the six omens to appear."
That's enough.
Great events are always accompanied
by significant shocks.
There are strange occurrences in the heavens and calamities on earth that scare everyone,
but there is a reason for all of it.
When Shakyamuni Buddha
was about to preach the Lotus Sutra,
it was preceded by a great omen,
the only one in the 40-odd years.
The reason is that the Lotus Sutra
is the highest teaching,
capable of even destroying original ignorance.
Recently,
we've all been preaching the Lotus Sutra
and pushing the propagation work
a bit more enthusiastically than usual
in the Kansai region.
We've done nothing wrong.
However, in the Latter Day of the Law,
the arrival of the Lotus Sutra
must be marked by even more intense omens
than in the Shakyamuni era.
So, as you all know from today's morning and evening papers,
an absurd situation came about in which the Osaka Police have arrested six of our comrades.
The charges are based on an incident that happened more than a year ago
and had long been fully resolved.
They're dredging it back up,
trying to spin the story
to make us look like the ones at fault.
But you can't bend the truth.
In due time, the truth will come to light,
and our six comrades
will be freed without harm.
There are hardships we must endure
for our faith, and this is assuredly one of them.
You could say this is an honorable hardship borne in the name of the Lotus Sutra.
Allow me to be frank with you.
The newspapers waste no time painting Soka Gakkai as violent religious fanatics.
But you tell me—when and where did we ever use violence to enforce our faith?
If anyone here was foolish enough to spread faith through violence, step forward now.
The newspapers made a business
out of writing one-sided stories,
deciding right and wrong with a flick of a pen
without ever seeking the truth—
isn't that the real violence?
That's my opinion.
What do you all think?
Exactly!
Soka Gakkai stands alone
in this Latter Day of the Law
as the sole organization faithfully practicing Nichiren Daishonin’s Buddhism
just as he originally taught it.
Our only wish is to rid this world of such words as "suffering" and "unhappiness" altogether!
However, no sooner had everyone began working devotedly for the Common Path
than the government suddenly lashed out,
much like the Kamakura Shogunate that persecuted Nichiren Daishonin 700 years ago,
arresting six Soka Gakkai members on trumped-up charges and tired old slanders.
But we mustn't flinch an inch!
With tonight’s chapter
of the Scriptures in mind,
I’m convinced that this incident is an auspicious omen, heralding a great victory for us in Kansai!
I have to leave for Kochi tomorrow,
but the next few days will decide everything.
Shin-chan, you've done well.
Don't make a step away from Osaka
until everyone is safely released.
Yes, that was the plan.
No matter how many days it takes,
I won't leave Kansai.
From the Buddhist point of view, it is clear that this incident is the work of the demons.
However, this was the first time that our Kansai member was arrested for his religious activities.
What kind of effect will it have
on the ongoing battle?
In any case, I must keep chanting.
The only way to defeat
the demons is with faith.
As the person in charge,
my strong prayer will decide everything!
The next day,
Shinichi completed his scheduled tutoring rounds
during the day, and then in the evening,
he went through the roundtables,
offering encouragement to the members.
In spite of yesterday's news, the number of roundtable discussions held has not decreased.
It did not shake their will to fight.
The only problem now...
The leaders from all over the country
report that the atmosphere at the roundtables
suddenly became heavy.
The shock of being arrested for your religious work is hard to express in words,
Six people arrested
but it probably affected their hearts deeply.
Attack!
That's right, we'll be sitting ducks
if we try to play defense.
Attack is the best defense!
Only by going on the offensive can we seize our chance to win,
and the sooner that happens, the better.
All right...
Lightning
fast
This morning, dispatched members from Tokyo
and local executives gathered for an early morning lecture on the Scriptures as usual.
But there was a suffocating heaviness in the air
that had never been there before.
Shinichi sensed at once what was causing it.
Unbelievable. Even the executive staff
fell under the demons' influence.
The change must start here!
Let's hear the reports first.
What was the atmosphere like at last night's roundtable discussions? Anyone, please.
Then let's hear from Ueda-kun,
the dispatch executive.
Yes. Everyone was in good spirits,
but we dispersed early last night
No one brought up any specific questions
about the recent incident,
but it seemed as though everyone
was quite frightened on the inside.
I was prepared to answer any questions in full if they came up, but that opportunity never arose…
Aren't you the one who is frightened?
He’s right…
Deep down, I’m getting cold feet too.
I was scared just as much as everyone else!
In the Oral Teachings of the Buddha...
"Those carrying this
Lotus Sutra with them
should be prepared
to face difficulties."
...is the golden maxim.
We, who have been entrusted the Lotus Sutra,
must accept the current difficulties as a given.
However, it would be presumptuous to suggest that they measure up
to the hardships Nichiren Daishonin endured.
We cannot expect to remain entirely unaffected
by the ignorance of lay people.
Lightning fast: How to deal with this crisis and fight it is our biggest challenge right now.
Once, when one of his followers
was in trouble, Daishonin said...
"You must have deep faith,
for timidness won't
amount to anything."
...to lift his spirits.
"No matter how tough things get,
no matter what may come, you must never
allow yourself the sin of cowardice.
Keep your faith strong as much as you can."
That’s what Daishonin
would tell us if he was here now.
The moment you allow
even a trace of fear into your heart,
you can be sure you've let the demon defeat you.
That's what you need to cut off decisively.
What rests on our shoulders
is the weight of the happiness and misery
of 45,000 Soka Gakkai households in Osaka.
We must not treat lightly something
that has brought long-awaited happiness
to so many of our comrades.
Now's the time to man up!
If you intend to strike the demon down
with the sword of your faith, now's the time!
Th-That's right!
It's now or never.
I'll do it!
I can do it!
Never fear or falter!
We won't lose!
The righteous Buddhism and the righteous faith
always get the last laugh!
Everyone, muster your courage for this fight!
Let's show the rest of Osaka what the spirit of Kansai in Soka Gakkai members is capable of!
Yes!
It goes without saying
that from noon to night that day,
at roundtable discussions and meetings across Osaka,
Yamamoto Shinichi’s impassioned speech
during the early morning lecture
kept everyone energized,
like a torrent of life running right through the city.
In just a day,
Osaka had regained all of its momentum.
The sturdy organizational structure,
built over five months,
had proven strong and flexible enough
to withstand any challenge,
both from within and without.
Soka Gakkai
I got it, got it!
Additional results?
Yes!
You sure like to work hard!
That's 'cause all the group chiefs
are unstoppable!
Wow, I'm jealous!
We came here to chant together
to chant everyone up.
That's great!
Gyo-san, do your best!
What a huge change from yesterday!
This morning's guidance from Yamamoto really brought Osaka back to life.
At this rate, we'll see an even bigger spike in conversions this month!
Soka Gakkai Headquarters—Shinanomachi, Tokyo
Tokyo has certainly become more active
in roundtable discussions.
But it's merely a mechanical reaction.
Tokyo doesn’t even come close
to matching the exhilaration of Osaka.
At this rate, we’ll lose the battle before it even begins. Immediate action is needed.
Soon after, it was announced that Tokyo
would be changing commanders.
Director Ishikawa Yukio
was appointed overall commander,
while Ryoichi Sawada, whom he succeeded,
was assigned to oversee only the Tokyo area.
However, even with this change,
the Tokyo area,
once set on this course, ultimately couldn't break free from the path of inertia.
I see, so the district head
went out to proselytize?
When he's back, please tell him
Yamamoto wanted to see him.
Also, give this to your dad.
What now? A young man
named Yamamoto came?
You think that could be Chief Yamamoto?
It might just be...
And he gave me this for you.
Huh?
Check this out!
Chief tells me to leap into the battle
and fight like a lion!
I bet he doesn't know
how sluggish our district is.
That doesn't matter!
Anyway, I gotta do it now!
If I hesitate when he sics me like this,
what kind of man would I be?
The next day, this district head had become
a changed man who fights with ferocity of a lion.
It was soon after this
that he persuaded 33 people to join
during a single district roundtable discussion.
Good evening!
Hey, good evening.
How is your district doing?
All of our guys are keen as mustard.
Same here. We're unstoppable. Like a train!
Oops, pardon.
I gotta hurry, or they won't accept it.
Phew. Finally made it in time.
We got additional results!
Well done!
38 more households?
You did really well!
What's going on?
We got 400 in our area alone today!
I wonder what the overall branch result will come to.
There are only four days left until the deadline.
But it'll be one hella number for sure!
It feels as if the entire Kansai HQ
is sailing steadily ahead like a battleship to the rhythm of a military march.
South
Police
Station
of Osaka
The six members detained by the police
were released one after another,
and by the afternoon of May 25,
all had returned to Kansai Headquarters.
You're good!
Welcome back!
Chief, I'm back!
Good job.
Congratulations on your release.
You did well.
The arrested members
also immediately returned to the front line.
"The truth always wins in the end.
And we will definitely prove that."
The flame of the members' fighting spirit
could not be extinguished.
The battle of propagation
finally picked up,
and Osaka buzzed with activists rushing between roundtable discussions and propagation efforts.
New entries poured in without end,
and the results continued to climb
with no sign of stopping.
When finally...
May 31st—HQ Executive Meeting (Toshima, Tokyo)
And now, the results
of conversion work in May!
1st place: Osaka Branch,
11,111 households!
Yeah! We did it!
Thank you.
This is the fight of our comrades in Kansai
who gritted their teeth and fought till the end.
11,111 households—
an unprecedented conversion result
that nobody else would dare to dream of.
Under Yamamoto Shinichi’s leadership,
the Osaka members
have built an everlasting monument
that will shine with glory for all time in the history of the Common Path.
The strong foundation for the Invincible Kansai was laid here.
This May, thanks to the great progress
of the Osaka branch,
we were able to reach
nearly 30,000 households nationwide.
But that also means greater repercussions.
Established religious groups and societal forces will continue
trying to frustrate
the efforts of Soka Gakkai’s.
And their attempts are certain
to grow even more intense from here on.
We're finally approaching
a steep mountain on our path.
But no matter how steep and rough the way
may be, Shinichi and I must overcome it together.
It's to eliminate all unhappiness
and suffering from this world!
After this, Toda composed a poem.
A steeper mountain we now climb together.
Lay your heart down with the Common Path.
This poem was brimming with the warmth
of the teacher-student bond
between Toda Josei and Yamamoto Shinichi, along with their unwavering determination.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr, Muzussawa,
True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 16
The End