A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 20      The Succession
Final Episode
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
In August, with the introduction of the block system that subdivided Tokyo into 23 wards,
November 1957—Katsushika Ward, Tokyo
Yamamoto Shinichi was appointed head of the Katsushika combined block.
Ever since, he has been tirelessly crisscrossing the entire ward,
working to create a model block in Katsushika—
a downtown district of Tokyo—
brimming with the joy and happiness that faith brings, setting an example
for the rest of the nation.
It's getting quite late...
I'm tired.
But what worries me even more
is Sensei's health.
That look of exhaustion at the headquarters meeting wasn't a matter of course.
Sensei is planning to go to Hiroshima soon,
but it may exact a heavy toll on his health.
Soka Gakkai Headquarters (Shinanomachi, Tokyo)
Sensei, please cancel your trip
to Hiroshima tomorrow.
I beg you!
Please take some time off
to rest your body.
That is not possible.
I'll go. I have to go.
If you push yourself too far,
you'll be risking your health, or even your life.
Please cancel it.
How can I ever do that?!
You think that's something I could do—isn't that right?
But as a Buddha’s emissary, how can I take back a decision I’ve already made?
I'll go there even if I die.
Shinichi, how can it be wrong
it that's what the true faith is about?
Sensei puts his life on the line
to go to Hiroshima...
4,000 of our comrades are waiting for me.
Shinichi, don’t stand in the way
of my trip to Hiroshima.
Whether I die or come back alive,
it's all in Buddha's hands.
Toda's house in Shirokane, Minato Ward
Good morning.
Well, shall we get going?
Dear!
What's wrong?!
Izumida-san, this is serious!
S-Sensei!
Call Shinichi...
Following evaluations by two specialists—
Dr. Yabe, Toda’s attending physician,
and Dr. Kida, a leading gastroenterologist at the University Hospital—
Toda was diagnosed
with advanced cirrhosis of the liver.
He was ordered to rest in bed
and placed on a regimen of medication and a restricted diet as part of his home treatment.
Yamamoto Shinichi's House in Kobayashi City, Ota Ward
If we were to lose Sensei now,
the Common Path would surely crumble.
How can we let Sensei die?
As December went on,
Toda began to show signs of improvement
and steadily regained his strength.
Soka Gakkai
Chairman! The tally is in—
by the end of this month, Soka Gakkai has confidently exceeded 750,000 households,
reaching 765,000!
That's it! We've done it at last!
Harayama-san, please report
to President Toda at once.
So we've finally reached
the 750,000 households mark?
We had no more than 3,000 members
when I made that promise.
In just six years and seven months,
my most cherished dream was realized.
It's all thanks to our comrades
who stood by me through thick and thin.
The challenge now is making our members
in all 750,000 households truly happy.
More precisely, the question is:
"What path should we take to guide people
toward happy and fulfilling lives?"
With faith at its foundation...
Everything hinges on their ability to stoically persevere in faith, no matter where it leads them.
What greater goal must I set for them
to make it a reality?
How should one practice their faith?
To have faith—what for?
It's crucial to clearly point out those
signposts for everyone to follow right now.
All right, it's decided.
December Headquarters Meeting (Toshima Public Hall)
The total number of households
converted in December is 25,089.
This allowed us to confidently surpass
the 750,000 households target!
At long last, the lifelong goal President Toda
set when he took office has been fulfilled!
The news reinvigorated Toda-sense greatly.
On that occasion,
he wanted to reassure everyone
that he would attend the first service of the year at the headquarters.
Furthermore, as we embark
on a new journey in the coming year,
Sensei wanted to pass to you
the "Three Guidelines of Soka Gakkai"
as signposts for your faith.
As per his request,
I will now announce them to everyone.
1. Faith for a
harmonious
family
2. Faith for
each person
to become
happy
3. Faith for
surmounting
obstacles
These are the three guidelines.
Let's all work hard next year
for the fulfillment of those.
These guidelines are filled with Sensei's wish for the happiness of all members.
Let us engrave them in our hearts
as the guidelines for all eternity!
New Year's Day, 1958
The New Year's Service,
which marked the start of activities for 1958,
was held at the Soka Gakkai Headquarters on January 1st.
Sensei presented us with a New Year poem.
Allow me to read it now.
The lion roared
to save the people
from suffering
Seven years old—
what a glorious life!
February 10th, morning
That's the current situation.
I see.
Good job out there.
Yes, our position in Kansai
is pretty much ideal.
It is no exaggeration to say we've laid a firm foundation for the Common Path in Japan.
The real challenge only begins now.
How far will we make it
in the next seven years?
We have to hurry, Shinichi.
Do you think we can reach 3 million households in the next seven years?
Yes, we can.
I will make sure we do.
I am your faithful disciple.
As a disciple, it's my duty
to fulfill my master's vision.
Rest assured.
Good. I look forward to seeing how far
you can take it with your own hands.
Wouldn't it be wonderful if the time had come when our ranks numbered 10 million believers?
Yes, I'm looking forward to it. I really do.
As part of his will, sensei left me
more goals for the future.
I absolutely must achieve them
and make him happy.
March 1st—Head Temple Taisekiji
On March 1st, a pompous dedication ceremony
and a special commemorative service were held
at the newly built Grand Auditorium
of Honmon Branch amid joyous crowds.
Let us all celebrate together the completion
of this magnificent Grand Auditorium,
made possible by the heartfelt contributions
of over 750,000 Soka Gakkai households!
The mountain hikes in celebration of the Grand Auditorium's completion began on the 2nd,
with 200,000 people
booking a climb that month.
The combined number of participants in the overnight and day trips reached 7,000 each day,
making Taisekiji Temple
more vibrant than ever before.
Pilgrimage Headquarters at Rikyoubou Temple
Shinichi, my friend, Prime Minister Mine,
called me and said he'd like to visit
on Sunday, March 16th.
Really?
This is a good opportunity.
Let's send the youth division climbing that day.
And let's also hold a rehearsal, a mock exam ceremony for the future of the Common Path.
Okay.
Shinichi, during this ritual ceremony
on March 16th,
I'm going to entrust the official seal
of the Common Path to you.
You’ll be in overall charge of this ceremony.
Don't hold back and give it your best.
Yessir, I’ll make it a perfect gathering for giving my oath as the successor of the Common Path.
Sensei's waning strength is what worries me.
Even just walking is getting harder
for him with each passing day.
What can I do to reduce
the burden on his health?
Yes, let's prepare a litter.
Good night!
Good job getting here.
Please watch your step!
It's good!
So warm!
I finally get why they told us
to bring our own chopsticks and bowls.
That's true. You can feel Sensei's soul
in this pork soup he treated us to.
And in this cold,
it warms you from the inside!
That sure is great!
March 16th, 1958
Mine-san? What Mine-san?
Huh? Y-Yes I'll pass it to him at once.
Sensei, a call for you.
Toda listening...
The caller was Prime Minister Mine.
"A diplomatic issue has emerged in the government, and I must address it urgently,
so I won't be able to attend the ceremony," he said.
Mine-san, 6,000 of our young members have been waiting quite some time for your arrival.
Wouldn't that be unfair towards them?
You don't need to apologize to me.
Apologize to our young people!
Hello?
He hung up.
Prime Minister Mine isn't coming.
How would our young men feel when they hear that the Prime Minister won't attend?
They'll all be depressed.
All right, let's convene an emergency meeting
of the Youth Division leaders.
Long story short,
Prime Minister Mine couldn't make it.
His family and a House of Representatives member Saijo,
who also attended the memorial service on the 1st, will be climbing the mountain on his behalf.
With or without the Prime Minister,
let's carry out the ceremony in full force as planned and give the youth a rousing welcome.
Yes!
This doesn't change that today's ceremony
would be a mock ceremony
for when the Common Path is achieved.
I regard everyone here today as my successor,
and through this ceremony, I will entrust you with the cause of the Common Path.
Since the PM isn't coming, I intend to encourage everyone with my own strength.
Thank you!
It's too big and unfit for a real battle.
You can't do any fighting in this.
Sensei, please forgive me for this oversight.
However, your disciples
put their souls into this litter.
Please, let us use it.
Very well.
Toda-sensei!
You’ve all grown up so much—
truly, it’s incredible to see how far you’ve come.
This could well be the last time
we all get to gather like this…
Ah, it's Sensei!
Toda-sensei!
Sensei! How are you?
Sensei! Please stay well forever!
The future belongs to the young.
As long as we have these young men,
I have no doubt that we can turn Japan
into the paradise of peace.
An address by Toda Josei-sensei!
During the ceremony,
Toda spoke from his chair.
He tried to stand up and speak,
but was no longer strong enough for that.
It’s our mission to carry the Common Path
to every corner of the world.
And today, I pass that noble cause
to you, the young men and women.
I entrust its future to you.
Please take good care of the Common Path!
Soka Gakkai is the king of the religious world.
You have nothing to fear.
Never forget your responsibility—
you were chosen to succeed me in this battle,
the spiritual battle for the Common Path
as the young, rising warriors.
So fight it with courage to the end.
Okay!
"Soka Gakkai is the king of the religious world."
These words stood as a powerful declaration of victory for the Common Path—
Toda’s lifelong aspiration.
It would also prove to be Toda’s final lion’s roar to the youth.
This is the end...
Makiguchi-sensei, I have inherited your will
and built the solid foundation
for the Common Path for all eternity.
And just now, I have also bequeathed
its future to my beloved disciples.
Your aspirations still pulsate
in the hearts of the young, redder than blood.
My work here is done.
Sensei, did I do well?
Sensei, you can count on us, your disciples,
to carry the torch of the Common Path!
Leave all worries behind.
March 16th would later be commemorated as the Memorial Day of the Common Path—
the day Toda's disciples inherited it and vowed
their renewed commitment to its cause.
From March 16th onward,
Toda's health began to deteriorate rapidly.
Though he was too ill
to even rise from his futon unaided,
his spirit remained steadfast.
Good morning.
Shinichi, I dreamed I went to Mexico yesterday.
Mexico?
They were waiting.
Everyone was waiting for me.
The people there were yearning
for Nichiren's Buddhism.
I wish I could go there, launch the journey of Common Path throughout the world...
Sensei...
Shinichi, your goal is the world.
Your real stage is the world—
but what a vast stage it is...
Different races, different ethnicities...
Liberal countries
and socialist countries...
Each country has its own
approach to religion.
Some allow missionary work,
while others do not.
How can you harmonize the Mystic Law
with all those diverse nations?
I want you to consider it carefully right now.
The true essence of Buddhism lies in bringing happiness and peace to all humanity.
Your weak health is what worries me.
Shinichi, live!
You must live a long life and go to the world.
I will!
Sensei, good morning.
March 29th, morning
How are you feeling today?
Uh... I'm fine.
Is the mountain pilgrimage proceeding as planned?
Yes, we have everything under control.
The pilgrimage will continue for two more days.
There haven't been any incidents.
You have nothing to worry about.
I see. So it's all going smoothly?
Is everyone from our youth well?
Yes, they're all well and doing their best.
The only possible issue had been
this particularly unruly monk.
We wanted him to reflect on his actions,
so we filed a protest.
Did anything come out of that?
Yes.
Shinichi told Toda in detail about the atrocities
committed by one of the head monks.
One of them had been drinking at the inn since morning,
despite the ban on alcohol
during the Grand Auditorium opening ceremony for security reasons.
On another occasion, still drunk,
he verbally abused the young monks,
insultingly telling them to go to Mount Minobu.
He also placed bells on their heads
and struck them unsparingly with the bell sticks.
Also, this head monk has long held a grudge against Soka Gakkai and you personally,
and has been slandering us for some time.
So I thought we should arrange
a proper meeting and have a thorough discussion.
What a sorry sight...
Shinichi, this might look like a minor dispute,
but it actually signals a deeper issue
of corruption and decay within the sect.
Why do monks start to fall
into corruption and depravity?
That's because they've lost sight of living
for the higher purpose of the Common Path.
If this one point goes wrong,
everything goes wrong.
It's sad that many monks today,
Upholding the Monastic Laws
while paying lip service to Upholding the Monastic Laws just to protect themselves,
are in no hurry to let go of their selfish earthly desires.
In other words, they've become slaves to those desires and sunk to the level of animals.
Just like it did during the war, the sect may again harbor demons in the future—
those who aim to destabilize the true Dharma
and block the Common Path.
However, we must never allow
Daishonin's Buddhism to be ruined!
That’s why you must stand firm
and fight the evil festering within the sect—
do you understand, Shinichi?
Yes.
Not a step back, remember?
Yes!
Don't let up on the chase.
Yes! I will never forget your wise guidance!
Sensei, please rest assured.
No matter what happens,
we'll protect Soka Gakkai with our lives!
Don't let up on the chase!
If this continues,
Sensei is only going to get worse.
We need to take him to his home in Tokyo
as soon as possible and get him a proper doctor.
Even if you’re thinking of moving him to Tokyo,
I’m not sure it’s even possible...
How about having Dr. Kida come here
and examine Sensei
so that we can decide on a course of action?
Evening of the 31st
He still has a steady and strong heartbeat.
They say his strength has been waning rapidly these past few days.
In that case, we might need
to move him to Tokyo as soon as possible...
Sensei, we need to leave.
I'll be accompanying you.
April 1st, 2:20 a.m.
Numazu Station
Numazu
Sensei, you're safe now.
I see...
April 1st, 7 a.m.—Surugadai University Hospital
Well then, I will now begin working on the treatment.
Please spare no effort
to get the best treatment for Sensei.
Yamamoto-san, thank you
for looking after him so much.
No, it's nothing.
I’ll excuse myself for now,
but if anything comes up,
don’t hesitate to call me
at work or at home.
Okay.
All I can do now is pray
for Sensei's complete recovery.
I will ask everyone
in the youth division to do the same.
April 2nd, evening
On April 2nd at 5 p.m., a joint meeting between the board of directors
and the youth division leaders
was held at the Soka Gakkai headquarters.
The agenda for tomorrow's
HQ Executive Meeting has just been set.
The exam preparations are also in order, right?
Yes.
Yes!
That should be all for today's meeting...
Yes?
Chief Yamamoto, we just got a call from the hospital—it was Sensei’s son, Kyoichi-san.
C-Coming!
Sorry for the wait, Yamamoto's here.
My father just passed away.
He passed away...?
But he was well just this morning...
Yes. It seemed like he was fine.
But at 6:30 p.m., shortly after the doctor
had finished his examination,
he passed away peacefully in his sleep,
with my mother by his side...
Thank you very much to all of you
for taking such good care of him.
Sensei is no more...
Sensei had...
passed away just now,
at 6:30.
As he had foretold, he departed this world
just as the cherry blossoms came into bloom.
Just as he had planted the saplings
of the Mystic Law in over 750,000 families
and the flowers of happiness had begun to bloom,
he was swept away in an instant—
like the fleeting cherry blossoms.
Toda Josei is coming!
Grand Lecture on the Lotus Sutra
Toda Josei, who dedicated his life to the Common Path, has now passed into eternal sleep.
However, as Toda demonstrated through his own example, the path of a great human revolution—
beginning within one person—holds the power
to ultimately decide the nation's fate
and even remold the fate of the human race.
That was the greatest and finest legacy
that Toda Josei left to mankind.
Ah, April 2nd...
For the
Soka Gakkai,
for me,
and for all
his disciples,
this day
will never
be forgotten.
Sensei....
Toda and Shinichi's first meeting
How old are you, Yamamoto-kun?
I'm 19 years old.
Hm. Almost 20, yes?
When Toda resigned as the President due to financial difficulties
Sensei...
Please.
Oh! What do we have here?
"Still serving an old and mystic fate,
Though others change, I alter not.”
Still serving an old and mystic fate,
Though others change,
I alter not.
All right, I’ll write you a poem too.
"Whenever I stand on the fields of war,
Unfailing at my side,
You are my sword.”
At Haneda Airport, before turning himself in to the Osaka Police
Shinichi, don't you die.
You cannot die!
Shinichi, if ever...
If you were ever to die,
I’d rush over to your side,
throw myself over you,
and die with you then and there!
In the elevator after the Grand Auditorium opening ceremony
Sensei, this way.
Well, my job here is done.
Now I'm prepared to die anytime.
Shinichi,
the rest is up to you.
Please...
Of course!
I made a promise to the Sensei.
I must stand tall now.
It is my duty to encourage
our many grieving comrades!
Stand up! Rise!
Become a strong person
who can overcome anything!
The final curtain has fallen
on the life of an unsurpassed hero
of the Mystic Law,
our great mentor in Common Path.
However, as the one chosen
to carry on his work,
I shall rise to the challenge and boldly raise
the curtain on the second act
of the Common Path!
News of Toda’s death quickly spread nationwide through newspapers and radio,
April 20th—Toda's funeral
and the media swiftly reported remarks from religious scholars and critics
predicting that, without its supreme leader, Soka Gakkai
would descend into internal strife
and eventually collapse.
And most of the Japanese people
needed no further persuasion.
However, Soka Gakkai didn't so much as waver.
Aoyama Funeral Home
With Shinichi Yamamoto—Toda’s most devoted disciple who carried on his legacy in the struggle—
rising as the spiritual cornerstone of the Common Path,
Funeral of the Soka Gakkai
President Toda Josei
all the members stood firmly united in purpose.
Chairman
For his own sake, for the happiness of the people,
and for the betterment of society,
Shinichi threw himself into spreading
the Lotus Sutra and uplifting the members.
With Yamamoto Shinichi at its center,
Soka Gakkai made greater strides than ever before and continued to expand in all directions.
Then finally, two years after Toda's death,
he was ushered in as the next president.
May 3rd, 1960
The inauguration of Yamamoto Shinichi, the third president
Although I'm still young, from today on I will represent all of Toda's disciples
and take the lead in taking the Common Path
to the next, global stage!
Have a safe trip!
October 2nd—First overseas trip
Take care!
Good luck!
Hang in there!
Sensei, I'm off. Goodbye!
With his journey to America,
Yamamoto Shinichi at last took his first step
toward globalizing the Common Path.
To fulfill the lifelong dream of his mentor, Toda Josei,
who wholeheartedly yearned for peace
and happiness for all people around the world.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation & TS
Editing
QC
QC & TS
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr
True Noobow Gamer
The End