A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 17        Turning Point
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
June 12th, 1956.
House of Councillors election campaign begins
June 12th, 1956
The 4th House of Councillors election was announced,
Vote Kiyohara Katsu
and six candidates were nominated by the Soka Gakkai: Kiyohara Katsu for the Tokyo district,
Haruki Seichiro for the Osaka district,
as well as Seki Hisao, Harayama Koichi,
Yamadaira Chuhei, and Jujo Shunzo
for the national district.
The Kansai comrades,
who proved their strength
Vote Seichiro Haruki
in the people’s victory
during the May battle
and laid the firm groundwork
for “Invincible Kansai,”
have now thrown themselves wholeheartedly into campaigning
to secure candidate Haruki the top seat
in the House of Councillors election.
Soka Gakkai Kansai Headquarters
On this day, Josei Toda, who had been traveling around the country to encourage members,
arrived to Osaka where his beloved disciple
Yamamoto Shinichi was in charge.
To put politics back into the hands of the people,
I recommended you to pick from our ranks
virtuous and capable distinguished citizens
to represent our ideals...
"Virtuous and capable distinguished citizens."
This is the very essence and purpose
of Soka Gakkai's entry into politics.
Sensei already outlined it before
at the Suikokai meeting.
Once in political power, a person
is apt to succumb to its lurking demons
that parasitize on the general public.
Please strive to become virtuous, capable men who reject self-interest.
March 1955—Suikokai meeting
Live among the people, fight for them,
and spend your final days by their side.
And also that...
Our political philosophy doesn’t align with either capitalism or socialism.
October 1955—Suikokai meeting
Instead, it is a centrist humanism
grounded in the precepts of Buddhism.
To apply these ideals to people-oriented politics, we must enter the Diet,
the nation’s highest decision-making body,
and reform the political world from within to abolish politics driven by internal party agendas.
Japanese politics is currently
in a state of disarray that cannot be ignored.
That's why we must make haste.
In Osaka, a city of the common people
in the Kansai region,
I want to start a peaceful revolution that will return politics to the hands of the people.
I want to reiterate it once more: campaigning must be carried out fair and square.
You must never force it on anyone
or get so carried away that it turns destructive or breaks the law.
Fight with dignity and honor until the end
and let's win this House of Councillors election!
Can you do it, my friends?
Yes!
With each passing day,
the election campaign
was becoming more and more intense and it was finally entering the final stages.
Good morning!
Hey, good morning!
Be diligent in developing your faith until the last moment of your life.
Otherwise you will have regrets.
For example, the journey from Kamakura
to Kyoto takes twelve days.
If you travel for eleven,
but stop now with only one day remaining,
how can you admire the moon over the capital?
Our situation is the same.
We're just one last push away
from admiring the moon over the capital.
This is a watershed moment!
Let’s steel ourselves,
shake off all complacency,
and fight with unshakable faith
and full resolve to the very end!
Yes!
If we lose after coming this far, we’ll let down the people of Osaka who put their trust in us.
But we'll never let that happen!
Losing is not an option!
Let's win with confidence!
Yes!
To drive Osaka’s growth
as a city of the people,
I plan to reform the tax system
with fairness in mind,
giving small and mid-sized businesses
a real chance to thrive.
I'll fight tooth and nail for you!
Haruki-san, good luck!
Don't forget your promises
when you get there!
There sure are a lot pf people waving to us.
They’re going out of their way
to give us a warm welcome.
Chief was right. If we keep doing this,
it might just work out!
Haruki Seichiro will channel the fighting spirit
he honed on the baseball field
to make sure everyone's voices
are heard in politics!
Good! You have my vote!
The voting day came on July 8th,
and the vote count took place the next day.
Please listen to the noon news.
The vote counting for yesterday’s House
of Councillors election is proceeding smoothly.
As of 11:30 a.m., here’s the latest vote count for the Osaka districts.
Sato Yoshiaki, Liberal Democratic Party,
298,750 votes—elected.
Tsubaki Shigeo, Social Democrats,
215,760 votes—elected.
Haruki Seichiro, non-partisan,
194,860—confirmed elected.
Ah! Confirmed as elected!
We did it! I won!
We won! Won!
Thank god!
Now we're finally worthy of Sensei's support.
I'm truly glad to share this joy
with our Kansai comrades.
But what worries me is Tokyo.
Sensei said it might develop into
a losing battle for us...
Against all odds, candidate Haruki
The Social Democratic Party won 0 seats in the national constituency
How the turntables!
secured third place in the fiercely contested Osaka district House of Councillors race,
"The impossible"
is a reality!
where only three seats were up for grabs.
Everyone said it was impossible,
but now it was reality.
It was, in every sense, a victory
that made the impossible possible.
National constituency candidates Seki and Jujo were also elected,
bringing Soka Gakkai’s total to three seats
in the House of Councillors.
Soka Gakkai Headquarters (Shinanomachi, Tokyo)
I'm finally back!
Oh, welcome back! You've made good use of that long business trip.
Your support at every stage of our struggle
is what made the victory in Osaka possible.
Thank you.
Congratulations. Isn't it great?
Tokyo, which should not have lost, lost,
and Osaka, which should not have won, won.
It seems Tokyo needs to be reminded of the fundamentals of faith.
We got careless and started going through
the motions, so our efforts had no real impact.
But I’m really glad Osaka pulled through, Shin-chan. That was one heck of a fight.
Thank you very much for your hard work.
No, don't mention it.
More importantly,
the public is probably shocked right now.
You can bet the media’s
going to whip up another storm.
We must stay perfectly calm—
there’s nothing to fear.
What had once been a fringe religious group now had three representatives in the Diet—
the media jumped
on the shocking election results
The explosive growth of "Soka Gakkai"
and kept churning out articles full of criticism and slander against the Soka Gakkai.
And then we looked into Soka Gakkai
You're not believing hard enough
Unraveling the mystery of Soka Gakkai
They were all shallow, misguided, and thrown together for amusement—
but to Toda, it was clear that a larger, entrenched power stood behind them,
swaying public opinion.
Shin-chan, there are still many steep mountains ahead on the journey of the Common Path.
Stay sharp, plant your feet with purpose,
and move forward carefully.
Yes—I’d be glad to walk that path with you.
August: To prepare for the rapid spread of the Common Path and a surge in new members,
Ryogoku International Stadium
a sweeping organizational reform was launched, establishing 16 new branches nationwide
August 26th—Branch Formation Conference
Asahikawa
Otaru
Sapporo
Hakodate
Akita
The number of branches has doubled to 32,
and a nationwide system was established,
Niigata
Omiya
Kyoto
Hamamatsu
Nagoya
Matsushima
Senba
Umeda
Okayama
Kochi
Fukuoka
ushering in the new era for the Common Path.
The more influence Soka Gakkai gains in society,
the greater its ability to save the people is,
the clearer the attempts
to block its progress become.
It’s all the demons' doing,
trying to stop the spread of the Common Path.
Sacred Scriptures
To confront and fight it, we need to be fully prepared and armed for the battle ahead.
And we can't take our time...
Which means...
Maybe it’s time I step back
from day-to-day maintenance
and focus on laying
a solid foundation for Soka Gakkai.
Sensei,
I have Daito Trading's
financial results for last month here.
I don't have to worry anymore.
You can walk on your own now.
From now on,
I will leave all management to you.
I trust you guys to not run it into the ground.
Huh?
I would like to take this opportunity to retire from all commercial ventures, not just Daito.
The reasons is because
I can't stick around forever, you see.
I haven't told anyone yet,
but this is my irrevocable decision.
There’s still a mountain of work ahead for the future of Soka Gakkai and the Common Path.
But sadly, my time isn’t limitless.
I’ve got to make the most of each day
in the little time I have left.
Sensei, I understand what you're trying to say.
As you put the final touches on the Common Path,
take good care of yourself—
and don't feel restrained in all that you do!
Yes, thank you.
It's a turning point.
Just as a person faces
many life-changing moments,
so too do nations and organizations
meet their own turning points.
We're standing on one right now.
Both for me and for Soka Gakkai.
Shin-chan, take a look.
The spread of the Common Path
now varies greatly from region to region.
If we keep moving forward
without considering it,
the regions with a large number of households will just keep growing.
But the rural areas with only a handful of households will forever be left behind.
If left alone, this imbalance
will only get worse over time.
It seems to me we need to take
urgent action—right now.
The point of most concern
is the Yamaguchi Prefecture.
Hamakura
Okayama
Hiroshima
Shimane
Yamaguchi
Ehime
Wakayama
Tokushima
Fukuoka
Oita
Kumamoto
430 households?
It's this bad?
That's not right...
Hamakura
Okayama
Hiroshima
Shimane
Yamaguchi
Ehime
Wakayama
Tokushima
Fukuoka
Oita
Kumamoto
There are 2,000 in neighboring Hiroshima,
and even in Shimane, at least 1,000 households.
Indeed, if this issue isn’t addressed,
Yamaguchi Prefecture could become the Achilles' heel the Common Path, just as Sensei warned.
From now on, we must also tend to mobilizing and strengthening our organization
in these untapped and underdeveloped regions.
This is a turning point, after all.
What do you say, Shinichi?
Do you think you can take the lead
at this turning point
and spark a whirlwind of roundtables
and conversions in Yamaguchi Prefecture?
Yes, I'll do it!
After all, Yamaguchi Prefecture
is the birthplace of the Meiji Restoration.
There are gifted, outstanding men
lying dormant there,
who can lead the Common Path to greatness.
I’m sure you can draw them out.
October 9th—Shimonoseki Station
Hey, how is it going?
Is this everyone?
Yes!
Let's head straight to the base, then.
And so, the “Yamaguchi Campaign”—also called the “Yamaguchi Pioneering Guidance”—
October Yamaguchi Campaign
kicked off in Shimonoseki on October 9th,
led by Yamamoto Shinichi,
with members and volunteers
from 32 branches nationwide taking part.
Toyo Inn—center of operations
Hello! Is everyone doing well?
Yes!
Well then, let's start with a short service.
At that time the World-Honored One, wishing to state his meaning once more...
Chief Yamamoto's voice is so lusty,
and the tone is reinvigorating!
So this is how the service supposed to go?
Let's read some Scriptures
before we go out there.
Question: If a person simply chants Nam Myoho Renge Kyo
with no understanding of its meaning,
are the benefits of understanding thereby included?
Some person asked Nichiren Daishonin this.
"If your disciples do not understand the Lotus Sutra at all
and just blindly chant
Nam Myoho Renge Kyo,
what do such people amount to in a spiritual plane?" That's what the question is.
Those disciples are us.
The people of Shimonoseki and we still don't fully understand Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism.
Still, while chanting before the altar,
one might wonder,
“What position will this earn me?
What will I gain in the long run?”
Nichiren Daishonin answers this question as follows:
"Those entrusted with this Sutra
surpass all the founders of other sects,
were Bodhisattvas of great merit
in their past lives,
and are certain to receive boundless blessings in the future."
No way...
Is that true?
I know it's hard for you
to believe right now.
So Daishonin also said...
They are like an infant emperor wrapped in swaddling clothes,
or a great dragon who has just been born.
Do not despise them!
Do not look on them with contempt!
...before finishing his answer.
When the Son of Heaven is still a baby,
crying in swaddling clothes,
how can you believe that he will one day
become the Emperor?
In the same way, we are like babies who know nothing yet and can only believe for now.
We may be poor, sick, and have nothing to our name right now—
but look once more into the scriptures.
"They're bound to end up happier
and more respected than anyone else in the end.
That's what Daishonin guarantees.
The world may look down on us Soka Gakkai members for now,
but as Nichiren Daishonin cautioned,
“It’s foolish to despise my disciples—
they are as precious as the Son of Heaven.”
There's no need to worry about anything.
If you hold the Lotus Sutra in your heart all your life, you will surely be able to lead a fulfilling life.
Let’s make today a fresh start,
grounded in unwavering faith.
Yes!
Hagi
Yamaguchi
Hofu
Ube
Shimonoseki
Morning of the 13th.
October 13th—Hofu City
Shinichi arrived to Hofu city and rushed straight to the inn that served as a base.
Have no worries.
INN
LODGINGS
We prayed with all our hearts
for the smooth progress of propagation.
Won't you agree?
Don't you feel empowered?
Yes!
Try to think about it.
Our fight is that of Buddha's messengers.
And that fight begins with a sincere prayer.
If we do that, we'll be able to work with a firm resolve
to “do whatever it takes to bring forth
the Bodhisattvas of the Earth into this world!”
Only then will the power of Buddha
and the Dharma reveal themselves to you.
Got it!
It'll be fine.
I know you can do it!
Yamaguchi
Hofu
Ube
Tokuyama
On the 14th, Shinichi was in Yamaguchi City,
the prefectural capital.
October 14th—Yamaguchi City
So this is Yamaguchi—the city of history?
It sure has a feel all its own.
Yeah. It's called "Little Kyoto" for a reason.
Saito Inn
The Tokugawa clan’s 300-year reign
was secured by subjugating the Chugoku Region—
putting the Mori clan
squarely under their heel.
If we’re to win the battle for the Common Path,
we’ll have to take Yamaguchi Prefecture first too.
Our struggle is about opening
people’s hearts and minds through compassion and reason, wherever this path takes us.
Let’s triumph in this Yamaguchi struggle
and carve our names into the eternal history
of the Common Path!
Yes.
Yes!
Hagi
Yamaguchi
Ube
Hofu
Tokuyama
Iwakuni
Yanai
On the 15th, Shinichi appeared
at Koike Inn in Iwakuni City.
October 15th—Iwakuni City
Tokuyama
Iwakuni
Yanai
On the 16th, he was in Yanai City.
October 16th—Yanai City
Tokuyama
Yanai
Iwakuni
And on the 17th,
he arrived to Tokuyama...
October 17th—Tokuyama City
Chief, we're off!
Good luck!
Show 'em what's what!
Okay!
We should also get to work...
Yes. I'm looking forward to today's results.
Okay. We won't disappoint you!
All right, later!
Good luck!
Chief,
no matter how much we try
to lift their spirits, it just isn’t working.
So why is it that whenever you appear, everyone immediately becomes cheerful and upbeat?
Oh no, I don't have that kind of power.
I just feel a heightened sense
of mission and duty,
knowing this might be
my one and only time in Yamaguchi.
That’s why every time I speak,
it’s with the firm resolve to leave my mark
on the history of the Common Path here.
Perhaps everyone else here can sense it too.
Hagi
Yamaguchi
Hofu
Tokuyama
Ube
Shimonoseki
Yanai
And on the 18th, Shinichi headed to Ube City.
October 18th—Ube City
Matsuya
Inn
Ube has a wealth of member households
and capable individuals.
It will be a great hub city in the future.
When this month's fighting is done,
I'm sure everyone's selfless work
will show in next month's results.
Tokyo Station
The general meeting at Korakuen Stadium
was a big success,
and we wrapped everything up neatly.
15th Autumn General Meeting (Korakuen Stadium)
All right, then. It's time to jump back into the fight.
Hiroshima
Iwakuni
I have to ensure that everyone
I meet in Yamaguchi is properly trained
November Yamaguchi Campaign
to save both themselves and others.
The Yamaguchi Campaign carried on into November,
November 15th—Iwakuni City
with Shinichi launching the next phase of activities in Iwakuni City on the 15th.
Iwakuni
Yanai
Tokuyama
On the following day, the 16th,
he presided over a roundtable discussion at Kaisakuya Inn, the Yanai City base.
November 16th—Yanai City
Iwakuni
Yanai
Tokuyama
On the 11th, three women came from Hiroshima,
volunteering to join the campaign efforts.
November 17th—Tokuyama
Surely, you don't plan to keep fighting
for the entire duration of the campaign?
No, that's what we wanted to do.
Unthinkable!
A woman mustn't stay away from home
for such a long time.
You should return at once.
No, I can't go home.
My husband told me not to come back
until I achieve my goal.
Same for me!
Please allow us to join in the fight.
Please!
All right.
It's gratifying to know that the Okayama Branch
sent their very best to support us.
Say, how about I write letters
to your husbands?
Please write their names and addresses here.
Your wife is doing well in Tokuyama
and working hard to build a new castle.
-Shinichi Yamamoto
Shinichi made it a priority to value
and look after each one of his subordinates.
Hagi
Yamaguchi
Ube
Hofu
Tokuyama
Shimonoseki
After the battles in Hofu, Ube, and Yamaguchi, Shinichi
set out for Hagi City on the 20th—
the prefecture’s sole base facing the Sea of Japan.
So that's Hagi—
the cradle of the Meiji Restoration?
"The talented champions of the Common Path
must be in the hiding right now..."
That's what Sensei said.
So how much of that talent
can I awaken from their slumber?
That's what my next battle is going to be!
November 20th—Hagi City
On the 21st, Shinichi took time between training sessions and propagation
to visit Hagi’s historic sites, which preserve the legacy of the Meiji Restoration—
Takasugi
Shinsaku's
birthplace
a major turning point in Japan’s history.
Takayoshi
Kido's
birthplace
Shokasonjuku Academy, founded by Yoshida Shoin
An 8 tatami room, a 4.5 tatami room,
and a small 3 tatami room...
Sensei told me about it, but it's vastly different from the fancy Meirinkan school facilities.
Elite Meirinkan school
Still, this place, as small as it may seem,
had produced so many great talents?
Takasugi Shinsaku
Kusaka Genzui
Ito Hirobumi
Indeed, this little town of Hagi
is where Yoshida Shoin and his students kicked off the whole Meiji Restoration.
However,
Yoshida Shoin wasn’t the only
great person from here.
Yoshida Shoin
His disciples were also great,
spreading Shoin's name far and wide.
They gave their lives for a political revolution.
But our goal is a bloodless religious revolution,
in which not a single person will die.
Although it takes place in a different plane, the master-disciple relationship remains the same.
Toda-sensei is a unparalleled leader in the religious world.
He's the great guide.
If we, his students, don’t at least try
to live up to him, then what’s the point?
Just like Hagi once raised leaders
for the Meiji Restoration,
it’s now our turn to help it
produce champions of the Mystic Law
who will fight for peace and happiness
of all the people in the world!
We can only start that process
by achieving greatness ourselves!
Yes!
Every base in the prefecture
is gaining momentum in the fight,
and we keep breaking conversion records.
Organizational development: we're making good progress training and promoting the talents.
Next time I'll come to Yamaguchi...
Okay, let's make it January of the next year.
The last executives' meeting of the year
was held to conclude the activities of 1956.
December 21st—December Executives' Meeting
The total number of households
converted in December is 58,694.
Thanks to everyone’s incredible effort,
we’ve already blown past this year’s goal of 500,000 households!
And so, the 750,000-household goal
that Toda Josei had set when he took office
was now finally within reach.
New Year's Day of 1957
New Year's Day of 1957.
The annual New Year's Service
was held at the Soka Gakkai Headquarters.
Everyone,
what I have here is a New Year's poem
from Sensei. I shall now read it.
Reassuring sight—young people gathered for the Common Path;
They are like orcas among the raging seas.
I'm so glad—Sensei composed
a poem for the youth division.
It's a sign that Sensei has the most appreciation for the youth division.
Our youth division truly are the orcas—
strong and resilient as ever.
Just look at Shinichi—he showed his endurance
in last year's Battle for Osaka.
With Shinichi around,
I know the youth division is in good hands.
Before long, the youth Shinichi had raised
would be like a pod of orcas,
braving the stormy, wicked seas of the Latter Day of the Law in pursuit of the Common Path.
I'm looking forward to that time...
On January 13th Shinichi flew to Hokkaido
After receiving reports that Soka Gakkai members working in the Yubari coal mines
had faced discrimination and harassment from the mine labor union since last July’s election,
Shinichi, serving as deputy head
of the Bunkyo Branch,
Yubari City—Shikanotani Station
rushed to Yubari to offer
his encouragement to the workers.
Chief, good to see you here!
Oh no...
Welcome!
Still, it’s kind of hard to believe that 110,000 people live here.
Wakana Theater
What do you make of the Buddha's position in life?
January 13th—Bunkyo Branch Yubari District Rally
There is no poor Buddha.
There is no ailing Buddha.
So there's no way that you shouldn't be happy too.
It might feel like people around you are giving you a hard time because of your beliefs,
but there's nothing to be afraid of.
Move forward with the tenacity of a lion king,
and stand firm in your faith!
Yeah!
At last, the Yamaguchi Pioneering Guidance
program entered its final phase
January Yamaguchi Campaign
with a rally in Iwakuni on January 21st.
January 21st—Iwakuni
January 22nd—Tokuyama
On the 22nd, Shinichi was in Tokuyama,
then in Hofu on the 23rd,
January 23rd—Hofu
January 24th—Ube
and finally arrived in Ube on the 24th.
Oh, welcome, Chief!
Oh, Branch Chief Okada?
Looks like the Okayama Branch is raring to go!
Yes! I was so excited for your arrival,
I came out to meet you!
Our new recruits brought their friends along
and are waiting for you at the base.
I see. Let's hurry!
It's all okay!
As long as you stay true to your faith, the fulfilling life you’ve dreamed of will surely follow.
Please proceed with peace of mind.
Okay...
So, what do you think?
Will you walk the path of faith with us?
Yes, I'll try my best!
What about you?
Yes, I think I'd also give it a shot.
Congratulations!
Wow, that's a relief!
It's a mystery...
He was so opposed to it before,
so why was he so easily convinced now?
It never works this way for me,
no matter how hard I try.
Ube Labor Hall
Branch Chief Oyama...
Are we really going to hold a rally
at such a large venue?
Yeah, it's all okay.
But with so many vacant seats...
Don't you worry!
We at Senba Branch have been working really hard to fill this place up.
The Okayama Branch
wasn't slacking off either.
All right, I get it.
That's truly impressive. Just four months ago,
Ube barely had a dozen households...
Yes!
Yes.
Our growth was so explosive that we'll need to ask for a district to be formed at once.
I see.
Born as a Japanese man,
standing on the battlefield
Cherish your name, you, the warrior
It's just as Oyama-san said.
When it's time to fall, fall honorably
We've completely filled up this large venue.
Like the sakura petals scattering back home
Yamaguchi has now firmly joined
the flow of the Common Path.
Even the most compassionate man,
I'm sure the Lotus Sutra will keep growing endlessly with its own power
on this new fertile ground from now on!
when he takes up the right sword...
The Yamaguchi Campaign, which spanned three months—October, November, and January—
led to a tenfold increase in the number of Soka Gakkai households in Yamaguchi Prefecture,
End of September—459 households
End of January—4,073 households
from 459 at the end of September
to 4,073 by the end of January.
It was a truly great victory,
concluding this Battle for Yamaguchi.
Even in sparsely populated
and neglected areas,
with enough cultivation effort, you can turn them into fertile ground for the Common Path.
The resounding success
of the Yamaguchi Campaign
demonstrated to every branch across the country how it's done,
leading to an increasing focus on guidance and propagation from local bases.
And so, the wave of propagation was now spreading evenly
to every nook and cranny of the Japanese archipelago.
But soon after, two unprecedented and monumental incidents occurred,
threatening to destroy
the beautiful unity of Soka Gakkai
and impede the progress of the Common Path.
Osaka detention center
The "Osaka Incident"
and the "Coal Miners Union Issue."
Yubari Coal Mine
Toda Josei and Yamamoto Shinichi—
a teacher and his disciple—
would once again hurl themselves
at the barricades
to protect their followers
and champion justice for the Soka Gakkai.
Soka Gakkai
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr, Muzussawa,
True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 17
The End