A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 18        Yubari
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
April of 1957.
Once again, the city of Osaka
was swept up in the national elections.
Tsutenkaku Tower, rebuilt last October
April 1957.
The by-election for the House of Councillors
in the Osaka constituency
was announced on March 29th.
Though the race lacked excitement
with eight candidates vying for a single seat,
Oyama Tatsuzo, endorsed by the Soka Gakkai,
campaigned passionately throughout the prefecture,
steadily winning over voters with his policies.
Soka Gakkai Kansai Headquarters
I'd like to talk about
the fundamentals of our next battle.
1st: election fraud will not be tolerated.
First and foremost:
election fraud will not be tolerated.
Second: our religious guidance
cannot be shallow.
2nd: our religious guidance cannot be shallow.
3rd: don't take the elections lightly.
Third: don't take the elections lightly.
As citizens of this nation, it's our duty to campaign with everything we've got—
within the bounds of election law—and I'm certain that doing so will lead us to victory!
Yes!
As the mid-April by-election entered its final stretch,
the race grew increasingly chaotic amid an unexpected surge
in support for candidate Oyama.
Oyama's campaign promises
struck a chord with voters,
and the growing wave of popular support
for him began to rattle his rivals.
Pitted against the two major parties—
the Liberals and the Socialists—
Oyama was initially dismissed
as a long-shot, desperation candidate.
However, the race has turned into a fierce three-way battle,
with the outcome now anyone’s guess.
It was then, on April 22nd,
the day before the election,
during the final stretch of the campaigning efforts, when a sudden incident occurred.
What did you say?
Reception
Someone was handing out cigarettes
with Oyama's name on them in front
of the employment office in Taisho Ward?
Of course it's important!
Get in touch with Chief Yamamoto at once!
Also bring those cigarettes
to the Kansai Headquarters!
Combining on-site reports and the evening news, this is what we know to date.
Early this morning, a man arrived by taxi at four employment offices
in Taisho, Nishi, Minato, and Fukushima wards, handing out to the day laborers gathered there
hundreds of packs of Pearl Light cigarettes.
Then he disappeared on the streets.
Vote for cigarettes!
Oyama’s name, written in katakana,
was printed on the flaps of those cigarette packs.
Here's one pack as a proof.
That's all.
Reportedly, around 8 p.m. tonight,
someone was seen distributing 100-yen bills
attached to Oyama’s business cards
in the Ajiro area of Fuse City
and along Katsuyama Street in Ikuno Ward.
It seems they were also distributing them
to passersby while riding bicycles
around Shigino in Joto Ward
and Nagare in Oyodo Ward.
They even went that far?
Chief! It’s got to be another party trying to discredit Oyama-san in the eyes of the voters.
That's gotta be it!
All right, immediately contact the Election Security Office
and file a protest in the name
of Oyama’s Election Office.
On election day, the 23rd,
all the morning newspapers ran headline stories
about this major bribery scandal.
With Oyama’s reputation in shambles
and now at a huge disadvantage,
they could only watch
as the polls closed as usual.
April 24th, the day of the vote count
That day, on his way back from a lecture in Kyushu, Toda stopped by the Kansai HQ
and waited in the president’s office
for the election results.
Okawa Mitsuzo, LDP.
239,409 votes.
Murao Shigeo, SDP.
236,880 votes.
Oyama Tatsuzo, non-partisan.
151,823 votes.
The gap is a lot more than before!
How was it?
We lost.
Sensei, please forgive us.
Sensei, I have disgraced you.
I’d like to request dismissal from all of my current positions.
What are you saying?!
Shinichi, in a battle you always win or lose.
That’s the nature of battle.
But you live to fight another day.
Fight to the bitter end!
Sensei, forgive me!
Someday, I'll definitely put up a fight
that'll take the world by storm!
Good.
That's what I wanted to hear.
And so, within less than a year of his assignment to Osaka,
Shinichi tasted both the thrill of a triumphant election win and the sting of a heartbreaking loss.
May 19th—Shinichi Yamamoto's house in Tokyo
Wh-What?!
"The Coal Miners' Union has resolved
to take measures against new religious groups?"
Measures
against
new
religions
Chikuho Coal Mine, Kyushu
Among the many labor organizations, one stood out for its formidable sway across Japan—
Yubari Coal Mine, Hokkaido
especially in the coal mining regions
of Kyushu and Hokkaido:
the Japan Coal Miners' Union, said to be so fearsome it could silence even a crying child.
At the 17th regular meeting of the Coal Miners' Union,
Central Labor Relations Committee Hall, Tokyo
held at the Central Labor Relations Committee Hall in Shiba, Tokyo,
a new policy of countermeasures against emerging religious groups was adopted—
chiefly aimed at Soka Gakkai.
This is outrageous.
When I went to Yubari in January,
January—Yubari
I heard about bullying and mistreatment of the members among miners.
And now that institutionalized injustice
is bound to become even more prevalent.
The house of Mitsubayashi, who runs a dance hall
Mitsubayashi-san, Arakawa-san,
what exactly entails this "unjustified oppression
and harassment" by the miners' union?
Well, for example, small loans from labor banks require approval from the welfare commission.
But the union leaders never allow that.
Some even openly say, "We'll only lend to you if you renounce Soka Gakkai."
Hm?
Not only that, but when we apply
for roof repairs to the miner barracks we live in
or ask for new mats, our comrades are always sidelined or even told they don't care.
That's terrible.
Why would they do that?
I think it's because we didn't support the candidate that the union endorsed
in the last House of Councillors election.
But even the Coal Miners' Union has no right
to interfere with one's right to vote.
It's also a violation of our constitutionally protected freedom of religion.
We know that...
They wouldn't directly say
it was because of the election,
but they resented the significant drop
in the union's votes
and blamed the Soka Gakkai members
for weakening the union's power and disrupting worker unity.
Since then, we've been subjected
to constant harassment and oppression.
Either way, Soka Gakkai will have
to step in and resolve that issue for good.
Yubari Coal Mine—Hokkaido
Beware of fake religions!
"We need to have a serious talk with five Soka Gakkai executives working at Mine No. 2, including Arakawa Shozo. After leaving the mine, gather at the guardhouse at 4 p.m."
All right, let's face them!
We've not done anything wrong!
We've seen your invitation.
Now what?
We want anyone who disrupts the union's authority to leave the union immediately.
That's what!
What?! When and where did anyone ever disrupt their control?
Don't play dumb! Try to think about it,
with your hand on your heart!
Now, now, let's not get emotional,
or this conversation won't go anywhere.
Let's try to talk things over calmly.
Sit down, please.
You're just full of hot air!
There's no way you can substantiate that!
Are you kidding me? Soka Gakkai always opposes the union's policies!
Now that's new.
In the past, during labor disputes,
haven't Soka Gakkai members
always stood with the other union members?
Your argument is incredulous!
The talks went nowhere
and ended without any resolution.
Toda's house in Shirokane, Tokyo
That's the situation in Yubari, according to both branch heads—Mitsubayashi and Arakawa.
I want to move quickly to guarantee
that Soka Gakkai members on-site
can practice their faith safely.
Yes, very well.
Send the youth division leaders.
You should be ready to fly at any time too.
Yes, that was my plan.
Still, it's incredible how wrong
the Miners' Union is.
Labor and religious organizations
have completely different goals and duties.
And since our spheres of interest
are so different,
there is no reason for us
to interfere with each other.
What a weird happening indeed...
A few days later, at a small factory in Oyodo Ward, Osaka
The work is finally done and dusted with.
I wonder if there's been any interesting news...
Uh? What the hell!
"The cigarette handout incident and the 100 yen
note incident were Soka Gakkai's doing?!"
Supporters
from Tokyo
Damned if we let them
get away with this bollocks!
I gotta let Branch Chief Haruki know at once!
Soka Gakkai Headquarters (Shinanomachi, Tokyo)
Second President's Office
Yesterday evening's paper reported that Omura Masato, a Soka Gakkai district chief,
was the mastermind behind the pre-election cigarette and 100-yen bill handout incidents.
Four have been arrested already.
The investigation revealed that Omura and 30 others handed out cigarettes
in front of 10 prefectural employment offices
on the morning before the election,
and that same evening,
distributed 100-yen bills
across Osaka and other areas
before retreating to Tokyo.
That Omura Masato...
If I remember correctly...
It has to be the district head Omura
of the Kamata branch.
What did you say?
But I'm sure he wasn't part
of the campaign team for this election.
Yeah…
Unbelievable...
He was probably raring for recognition
and wanted to distinguish himself somehow...
Kiyohara-san, I believe the leadership needs
to determine whether this was simply a reckless,
unilateral act by a few overzealous members,
or part of a larger plot aimed at discrediting Soka Gakkai. Will you see to it?
Certainly. Soka Gakkai needs to shed light
on this and take immediate and firm action.
Yes, start an investigation as soon as possible.
Okay.
The Hokkaido Coal Miners' Union adopted
a more aggressive stance toward Soka Gakkai,
escalating the hostility;
on June 27, it formed a special committee
to deal with dissidents for good
June 27th: Hokkaido Miners' Union announces
3-month "Anti-Soka Gakkai" campaign
and issued a directive to all branches
and coal mines across the prefecture,
setting a firm deadline for the expulsion
of Soka Gakkai members.
Unaware of this, branch chief Mitsubayashi was on his way
to the Yubari Miners' Union office that day.
With the persecution of Soka Gakkai members worsening by the day,
he resolved to meet the union president face-to-face to lodge a formal protest.
Hokkaido News Yubari Branch Chief
If it isn't Mitsubayashi-san!
Oh, editor-in-chief!
Good timing.
I was on my way to the miners' union office to issue a protest.
Would you like to come along?
Sounds good. Let's go.
Yubari Miners' Union Office
I told you already! Get me the union executive—
I need to talk to him personally!
I don't care what you believe in,
but you'll need to stop proselytizing around here.
Your members are a thorn in our side!
What are you talking about?
Propagation is the lifeblood of faith!
Our constitution also guarantees
the freedom of proselytizing!
Is your union trying to obstruct it?
It's a violation of the constitution!
Our missionary work is aimed at saving as many people as we can from misery!
Why would we ever stop?!
Excuse me for a moment...
How cowardly can they be?
The union executive is right there in that room,
but he wouldn't even show himself!
Mitsubayashi-san, this isn't going anywhere.
So what are we going to do?
We could arrange a formal meeting
to hold a discussion on this matter.
A public debate, huh?
All right, at this stage,
we can't take a step back!
What do you say?
Just so we're clear—are you proposing a public debate between Soka Gakkai and your union?
That option is also among the possibilities.
Fine by me! A debate is fine.
Very well, we accept it!
So, when and where
are we going to have it?
We will contact you again
for details such as a date and the venue.
All right.
Editor-in-chief, won't you be our witness?
Yes, happily.
Following that, the secretary-general
of the Yubari Miners' Union reached out to him
and said, "We’d like to hold a debate on July 4th at the Yubari Labor Hall,
with ten representatives from each side."
Yubari Telephone Office
...That's what they said.
Yes, I'll tell everyone in Yubari.
But what about the Chief?
Got it. We'll be waiting.
Soka Gakkai
I see... It all piled up on us at the same time?
Reception room #1
It appears that the Osaka Prefectural Police are preparing
to charge Chairman Konishi and
PR Department Chief Yamamoto with bribery
and door-to-door canvassing.
What's going on? Are they trying to frame these two for a crime they didn't commit?
The prosecutor is relentless.
Attorney Ozawa
I think it's safe to assume
that they'll stop at nothing.
So, are they about to move in to arrest them?
Yes, that's what it looks like.
Let them come!
I'll accept everything with a smile on my face.
Not only in Yubari, Hokkaido, but also in Osaka, the darkest cloud in Soka Gakkai’s history
was gathering above it, with a storm brewing, ready to come crashing down all at once.
Yubari Station
Well, I'll be leaving for Sapporo now
to meet Chief Yamamoto.
Got it. I'll get everything prepared here.
However, on the following day, the 29th,
an unexpected development
had turned the situation upside-down.
Um...
Hm?
A man at the door says he’s the head of public relations for the Yubari Miners’ Union...
The Union's PR head?
But why so suddenly?
All right, let's meet him.
I'm Sawada, I came here from Tokyo to help
with the preparations for the upcoming debate.
PR head, what was it
you wanted to discuss?
Um... I'm not really sure how to put it...
About the debate we scheduled yesterday—
we'd like it postponed... indefinitely.
What did you say?
I'm really sorry...
You see, we were already planning
to launch a strike in July,
so we don't happen to have any time or resources
to prepare for debates and such.
What are you talking about?
Your side’s the one that proposed the debate.
Hell, you’re the one who started all this!
Do you think we've got
no other business to tend to?!
I came all the way from Tokyo to do this,
and I can't return empty-handed!
We'll hold it as planned!
Please, you have to understand.
We're really busy, you see. I said sorry, didn't I?
Hey, Arakawa-san, at least say something!
No, that ain't gonna do.
What were you thinking, harassing Soka Gakkai members all this time?!
No backing out now!
There's no way we can attend those debates!
What’s with this sudden change of mind?
We need to inform Chief Yamamoto right away!
June 29th—Mitsubayashi's house
Hey, everyone! How are you?
Cheer up and keep it that way. Now that I'm here, there's nothing to worry about.
Have no worries, everyone!
Okay!
How can we lose in a fight for religious freedom and the happiness of the people?
We are sure to win!
The next day, Shinichi
requested a meeting with the Miners' Union’s PR head twice—in the morning and in the afternoon—
but was turned down, first with the excuse
of a meeting, and later due to a reported fever.
Yubari City—Shogetsu Inn
I can relate to everyone's frustration
and anger all too keenly.
This abrupt shift in the Yubari Miners' Union’s stance
may have been directed by the Coal Miners' Union headquarters in Tokyo.
Perhaps it dawned on them that the Union’s policy
Article 20 of Japan's Constitution
guarantees freedom of religion
infringes on the workers’ religious freedoms—
and might be deemed unconstitutional.
So they called off the debate at the last minute
as a form of damage control.
The fact that they turned me down twice
makes it clear the union
has lost all will to engage in a debate.
But that's not the end of our troubles,
not by a long shot.
The union will likely keep coming up with new methods to harass Soka Gakkai members.
That’s why, this time, I’m determined to settle this once and for all—
so our comrades in Yubari are never subjected to mistreatment again.
We’ll do it in the form of protest rallies
against the Miners’ Union—
one in Sapporo on July 1st,
and another in Yubari on July 2nd.
On June 30th, amidst the raging storm
of the Miners’ Union issue,
June 30th—Azabu Public Hall, Tokyo
the formation meeting
of the Soka Gakkai Student Division took place
Student Division formation meeting
at the Azabu Public Hall in Minato Ward, Tokyo,
marking a new chapter
in the history of the Common Path.
The student division formation ceremony is to be held today.
I should send the students a congratulatory telegram, wishing them a bright future.
We have received a congratulatory telegram from Chief Yamamoto in Yubari, Hokkaido.
“Congratulations on the formation
of the Student Division,
where brilliant minds of the new century
have come together.
Soar boldly into the world under President Toda’s leadership. —Yamamoto Shinichi”
So this is what the former nitpickers
from the Tokyo University
Lotus Sutra Study Group have grown into?
There's quite a lot of female students too...
Greetings from the Director of Student Affairs Shiroya!
I hope today marks a turning point for you—
where you not only
dedicate yourselves to your studies,
but also bloom into true talents who distinguish themselves in Soka Gakkai activities.
Everyone keeps saying
our student division is dwindling—
yet here you are,
500 bright minds strong.
I can by no means call it a small number.
If only half of you become executives
and the other half become professors, wouldn't that be more than enough?
If we can succeed in raising even that number of leaders,
that alone would surely throw into a tizzy
those the world currently holds up as its leaders.
Personally, I'm more than happy
with this number.
You have my undivided support!
Moreover, on the 30th,
the authorities finally closed in on Shinichi’s inner circle with the intent to arrest him.
Sapporo Inn "Reisui Villa"
Yamamoto needs to report himself to the Osaka Prefectural Police?
All right.
But right now it's impossible.
Please wait a day or two.
We can do this the hard way—
an arrest warrant won’t take long.
What are you saying?! Yamamoto Shinichi
isn't trying to run away or hide!
What difference would a day or two
of delay make for you?
So you're saying we can come for him on July 3rd?
That's right.
Are you sure?
I am sure!
July 1st—Soka Gakkai Sapporo rally
So the Osaka Police finally summoned me?
Three days... All right, we can't lose this!
I'll fight them head on!
Unilateral decision
of the Miners' Union
The Sapporo rally opened at 6 p.m.
The 13,000 attendees who packed the hall
were outraged by the revelations
The union is
building feudalism
of the Coal Miners’ persecution of Soka Gakkai members,
Union's leaders must
reflect on their actions
making the convention a rousing success.
Pointing to the drop in votes during the election,
they’ve blamed Soka Gakkai members for the alleged anti-union behavior—
even going so far as to unconstitutionally interfere with their religious activities!
As a society, we can by no means overlook it!
That's right! That's right!
Yeah!
Nichiren Daishonin said...
When the skies are clear,
the ground is illuminated.
Similarly, when one knows the Lotus Sutra,
one understands all worldly affairs.
In other words, by continually meditating and improving on the basics of your faith,
you can pave the way to success in your work or business and by extension—your personal growth.
That’s why we strive to integrate our faith
into every aspect of daily life—
our work, our routines,
and our union activities.
This is the correct way forward
and the guiding principle of Soka Gakkai.
Sadly, the Miners’ Union
not only refuses to understand this,
but has also aligned itself
with destructive forces,
actively obstructing Soka Gakkai's efforts
to save the people and build a peaceful world.
This appearance of the three formidable enemies is proof that the fulfillment
of the Common Path is near at hand!
On July 2nd, a demonstration march by the Soka Gakkai Youth Division began in Yubari City.
July 2nd—Yubari City
Born as a Japanese man, standing on the battlefield
Young men from Tokyo and Sapporo
Cherish your name, you, the warrior
marched with pride and dignity through the city
alongside the Yubari Men’s Youth Division.
When it's time to fall, fall honorably
We won't tolerate the union’s tyranny!
Like the sakura petals scattering back home
We'll correct their wrongs and elevate
Soka Gakkai's righteousness without flinching!
Even the most compassionate man,
Soka Gakkai launched a protest against the union
who can even silence a crying child!
when he takes up the righteous sword,
Quite the nerve they've got...
Good luck, youth division boys!
will not hesitate to fight a million men...
You can do it!
Soka Gakkai Yubari Rally
Reception
Which branch are you from?
Why should we be from any branch?
Can't outsiders join your little party?
There are separate seats prepared
for non-Soka Gakkai members.
I’m a Yubari Miners’ Union executive—
I came to hear your convention.
You'll let us in, won't you?
Yes, I'll arrange it now, please wait.
I'm Yamamoto, in charge here.
You're welcome to attend.
However, I would ask you to listen patiently until we fully explain Soka Gakkai's position.
We can have a discussion afterwards.
All right.
Then at 6 p.m., the Soka Gakkai Yubari Rally
finally began at the Wakana Theater in Yubari, where the clash with the Miners' Union started.
The leaders of the Miners’ Union keep claiming they care about their members’ welfare,
but their actions show they’re only ever thinking about their own self-interest!
That's right! Exactly!
Soka Gakkai
Yubari Rally
Huh?
Didn't you promise the Chief
to have a discussion afterwards?
Something urgent just came to mind…
P-Please wait a moment!
You're the Secretary General
of the Yubari Miners' Union, right?
Since you've come all the way here,
why don't we have a discussion?
No, actually, there's an urgent matter waiting for me at home right now...
Not even for a short while?
No, I'm afraid not.
That's a shame.
I hope I'll see you again.
With that said,
the Yubari convention is concluded!
This should see the Union issue
finally settled for now.
July 3rd—first leg of Shinichi's journey—to Haneda Airport
It's July 3rd today...
That's right! July 3rd is the day
Toda-sensei was released from prison.
And I'll be imprisoned on that same day...
What an eerie coincidence.
Haneda Airport
Shin is not here yet?
He'll be here soon enough.
I hear the plane has just landed.
When Konishi turned himself in to the Osaka Police earlier, he was arrested immediately.
If they're going to do the same to Shinichi next...
Shinichi, who has to report to the Osaka Prefectural Police today,
landed at Haneda Airport
to transfer to a flight to Osaka.
He had only a little time to transfer.
Sensei is waiting for you.
Huh? He's here?
Sensei!
I've just landed.
Oh! Shinichi...
I ended up worrying Sensei so much...
A senior union official
came to yesterday's rally in Yubari...
I know, they called me last night.
Shin-chan, you've done well. I mean it.
Shinichi, keep going.
Okay.
Shinichi.
Our spiritual battle for the spread of Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism and the Common Path
still needs to be fought in the real world.
The deeper we plant our roots in the real world,
the more resistance we’re bound to face.
That is something entirely unavoidable!
No matter what difficulties arise,
we have no choice but to fight back!
No matter what great hardships lie ahead,
Shinichi, keep going!
Yes, I will.
Good.
Sensei, how is your health?
You ought to worry
about your own health first.
Shinichi, don't die.
You cannot die.
Shinichi, if ever...
If you were ever to die,
I’d rush over to your side,
throw myself over you,
and die with you then and there!
Sensei depends on me that much...
I absolutely will not lose!
No matter what great hardships befall us,
we will fight through them.
As Sensei's disciple,
I will fight with all my might!
Chief, it's about to take off.
Coming.
Shinichi, we finally published it.
Read it sometime later.
The
Human
Revolution
by Myogoku
Stay strong.
Okay.
Honey...
Thanks.
It'll be fine. Don't worry!
Look after the kids.
Chief, you need to hurry!
Bye.
Reading "The Human Revolution" by Sensei
let's you experience vividly
the intense struggles he faced while in prison.
Makiguchi-sensei!
Don't be harsh on him!
Makiguchi is dead.
I get it!
The Buddha is life itself!
It's the quality of being alive!
Sadly, I too will soon follow Makiguchi-sensei and Toda-sensei into imprisonment.
All right, I'll fight with determination!
Toda-sensei is a lion.
If so, as his faithful disciple,
I also have to become a lion.
The day of reckoning has come—
and it'll show if I have the lion in me.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr
True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 18
The End