The great human revolution, occurring in one -
before long, it'll define the fate of the nation.
Furthermore, it could one day remold
the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 4         Garden of Life
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
You seem to be pretty excited, Sakata-kun.
Yes. You've appointed Iwata-san the dispatched roundtable moderator,
so I decided I also need
to rise to his level as soon as possible.
I see. Good to know our young men department is so full of vim and vigor.
But Iwata also needs to learn to control himself, let's not forget that.
January 1949
Soka Gakkai Headquarters
You can't let your authoritative role go to your head.
The other day, you kept talking to yourself for hours.
A roundtable discussion
is where everyone can have a word.
Yes, sir!
I'll pay more attention now!
Whoa there, no need to put on
such an intimidating look.
That'll be sure to scare everyone away.
Roundtable discussions
are not just for young men.
We welcome the newcomers and young ladies as well.
The society may become an infinitely dark and bleak place, but our meetings
must remain the beacon
of light and hope for the people,
where the most courageous conversations take place.
Around that time, Soka Gakkai was actively intensifying its roundtable-related activity.
As many as 38 roundtable discussions
were held every month
at locations in Tokyo and nearby prefectures.
Since the beginning of that year, Toda had been training and nurturing
the new roundtable moderators
to attend those in his stead.
Morikawa-kun had hardly been showing up since this year started.
I hear he's starting a diner...
I can't help but wonder about his family's circumstances and if his piety stands strong.
Besides, the members of our Tsurumi Branch
must be very upset to hear that Morikawa-kun,
a man of pure faith,
has been fired from his company.
Three Meals a Day Coupon Diner
Sensei...
I'm so sorry for not visiting you in a long while.
Thank you for coming all the way to Tsurumi.
Missus!
I'm out of soy sauce!
Coming!
Well then, take your time.
Morikawa Koji, the linchpin of the Tsurumi Branch in Kanagawa Prefecture,
Credit Union "Hope"
resigned from the credit union where he had worked for many years, just last year.
The union executives, repulsed by Morikawa's strong sense of justice and outspoken opinions,
conspired to force him to resign.
They made it look like he asked for a resignation himself.
Morikawa then began operating a diner, something he was not accustomed to,
in the hope of doing something
to help people
in these times when food was scarce.
Restaurant Ichiba
So, Morikawa-kun,
is your business going well?
Yes. It brings in just enough to keep my family fed.
I see.
More importantly, it's such an honor to have you
come to our roundtable discussion today!
Thank you kindly!
Oh no, I'm just glad to see you're doing well.
Morikawa-kun is the same as usual,
nothing to worry about.
The real problem will be...
As you probably know,
Morikawa-kun was fired from his company.
Don't you find it strange that it happened
to someone whose faith was so strong?
Gentlemen?
Sensei, to be honest,
I do find it troubling.
Oh?
At a roundtable discussion, Morikawa-san said,
"I was fired from my company,
but I'll try to turn this poison into medicine."
That's when everyone's faith
began to waver.
Don't speak for everyone,
just because your own faith did.
"With faith, I'll turn poison into medicine."
Turn poison into medicine
Through the merits of Buddha,
and through our faith,
we can transform poison into something beneficial.
Doesn't it sound natural to you?
If so, how can it make your faith waver?
Could it be that you don't understand what faith is?
No! I do understand that.
In his scriptures,
Nichiren states,
"Once you turn to the Buddha,
the three obstacles and four devils
will start fighting within you."
It is easy to understand through reason, but that is not the same as understanding it through faith.
Didn't you just say that what happened to Morikawa is troubling?'
If you truly understood it,
you wouldn't be complaining.
But really, you don't understand, do you?
It's not Morikawa-kun I'm worried about.
It's you, our Tsurumi followers.
While amusing yourselves at the fact Morikawa was fired for his strong faith,
not a single one of you
came to me for guidance!
Instead, when you get together,
you call it "troubling"
and use it as a pretext
to criticize and doubt each other.
That's what scares me the most
as a Buddhist.
If something were to happen to you,
you'd accept it as Buddha's will.
But when it becomes another's lot,
doubting and losing your own faith...
is the most foolish!
I'd hate to see you behave so foolishly, my friends!
So, did that give you a better understanding?
Yes!
Morikawa-kun's problem has already been resolved.
You'll understand it once you've observed it for a bit longer.
Thank god, you're still here.
Oh, Kazumasa-kun?
While they were seeing him off,
Toda gave Morikawa and his eldest son Kazumasa guidance and encouragement.
And just as Toda had said, within a year, Morikawa Koji
was offered a position on favorable terms
at a credit union in Kawasaki.
Nihon Shogakkan (Soka Gakkai Headquarters)
I got us the illustrations
and a manuscript of a short story.
And then I also got him to agree to write a serialized novel for our new project.
Huh? Seriously?
Yeah!
Did you really get that writer
to work with us at our manuscript fee?
Yes. I told him about the editorial policy of “Adventure Boy”
and my personal vision for the magazine.
When I finished, he said,
"Okay, I understand," and graciously agreed.
Here it is,
the Great White Lotus project.
Let's see.
It was decided to publish a new journal,
"The Great White Lotus,"
in place of "Value Creation" journal,
so a planning meeting was held
with Konishi, Yamadaira and other editors.
That's it, Sensei.
We should by all means include
a column for personal experiences and one for refuting the dogmas of other sects.
Don't you agree?
Where do you think the false religious views
of a modern man come from?
I think bringing that to light
is the mission of the Great White Lotus.
Yamadaira-kun, I agree with you and I support that.
But let's consider it for a minute.
How can you be sure our readers will appreciate that?
Becoming self-righteous in image,
like all the other sects, won't do us any good.
I suppose... You're right.
The days of saying this and that
in a language that only our fellow academics and clergy can understand are gone.
We're long past the times when you could merely provide
arguments that only work in the religious plane and call it a day.
We need to be more vocal, broaden our horizons, open our doors to everyone.
Why not make the magazine available to all kinds of educated people, or just those
familiar with the history of Buddhism?
You guys are anxious about how it'll turn out, aren't you?
Worry not, for Buddhism encompasses all schools of thought and philosophies.
That holistic nature is the main strength
of the Buddha Dharma.
Okay. I'll write for it myself!
Toda
Late at night, Toda was at home,
working on a philosophical article,
"The Theory of Life,"
to be published in The Great White Lotus.
The Theory of Life
Toda Josei
That reminds me...
Back then, I was also confined to a small room like this one,
pacing back and forth
like an animal in a cage.
March 1944
Sugamo Tokyo Detention House
The opening text of the Lotus Sutra,
the Innumerable Meanings Sutra
I lose the thread whenever I get to this piece.
34 negations in a row...
What purpose does this passage serve?
I just don't understand it...
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
Starting from New Year's Day, Toda resolved to chant and recite
the Lotus Sutra prayer 10,000 times a day
and he stuck to this plan.
He had already reread the Lotus Sutra three times and was now
on his fourth attempt in March.
And when he was once again faced with a Sutra
with 34 "not's" written across 12 lines,
he resolved not to go a single step further until he could be sure that he understands it fully.
His body is neither present nor absent...
He doesn't have a physical body.
Yes he's not immaterial either.
The Buddha's body in this world is not something that exists, nor is it something nonexistent.
Something that's not there...
Something that's not absent...
It's not square, nor is it round.
It's not short, nor is it long.
It can't move, it can't roll,
neither is it immovable.
What on earth could that be?
I don't understand.
These 34 negations cannot be just meaningless padding.
He's definitely describing something that does exist!
But what?
Late March
It's not present,
neither is it absent.
Not square,
neither round.
Not short,
nor long.
What on Earth is he trying to describe?
There is absolutely no way that the Lotus Sutra is just an idealistic chatter.
The Buddha's body...
It can't be something so mysterious
you can't even imagine it.
It's not created artificially.
Nor did it appear spontaneously.
It's not moving,
neither does it stand still.
And it definitely has to be real...
Neither present nor absent
Life
Life!
That's it! It's the life!
It's the quality of being alive!
I get it now!
His body... The Buddha himself
is the epitome of life!
I was looking for something that's outside,
but it's the very life of mine!
Life
No! He is present outside too!
He embodies all life in the universe!
"Buddha is life itself,"
having concluded that, Toda finally read through all the 34 negations
and could continue reading the Lotus Sutra.
Around this time,
a new question formed in Toda's mind.
That said, what exactly did the Buddha
want to teach us through these 28 chapters of the Lotus Sutra?
If the Lotus Sutra is the most important sacred teaching of Buddhism, then what is its essence?
What is the truth of the Lotus Sutra?
This second question became Toda's new obsession.
Awake or asleep, he kept asking himself, "What is the essence of the Lotus Sutra?"
He spent days chanting and meditating,
trying to uncover the answer.
In mid-November, the number of times he chanted the Sutra
since the New Year's Day was approaching two million.
On one such morning...
What a refreshing feeling...
Without a doubt,
it's the Buddha Realm.
All the Bodhisattvas of the Earth are here.
And I am one of them right now!
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
That's right.
There's nothing strange about it.
All the countless Bodhisattvas of the Earth,
numbering 60,000 times the grains of sand of the Ganges River...
I was one of them!
And the head priest,
the Ascended Bodhisattva...
It was none other
than Nichiren Daishonin himself!
"Sacred Mountain Meeting
Stands Solemnly Strong."
The meeting at the sacred mountain still stands strong and has not yet dispersed!
That's it.
My whole life is decided now.
I will spend the rest of my days
spreading this precious Great Law!
At the same time, old and ill,
Makiguchi Tsunesaburo
was held in a solitary cell
of a separate building.
Infirmity and malnutrition exacted a heavy toll on Makiguchi's health,
Makiguchi Tsunesaburo,
first president of the Soka Gakkai
so on November 17th, he moved voluntarily to a hospital room within the detention center.
And on the following day, the 18th,
he passed away peacefully
at the end of his noble, 73-year-long life.
At that time, Toda had no way of knowing about Makiguchi's death.
The Great Buddha, Daishonin-sama,
I am grateful to no end.
Having realized the mysterious reality of life through his "enlightenment in prison," Toda
proceeded to describe his experience in the opening article of "The Great White Lotus."
While many armchair theorists
philosophize for the sake of philosophizing,
Toda positioned his paper
as applied philosophy.
Toda's strong yearning for the happiness of all people led to the creation of his chef-d'oeuvre,
the philosophical treatise
"The Theory of Life,"
which would go on to open the way to the Buddhist Dharma for the broad masses.
Okay, that should be enough for today.
Almost there.
Late June
Let's call it a day, then.
Sensei! Toda-sensei!
We finished printing it!
Yes, it came out nicely.
The long-awaited new journal from Soka Gakkai,
The Great White Lotus, has been delivered.
The first issue, freshly printed, was distributed ahead of its publication date of July 10, 1949.
Toda and the Soka Gakkai members were overjoyed.
The Brandenburg Gates
Germany splits into East and West. Conflict deepens.
The conflict between East and West
is growing ever-deeper.
Communist offensive continues on the Chinese mainland
The Soviet Union tests its first atomic bomb in the Central Asian desert
Soviet Union announces possession of atomic weapons to contain the threat from the US.
The Cold War is growing more and more intense.
Hibiya GHQ (Allied Powers High Command)
Compelled to change its occupation policy towards Japan
Japan is a barrier against the eastward advance of communism, General MacArthur declares
Belief in the role of the national assembly in promoting peace, not just propaganda
and turn it into a bulwark against communism, the US orders the Japanese government
Minister and Economic Adviser to the Supreme Commander for the Allied Powers, Dodge (GHQ)
to enact the "Nine Principles for Economic Stability," also known as Dodge Plan.
Nine principles for economic stability
It hastened the recovery of Japanese economy's self-reliance.
JNR issues first round of layoff notice to 30,700 employees yesterday
And for that reason, the society...
Deflationary 42 billion yen:
next year's funding program
Nippon Electric to lay off 3,000 employees;
proposes downsizing to union
More returns!
We're seeing a gradual increase in returns,
and if we keep ending up in the red,
the banks won't give us any more loans.
I know that.
As I've been saying for a long time,
the days when you could make anything and it would sell are over.
Sensei, if we don't do something about it,
we'll all end up on the street!
Okay, I heard you.
We'll come up with something good to make.
And then we'll see what we can do.
Counting on you, sir!
The one thing selling well now
is the "Adventure Boy."
Women's magazine "Ruby" is in decline.
Perhaps, Mishima-kun was not cut out to work on periodicals, after all.
I'll try to put the young Sato-kun in charge of this.
As for the Boys' magazines...
Yes. Yamamoto-kun might be able to breathe new life into it with his insight.
It looks like he's gotten used to this job...
All right, time to appoint him
as the editor-in-chief!
Yamamoto-kun, I got a favor to ask.
As the editor-in-chief, please create a good magazine that promotes the children's dreams.
Of course, it also has to sell.
Which is not to say you must pander to the whims of the market.
Make it the outlet for your own ideas
and shape it according to your vision.
I understand. I will make every effort
to live up to your expectations!
Kanda Bookstore
Nakamoto Bookstore
Takayama Bookstore
It's my first serious work!
Adventure Boy
I'm so glad to see that it sells well.
I must meet Toda-sensei's expectations no matter the cost...
Make "Adventure Boy" the number one boys' magazine in Japan, beloved by the children!
An editorial meeting was held.
To tell you the truth, Sensei...
I'm thinking of changing the name of the magazine...
Oh? So what do you have in mind?
"Japan's Boy."
I tried to express my hope that Japan will open up to the future at the hands of young boys.
What do you think?
"Japan's Boy," huh?
Hmm, it does have a meaningful and powerful ring to it. Don't you agree?
It's a name with a much broader scope.
I think so too.
Good. Let's go with "Japan's Boy"
starting next month.
Any ideas on how to capture the readers' attention?
Yes. Here's my plan.
Shinichi spoke of his
new idea and a way to realize it -
magazine supplements: adding value
by changing the binding size.
He went on to explain that this would help to engage the children's minds.
All right. I like that.
Let's go with your plan.
Yes, sir! Thank you very much!
Okay, I got that.
What about you?
I like baseball.
I'm a huge fan of Kawakami from Giants.
You like baseball, then?
What about you?
Learning about the great minds of the world, I guess...
I just want a book that teaches me something new.
All right. Next month, we'll be launching a magazine called "Japan's Boy"
that'll contain all the suggestions
from you guys.
Make sure to read it.
Sure, sounds good!
Right, thank you very much!
The illustrations in this issue
are very well done. Way to go!
Yes, it's interesting!
Yamaoka Sohachi's
serialized historical novel
"The Three Red-Faced Swordsmen"
enjoys popularity among children.
Sohachi Yamaoka
Representative work: The epic novel "Tokugawa Ieyasu"
I'm sure everyone is looking forward to it.
Next is Nomura-sensei's house.
Shinichi had also commissioned a manuscript from the historical novelist Nomura Kodo.
Nomura Kodo
Representative work: "Zenigata Heiji's Detective Memoirs"
New publication announcement: Japan's Boys
Revised title of the "Adventure Boy"
Pen drawings collection from the six great artists
Sensei!
There! I take the rook. Checkmate!
Huh?
Hey, wait...
No, I'm not waiting. Not taking it back.
This is Yamamoto!
Oh, please come in!
Sensei, thank you for the ads campaign!
Yeah, I thought we can afford splurging a bit.
Oh, by the way, I approve the general plan for the New Year's issue.
Got it! Thank you!
Preparing the new year's issue already?
Yeah. Famous writers
are always in high demand.
We have to start preparing
and negotiating now.
Hm? I must say, Yamamoto-kun seems like a hardworking young man.
Is he still only 21?
Yes, he's our young editor-in-chief, though we only hired him half a year ago.
He's giving his all to "Japan's Boy,"
wants to make it Japan's #1 magazine for boys.
I knew something had changed.
Then, let's focus on roundtable discussions next month as well.
I'm counting on you.
We've been trying to find a way to increase the reach of our lectures on the greatness of Buddha
by organizing internal meetings within the Youth Division.
And yet, the number of participants, both the regulars and newcomers, is decreasing lately.
That's why I wish you all great inspiration!
Isn't everyone here lacking in spirit?
What we need in our fight
is a burning determination to do whatever it takes to fulfill our destiny!
I'm not seeing any of that
among you, people!
He's just yelling at us again...
Same old story every time.
I wish we could talk more calmly...
The atmosphere here is so hostile.
I need you people to get your priorities straight and decide
if you're prepared to see it through to the very end!
Sensei, we need your next manuscript soon.
Okay, got it.
We're all slacking off!
We've got work to do,
we've no time for crybabies.
That kind of whining is no excuse!
Still can't get over
their pretense of heroism...
But taking away their authority won't accomplish anything...
Ah, sensei!
Try not to dwell on it for too long.
Common Path can't be achieved in a day.
The shallow, thoughtless
and reckless gung-ho bravery
won't amount to anything.
Right... Got it!
Shinichi looked worried.
He must be having a hard time
adapting to that atmosphere.
Many serious young people
probably feel the same way about it.
But it's those young people
who are our strength.
However, even if we suddenly change our modus operandi...
Several days later
Okay, it's almost finished.
We have to make something good
for the kids to enjoy...
Ah... Sensei!
A pleasure to see you
being so energetic, Shin-Chan.
Yes. I'm assigning the work
for the next issue.
It's going to be good, isn't it?
Yes! That's what I'm here for.
Um... Sensei.
Hm? What is it?
I'd like to discuss something.
Oh, I see.
Well, let's get seated first.
So, what is it?
Allow me to speak frankly.
To tell you the truth, I just can't bring myself to get along with Soka Gakkai's executives...
Or even the Society itself.
I see. You're at odds with Soka Gakkai?
I was afraid that might happen.
Forgive me, Sensei...
Then how about this, Shinichi?
If you don't like it, why don't you try to make it a Soka Gakkai that you can like?
Huh?
A true revolutionary would fight earnestly
to build an ideal Soka Gakkai.
I don't need armchair intellectuals, who only criticize in their minds
without taking action!
Somehow, sensei knew exactly what I was feeling at that moment...
Listen, Shinichi.
What makes an organization enjoyable
is the variety of people in it.
Among them, there will be some who make you think you'll never be able to work together.
But it's the people like them
who allow us to evolve.
An organization made up entirely of similar people
will go to rack and ruin in no time.
The history knows
countless examples of that.
Sensei...
Please forgive me.
I really didn't understand anything.
All of our comrades have come together in this Latter Day of the Law,
each with their own role to play
in the fate of the Common Path.
How do we proceed to let those people's talents unfold fully?
Finally, how can we make Soka Gakkai a strong and respectable organization?
Deciding that is your role.
Don't forget it!
Got it!
Aobaso, an apartment in Omori where Shinichi Yamamoto moved to
Toda-sensei gave me a scolding.
It was my own fault.
I must reflect on my actions.
I have to believe in him
and keep working hard,
no matter for how long.
I must always reflect
on my own wrongdoings
to become a revolutionized person.
Otherwise,
you won't have anyone else to look at,
except your own pitiful life.
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
Young Yamamoto's life
shone like the morning sun.
"I'm going to build an ideal Soka Gakkai
that everyone can love and relate to."
"No matter what trials and tribulations I face, I'll do it!" - he vowed to himself.
And it wouldn't be long before Toda Josei and Yamamoto Shinichi were faced
with a mountain of tribulation by far exceeding anything they could have ever imagined.
The drama between master and disciple emerges from the neverending daily struggles.
And it wouldn't be until after they've overcome all those struggles...
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing & Typesetting
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Collectr
Muzussawa, True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 4
The End