The great human revolution, occurring in one -
before long, it'll define the fate of the nation.
Furthermore, it could one day remold
the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 10
Drive
Original work: Daisaku Ikeda
January 1954
Shinanomachi Soka Gakkai Headquarters
Soka Gakkai began its operations
in 1954 with a goal of converting 80,000 households that year.
Second President's Office
President Toda was focused on finding a way to accelerate
Soka Gakkai's progress towards
achieving the Common Path.
I'll leave that matter to you, then!
We got you!
Indeed, looking at the progress we've made over the past few years,
you could say that the Soka Gakkai ship is running at full throttle,
steadily sailing through the ocean of the Common Path.
But in which direction should we steer Soka Gakkai to ensure it doesn't go off course?
That's the #1 question.
The ship can't move forward simply by revving its engine.
To convert that into propulsion,
you also need a sturdy screw.
Engine, screw, and rudder...
Only when all three are in place
can we sail safely straight to our destination.
I've always though of myself
as the rudder of the Soka Gakkai ship,
but upon reflection,
I realize I've also been the screw.
But what happens when that vital screw
begins to wear out?
The Common Path is bound to falter then.
What should we do about that screw
that's supposed to propel the Common Path?
If we don't start thinking about it now,
we'll face a world of trouble later.
The propulsive force...
Yes. That overflowing energy is what's going to become Soka Gakkai's propulsive force.
What if we assigned a portion
of the Youth Department to each branch?
We'd risk disuniting the Youth Division
and dispersing their strength.
However, our youth can't keep growing if they have no place to apply what they've learned.
If we do that, they could end up becoming the propulsive force for that branch.
Let's give it a try.
But can we really expect the youth to become the propulsive force for all of Soka Gakkai
by simply placing one male and one female member in each branch?
I feel like I'm missing something.
But what is it...?
Soka Gakkai
Focused on promoting education, Toda
Three Great Secret Laws
delivered a variety of lectures, primarily general ones
at the Toshima Town Hall
three days a week.
This fourth-level lecture, aimed at other educators, was one such example.
The Three Great Secret Laws, formulated by Nichikan Shonin,
are the ultimate proof of the righteousness of Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism
that we believe in,
the Lotus Sutra.
Well,
that should be all for today.
Thank you very much!
Thank you.
Sensei! What's wrong?
Irie-san, I believe Dr. Hayami is here today.
Quickly call him over, but do it discreetly so as not to alarm everyone.
Okay, understood!
Sensei, Hayami-san will be here soon, please stay strong!
Hayami-san!
Something's wrong with Sensei, please check on him immediately!
Is Shin there?
What? What did you say, Sensei?
Shin is not there?
Shin...
Shin?
Yamamoto-san was busy with work today.
Shin...
Where did Shin go?
So?
Looks like a hypoglycemic attack.
No need to worry.
When I make this injection,
the seizure will subside at once.
So that's what it was...
Thank god!
But to be on the safe side,
I think it's best if he rests here tonight.
All right.
The harsh prison life
and the strain of the last ten years have taken a toll on my health.
I might not have much time left to live.
However, to lay the foundation for the future spread of the Common Path,
I must accomplish my mission of converting 750,000 households, no matter what it takes!
Second President's Office
Sensei,
forgive me for being away last night.
How are you feeling now?
Don't worry, I'm fine.
Shin-Chan, let's lie down.
You can use this as a pillow.
There's one thing
occupying my mind right now.
I haven't even gotten to the point where
I'm ready to talk to someone about it yet, but...
In the end, maybe even talking about it won't solve it.
The Sensei is acting strange tonight. Completely different from usual.
Shinichi, you young men have to study harder than anyone else, don't you?
Yes...
Now is the important time.
Got it!
How is your health these days?
The success of the Common Path depends on it.
You should be more worried
for yourself, Sensei.
My own health?
I can't die just yet.
A creature such as man cannot die...
as long as he has work to do.
In any case, I'll do everything that needs to be done.
And as long as you study with all your might,
I have no worries about the future.
It seems like Sensei is trying to tell me something, but I don't understand...
He said countless times that I must study,
but what exactly is he getting at?
That's right! I should let Shinichi
act as the screw in my stead.
For that to happen, we must first prepare a more fitting position for Shinichi.
What would that be?
Yes.
Rather than putting him in charge
of all of Soka Gakkai,
we should first let Shinichi try his hand
at being a strong screw for the Youth Division.
When the Youth move,
Soka Gakkai moves.
We need to consider the circumstances
in which such a correlation would be valid...
Caroline Islands
Enewetak Atoll
Bikini Atoll
Marshall Islands
On March 1st,
the United States conducted a hydrogen bomb test at Bikini Atoll in the Pacific Ocean.
In the process, a Japanese tuna fishing boat,
the Daigo Fukuryu Maru,
which was operating outside the danger zone,
23 Japanese fishermen caught up in Bikini hydrogen (?) bomb test
was struck by heavy nuclear fallout
and became contaminated.
All 23 crew members suffered from acute radiation syndrome,
and the entire tuna catch
had to be discarded.
One of the sailors later passed away due to complications from radiation sickness.
Do not touch!
Contaminated fish
Toda
This is terrible!
The Japanese people became victims
of three atomic bombings:
One person hospitalized with serious illness; University of Tokyo examines radioactive ash on the ship
Ambassador Iguchi was telegraphed that it was outside the "danger zone"
in Hiroshima, Nagasaki,
and now Bikini too.
This time, there will be mass outrage all over Japan.
The world's brightest minds, like Einstein,
warned us that a nuclear war would annihilate humanity.
Yet the leaders of the major powers
turn a deaf ear to that
and continue developing these dangerous weapons.
It must be because they're fixated on the flawed belief that intimidating opponents
with overwhelming destructive force
will deter war and lead to world peace.
US President Eisenhower
Soviet Union First Secretary Khrushchev
Atomic and hydrogen weapons,
which lead humanity toward destruction,
are truly the devil's handiwork.
Fighting that won't be easy,
but we gotta do whatever we can...
Toda's implacability at that moment
would later culminate in the historic "Declaration for the Abolition
September 8th, 1957
President Toda delivers the "Declaration for the Abolition of Nuclear Weapons" at Mitsuzawa Stadium in Yokohama
of Nuclear Weapons,"
which he delivered to the world from Yokohama.
Soka Gakkai
Interview Room
Sensei,
Suikokai Meeting
an appeal for a ban on hydrogen bombs has been made in Suginami Ward,
and now they've launched a nationwide signature campaign.
What should our stance on that be?
Hm... I think it's commendable that the people have realized
there is no future for mankind if we allow the nuclear weapons to go unchecked.
Yes...
Watari-kun, you know the UNESCO Constitution, don't you?
Yes!
In the preamble, it says...
That since wars begin in the minds of men, it is in the minds of men that the defences of peace must be constructed;
Period.
And I agree with that.
No truer words have ever been spoken.
But the key question is how and with what materials we should
construct a bastion of peace in our hearts.
That's something...
we never tried to shed light on
in general discourse.
The world's intellectuals and leaders have not been able to clarify it either.
But I can answer that with full certainty.
The only thing that could make this possible
is Nichiren Daishonin's great philosophy of life!
By adhering to the teachings of Daishonin, who truly expounded the sanctity of life,
and by offering his prayer to the Buddha,
one can become an angel or a demon.
We must transform humanity's fickle mind,
which is our entire life,
into a firm and unwavering one
that never ceases to desire absolute peace.
Only then can we build a bastion of peace in the hearts of all people that will never crumble!
Our nightly roundtable discussions,
doctrinal lectures,
conversion work, and personal tutoring
are humble activities, but they demand far more perseverance, study, and effort
than signature campaigns, as they comprise the life-transforming movement.
You, my friends, are the warriors,
who stand on the front lines of this movement!
I want you to keep that in mind at all times.
Okay!
Toshima Town Hall, Ikebukuro
By order of the president,
the following organizational changes
will be implemented in the youth division:
March 30th
March Headquarters Executive Meeting
Establish a new detached office.
Appoint as the new division chief:
Yamamoto Shinichi.
Okay!
A committee was established to design
and draft all operational plans
and educational policies aimed at advancing the Common Path and the religious revolution.
Yamamoto Shinichi was appointed as the department head,
with Jujo Kiyoshi as the chief of staff,
along with six other men and women.
"I appoint the following department heads:
1st Men's Division: Suzumoto Minoru..."
Additionally, a groundbreaking "one branch, one division" system was introduced,
assigning separate men's and women's divisions to all 15 branches.
Chuo University Auditorium, Ochanomizu
April 29th
Youth Division General Meeting
And then came the time for the Joint Youth General Meeting.
Under President Toda's leadership,
30 new division chiefs
from the men's and women's divisions
gathered in formation, ready to advance the progress of the Common Path.
These young people became 30 screws,
who are now going to propel their respective branches forward.
The history of the Youth Division is unfolding right before our eyes.
But I must not forget that this also
ushers in a new era for me personally.
Chief Yamamoto!
Hey, Jujo-san, let's hurry!
Members of the Executive Staff
would often hurry to the Soka Gakkai headquarters after work
and their missionary activities
to discuss various events and topics.
Second reception room
Department head,
I'd like to confirm once again
the intended role and planned activities of our movement.
What do you think?
Yes, let's do that.
As Sensei always says at Suikokai meetings,
I believe that the Common Path
is about fighting to save the unfortunate people of Japan and the world.
To achieve that, we need to develop a detailed and robust 100-year strategy
that takes into account all the various problematic contingencies we may face.
In other words, isn't it our responsibility to create a realistic and innovative plan
to address the issues,
starting with religion,
of politics, economy, ideology, culture, and education—
essentially all the various challenges that impact people's lives—
through the lens of Buddhist philosophy and under the guidance of Toda-sensei?
Only by becoming the unsung heroes can we serve as the driving force that propels
all of Soka Gakkai and Youth Division activities forward.
Understood.
By the way, just a suggestion, why don't we put together a music band in the Youth Division?
Huh? Music band?
Yes. Revolutions always come with music. Why should our religious revolution be any different?
A musical band performing at a youth event or meeting
will lift the spirits of our ranks.
I believe it will serve as a symbol of our youth's unity, and pave the way for a bright future.
I see! It's a great idea.
Isn't it, Irie-san?
Yes, I think so too.
Speaking of which, we have Arimura-kun, a composer in the Men's Youth Division,
so why not let him take charge of things?
Yes.
I agree!
I agree too!
If everyone agrees, I'm going to ask Toda-sensei
for his approval to form the band.
Please do!
Toda, who served as a counselor to Daito Trading,
Daito Trading
would come to the office every morning to consult and offer advice on business matters.
Sensei, may I have a minute of your time?
Very well. Get seated first.
What is it?
Sir, I'd like to form a music band
within the Youth Division...
Music band?
Yes, they will perform at all future youth meetings,
bringing courage and hope
to everyone in attendance, I believe.
I approve, but who's going to pay?
At present, Soka Gakkai doesn't have the financial wherewithal to buy instruments.
It's not a problem.
We'll make do with rented ones for now.
I see
Please leave it me.
Okay.
Several days later
Oh, Arimura-kun?
Thank you for coming.
Come on in now.
So, is the band prepared?
Yes. Nine members agreed to participate.
We borrowed the instruments from the Tsurumi neighborhood association.
All experienced performers?
Yes, more or less.
Still, we have little time to rehearse...
Just some Soka Gakkai songs will suffice.
Got it. I'll do what I can.
In that case, our next problem is the costumes.
Huh?
You know, the bow ties and such that musicians usually wear. What about that?
I'm afraid we don't have anyone
with a bow tie outfit...
It's the band's first public performance...
Get them all together.
I'll find the money for the costumes.
There's not much time for practice, but I hope you can pull it together
by the day of the youth's climbing of Taisekiji.
O-Okay!
Memorial Hall, Ryogoku (formerly the Kokugikan)
On May 3rd, 30,000 representatives from across the country
gathered to hold the 10th Spring Headquarters General Meeting.
May 3rd, 10th Headquarters General Meeting
When Toda took office in May 1951, Soka Gakkai had just 1,200 households,
but now, three years later,
it has expanded to 102,000 households—
nearly 100 times that number.
The desire to advance the people's religious awakening further on swept through the venue.
You might think of the Soka Gakkai spirit as a burdensome set of ideas,
but it's really just one—of returning to the times of Nichiren Daishonin.
Daishonin, driven by his deep desire to bring happiness to people,
was able to reveal the Great Buddha Dharma.
Embracing this spirit and working diligently to spread the teachings is what it truly means
to "return to the times of Daishonin."
I hope that by May 3rd of next year, we can all come together again,
having found true happiness through Buddha's grace by fully refining our faith.
That is my only wish!
Everyone!
Let's board!
Men 1
Men 2
Department head!
The second group of buses is running behind schedule.
But the train group already departed from Tokyo Station.
Got it, thank you.
Morikawa-kun, ask the bus company...
Got it! I'll call them and check on the situation.
The only thing I'm worried about
is the weather tomorrow.
The weather forecast calls for rain in eastern Shizuoka Prefecture... But I hope it holds.
Everyone is on board!
Chief, it started to rain!
What? Rain?
So my worries came true, after all?
All 5,500 members of 30 male and female youth divisions have just arrived.
Rikyoubou Temple
They're finally here?
Yes!
Are we doing it?
Yes! Just give a word.
All right, I heard you.
Let's do it!
The youth division began its solemn ascent.
On May 9th, 5,500 men and women from the Youth Division gathered in the pouring rain
to pledge their commitment
to a new beginning for the Common Path.
Let us, the Youth Division, solemnly vow to dedicate our lives to the fight
for the achievement of the Common Path, under the great leadership of Toda Josei-sensei!
Three years ago, on the day the Men's Youth Division was formed, it also rained heavily.
Back then, Director Kiyohara said,
This rain spells the challenges ahead for the Youth Division more clearly than anything else.
Three years have passed...
Today, the elite of 30 male and female divisions
gathered to announce the second beginning.
Once again, it became a ritual in the rain.
The heavens never seem to tire of reminding us how difficult the road ahead will be.
Then it is up to us to take on the many challenges
that will come our way in the future.
The unprecedented mission
of the Common Path
can only be accomplished by overcoming unprecedented difficulties!
The reason today's Youth Division meeting didn’t receive the blessing of Brahma and Sakra,
and we have to hold it in the pouring rain, is entirely due to my slander of the Law.
For that, I offer my deepest apologies.
However,
I hope that as you fight for the achievement of the Common Path
and work to build
a peaceful and happy Japan,
you will always stay true to the determination and resolve you swore on this rainy day.
Can you do that, my friends?!
Yes!
Soka Gakkai Song—Choir!
Conductor—Chief Yamamoto!
Come on! Put your hearts into it!
The band's first performance after its formation at a Soka Gakkai event
Born as a Japanese man, standing on the battlefield
Cherish your name, O man of beauty
When it is time to fall, fall gracefully,
Like the sakura petals that scatter across Japan
Don't be arrogant about your mountainous might
Our army is as flexible as the sea itself...
After this ceremony,
President Toda proposed that the Youth Division holds another Meeting at Taisekiji in October.
Yamamoto Shinichi and his young men and women
take on this new challenge with the goal of rallying 10,000 members.
"Do not preach this Sutra to people ignorant.
If you are clever, keenly aware of prajna, possess great wisdom and strong vijnana..."
In response to a request from the "Lotus Sutra Study Group,"
Toda's lecture to members of the University of Tokyo's "Lotus Sutra Study Group"
an intramural circle at the University of Tokyo,
Toda delivered monthly lectures
on the Lotus Sutra to the university students.
All the members had joined Soka Gakkai within the past two years
and participated in daily activities as part of the Youth Division.
That's good.
Now it's my turn to ask questions.
Who authored the Lotus Sutra?
Buddha!
What kind of age are we living in?
Latter Day of the Law.
What is the greatest wisdom of our time?
Um... I believe it's
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
Yes! That's it.
Now you understand, don't you?
Yeah...
Allow me to expand that thought.
Unless we make a clear distinction between Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism,
the highest wisdom of humanity, and the Buddha's Lotus Sutra,
we won't be able to apply the essence of Buddhism to the modern age.
In order to grasp this parable,
we need to return to the basics of Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism and study it closely.
Then you will be able to understand the Lotus Sutra with ease.
So that's where I need to look?
The reason Toda, despite his busy schedule, began lecturing on the Lotus Sutra
to a handful of argumentative and often critical University of Tokyo students
was his early recognition of the crucial role students play in advancing the Common Path.
He envisioned the future success that the students he introduced to the Buddha's Law
would achieve in the next few decades.
Toda's lecture to representatives from each university
In the following year of 1955, the number of listeners for his Lotus Sutra lectures grew to 30,
with applicants chosen from Waseda, Keio, Nihon, Chuo, Meiji, and other universities.
This gathering would later become the basis
for the formation of the
Soka Gakkai Student Division.
Haneda Airport
We're finally going to my homeland of Hokkaido.
Do your best while we're away, everyone.
Come back soon!
This year's annual summer regional guidance program greatly surpassed the scale
of any previous one, with 250 representatives sent to 20 major cities nationwide.
Yamamoto Shinichi accompanied Toda to Hokkaido and visited Sapporo for the first time.
Sapporo
Shinichi visited roundtable discussions in Sapporo and the surrounding areas,
encouraging people to join
and energizing the activities.
Hokkaido Convention
The regional guidance implemented across the country was an astounding success,
with the number of households converted in August hitting 12,700,
marking the first time it exceeded 10,000 households in a single month.
I've been wanting to show you my hometown for a while now.
Although it's just some fish and scenery in the middle of nowhere, at least it's scenery to die for.
I've been really looking forward to visiting Atsuta from the moment I heard about it from you.
So, does it help you grasp the vastness of the Ishikari Plain from looking at it?
Yes, it's really immense!
Shin-Chan, in a little while, we'll reach the Ishikari River.
Got it.
Sensei, it's actually incredibly wide.
Isn't it also quite deep?
Yes, because its drainage basin is huge.
For the first time,
the teacher and student travel together to visit the teacher's hometown of Atsuta Village
"I wonder what kind of nature and climate nurtured Sensei during his upbringing..."
Thinking about Toda's hometown of Atsuta,
which he would soon lay his eyes on,
Shinichi felt incredible lightness in his chest.
Human Revolution
Episode 10
The End