A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 19     Osaka Declaration
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
July 3rd, 1957.
July 3rd, 1957
Yamamoto Shinichi, who flew into Osaka
from Haneda, turned himself in
at the Osaka Prefectural Police Headquarters
near the Osaka Castle in the evening.
He was immediately investigated
for violating the Public Offices Election Law
Osaka Prefectural Police HQ
and was arrested shortly after 7 p.m.,
just as he had expected.
Coincidentally, it was exactly the same day
and time of day that Toda Josei
was released from prison
12 years earlier, in July 1945.
Later, Shinichi captured his deepest feelings
about that July 3rd in a haiku.
That day
released and imprisoned
master and disciple
Soka Gakkai Kansai Headquarters
Attorney Ozawa just informed us—
Chief Yamamoto has been arrested!
What the hell? Didn't he turn himself in as a witness?
Dammit! Not just Chairman Konishi—
now the Chief as well!
Why? What did the Chief do?
He hasn't done anything wrong in his life!
The Kansai members assumed
the matter was already resolved,
since those directly involved in the bribery
and door-to-door canvassing
had been arrested.
That's why this new development
has caused great shock and outrage.
Headline: Soka Gakkai's
Public Relations Director Arrested
East Police Station
Oya-san, is he really here?
They told us last night they moved him
to East Police Station.
It's a confirmed info.
No doubt about it.
Chief!
It'll be fine.
Don't worry.
Yamamoto, weren’t those your instructions?
"Nothing wrong with election fraud."
Hey! Why don't you fucking admit it already?!
As I have said many times,
I have not given such instructions!
You're one headstrong blabber, aintcha?
Even with all the evidence laid out, he keeps insisting he had nothing to do with the bribery.
What kind of evidence do you have for that?
Why don't you show it to me?
Well, whatever.
We can take it slow, you know.
But anyway, did you instruct the door-to-door canvassing?
At the April 21st briefing at the Kansai headquarters in Tsuruhashi, you said,
“Please go door-to-door to solicit votes—
I’ll take full responsibility.”
Wasn't that what happened?
No. What I said was,
"Election fraud would not be tolerated."
Quit playing dumb with us!
We have a witness who testified otherwise!
Then please arrange a meeting between us.
There, you'll see at once who's telling the truth.
I see. So you want to do it the hard way...
Your call! We’ll just have to keep you here
for who-knows-how-many more days
until you come clean!
Then there's no helping it.
I cannot possibly admit to what I've never said.
On July 8th, Yamamoto's custody
Osaka Detention House
was transferred from East Police Station
to Osaka Detention House.
Because they’ve locked him up here,
they won’t even allow visits or care packages...
Everyone is just as worried about the Chief as I am and can't sit still...
Can't see anything from here...
What makes this sorrow so jarring
is the fact that we lost this battle.
But we definitely can't lose this war!
We must win at all costs!
After his transfer to the detention center,
Shinichi’s interrogation
Osaka District Public Prosecutors Office building
was taken over by the Osaka District
Public Prosecutors Office.
On the very first day, two prosecutors
conducted a grueling interrogation until 11 p.m., denying him dinner.
But despite all the accusations thrown at him,
Shinichi gave no testimony—
other than to insist
he had done nothing illegal.
The prosecution failed to present any new concrete evidence
that could be considered damning,
and time passed in vain.
The prosecution was beginning
to feel the weight of responsibility
for arresting and detaining Yamamoto without being able to extract a confession.
Then, next afternoon...
Yamamoto, because you keep denying everything, we can't progress the investigation.
How about we hear what you have to say
in the annex interrogation room this time?
The district prosecutors office and annex were nearby,
but getting there required going outside and being escorted along a public road.
Out there, you immediately start drawing curious glances from passersby.
That kind of humiliating public exposure was intended
to amount to psychological torment for Shinichi.
However, Shinichi stoically endured the humiliation.
A lion remains a lion wherever he goes.
Ch-Chief...!
The Chief hasn't given in to this terrible treatment.
That means I can't lose either!
The Chief is handcuffed...
How could they?!
How can you lose heart
over something like this?
Soka Gakkai Headquarters (Shinanomachi, Tokyo)
He must be uncuffed immediately!
Listen, Ozawa-kun,
get them to let Shinichi go at once!
Tell the prosecutors—if they were bribed to take down Soka Gakkai, then let them come for me!
There’s no way I could stand by
and watch my beloved disciple
be handcuffed and thrown in jail!
I'm not gonna run away or hide!
Yamamoto-kun, why won't you quit playing games and confess?
Chief Prosecutor's Office
Everyone arrested for bribery and door-to-door canvassing
claimed they acted on your instructions.
If so, please let me meet them in person.
After that, there’ll be no doubt it isn’t true.
Didn't I suggest it many times over?
And yet you refuse to do that.
Why won’t you even try to determine the truth?
All you ever do is pressure me
to testify to a blatant lie.
I can't admit to what I've never done!
We’re not asking you to lie—
just suggesting that you'd be better off admitting what needs to be admitted sooner.
Just think about what could happen
if you keep sticking to your guns.
We’ll have to take action
against Daito Trading, where you work, and the Soka Gakkai headquarters—
and when that happens, Toda will go down with them.
What did you say?
What does Daito Trading
have to do with this incident?
It most certainly has no connection
to Soka Gakkai or Toda-sensei!
Oh no, it was Toda who appointed you
to oversee the elections in Osaka.
And Toda is the president
of Soka Gakkai himself.
This incident was organized
through Soka Gakkai.
Isn't it natural that we should investigate its president, Toda?
And for the record, we have confessions stating that Toda approved the bribery.
That's a lie!
That's definitely impossible!
Oh well, I guess we'll have
to ask Toda personally to find out.
Yeah, it's me.
First things first—
get ready to move on Daito Trading.
And tell the president of Daito Trading
to turn over all their books—utmost urgency.
Yamamoto...
With just one word from me,
it'll be done in a jiffy.
If you look down on me,
you’ll regret it—big time.
That afternoon, with two prosecutors watching them closely,
attorney Ozawa and Shinichi met
in the interrogation room
of the Osaka Detention House.
Yamamoto-kun, please listen carefully
to what I'm going to say.
The prosecutors office has something
really big on its mind this time.
If you don’t admit to the charges, they’ll raid Daito Trading and the Soka Gakkai headquarters—
and arrest President Toda.
The prosecutor said the same to me.
I see. Looks like they’re really going all out.
That brings me to this—
why won’t you agree with what the prosecutor says just this once?
That's really worrisome—
hearing it from my lawyer of all people!
Yamamoto-kun, the prosecutor
is a power to be reckoned with.
They can do just about anything if they so desire.
And if President Toda were arrested,
it would be a major blow to the organization.
The prosecutor also said that depending on your behavior, they may settle this quietly.
Yamamoto-kun, can you
compromise just this once?
I want you to satisfy the prosecutor and change your stance starting tomorrow. Please.
If I admit to that lie by pleading guilty,
what'll become of the justice we fought for?
If I don't, they'll raid the Soka Gakkai headquarters and arrest Toda-sensei...
If they raid the headquarters...
The humiliation and terror
of our members will be immeasurable.
And above all, Toda-sensei will be in a world of trouble.
Still, to let the prosecutor break me
by agreeing to a lie?
Wouldn’t that mean tarnishing my beloved Soka Gakkai with my own hands forever?
What should I do?!
All I want is for Sensei
to stay healthy and live a long life.
His health is already ailing right now.
If he gets arrested now,
Sensei's health would fail.
That would definitely shorten his lifespan.
He might even die in prison!
Why must he go through that?
Toda-sensei must absolutely not follow in Makiguchi’s footsteps and die in prison too!
At this point, Shinichi decided
to admit his guilt for now
and gamble everything on the trial
to prove his innocence in court.
On the evening of July 12th,
July 12th—Kokugikan in Kuramae
the Soka Gakkai Tokyo Convention was held at the Kokugikan in Kuramae.
The 40,000 people gathered in and around the venue
Soka Gakkai Tokyo Convention
erupted in outrage over the unlawful arrest
of Chairman Konishi and PR Head Yamamoto
by the Osaka District Public Prosecutors Office,
raising their voices in fierce protest.
We strongly condemn the prosecutors’ unlawful actions
and demand, loud and clear, the immediate release of both Konishi and Yamamoto!
Yeah!
I believe it would be wiser to devote this entire rally to the Q&A session.
Go ahead and ask, please.
We all know Chairman Konishi
and Chief Yamamoto are in prison right now...
How do you intend to use Soka Gakkai
to fight for the release of those two?
We've found ourselves up against
an extremely powerful opponent this time.
After all, it's a struggle
against a powerful enemy,
who wields enormous authority.
From the day I took office as president,
I was prepared to lay down my life.
I'm not scared of anything!
Be it the police or the prosecutors,
we'll stand fast in the fight!
How could I ever accept defeat?
That's right!
We're with you!
On the 17th, I will be going to Osaka
to give a lecture on the Scriptures.
I plan to hold another convention that day
and ignite an even greater wave of enthusiasm.
And if that still doesn't work, our next move will be to rally our comrades from across the country.
I will also put my life on the line.
Let us all stand up and fight together!
Ozawa-san, it seems there'll be a rally
at the Public Hall on July 17th.
CHIEF
PROSECUTOR
We’re close to reaching an agreement with Yamamoto on his confession,
so let’s have him released by then.
I think for Konishi, we'll even be able
to do it a day or two sooner.
That is much appreciated. Please do.
July 17th, 1957—noon
They said they'd do it at noon…
but it's getting late!
Do you think something
has happened to him?
It's only been ten minutes,
it's not really that late.
Still, it’s been scorching—
and they’ve kept him in there for 15 days!
Surely, it's been long enough.
They ought to free him now or...
Chief!
Welcome back, Chief!
Chief Yamamoto!
Thank you.
I'm sorry for making you all worry.
As you can see, I'm well!
After that, Shinichi went straight to Itami Airport
to meet Toda upon his arrival.
The two of them were to attend
July 17th, 6pm—Nakanoshima Public Hall
the Osaka Branch Convention
at Nakanoshima Public Hall in the evening.
I’m proud to declare the Soka Gakkai Osaka Branch Convention officially open!
Soka Gakkai Osaka Branch Convention
What's going on?
Heavens wrath?
Hm?
It's raining!
My dear friends, both here
and outside the venue—it's been a while!
I apologize for causing you
this much worry for such a long time.
At noon today, I was released from prison
with my spirit unbowed—
I owe it to the protection of the Lotus Sutra!
Thank you for your support!
On account of my imprisonment, Toda-sensei said, "One of the three formidable enemies—
Three formidable enemies
the overbearing false saints
made an appearance!"
Firmly believing in Nichiren Daishonin's golden maxim,
"Great evil portends the arrival of great good"
"Great evil portends
the arrival of great good,"
I am determined to strengthen my faith
and work hard alongside all of you
for the achievement of the Common Path!
Let us move forward with the conviction
that unwavering faith and true Buddhism
will ultimately prevail!
Yes!
Let’s make this a two-way conversation
and move on to the Q&A session.
Yes!
Please.
The newspapers have been publishing
nothing but fabrications
about Soka Gakkai
concerning the recent incident.
What can we do to correct them?
As you've just said, everything they publish
is hogwash that has nothing to do with the truth.
No matter what the media say,
it's not even worth consideration.
This whole business
made quite the name for us.
I guess we shouldn't be angry
at free promotion.
What do you think the journalists believe in?
If a war were to break out, they’d be
the first to cheer it on from the front row.
And once peace is restored, they suddenly become pacifists with a spotless conscience.
In the end, any discussion without integrity is like smoke.
But if you just keep quiet about what they write,
the world will automatically assume it's true.
So I'm going to say exactly what I need to say.
Once again, while they rely on hearsay and speculation,
we speak with firsthand knowledge of the truth about Soka Gakkai.
There's no doubt that our position is stronger.
A war of words takes many forms beyond print.
After all, what’s more powerful than a face-to-face conversation?
How can justice be defeated by a bunch of lies?
Justice will prevail—but its victory should never be taken for granted.
If we stop fighting,
justice will be trampled.
As long as Soka Gakkai is just, it cannot lose.
Buddhism is a battle
that we absolutely need to win!
That's why we keep fighting!
This concludes the Q&A session.
You don’t need to worry
about what comes next—
as long as you keep chanting
and stay strong in spirit, happiness will follow.
That is my primary desire!
Chief!
Welcome back!
All right, let's sing!
Born as a Japanese man,
standing on the battlefield
Cherish your name, you, the warrior
My comrades in Kansai who grieved,
grew angry, and prayed for me—thank you all.
When it's time to fall, fall honorably
I will fight with my life for the friendships I've made in Kansai for as long as I live!
Like the sakura petals scattering back home
Even the most compassionate man,
At the end of July,
Yamamoto Shinichi was indicted
when he takes up the righteous sword,
by the Osaka District Public Prosecutors' Office
will not hesitate to fight a million men
as the alleged organizer
of the door-to-door canvassing campaign.
Those who believe will always win
But after four and a half years
of intense legal battles,
No enemy can stand against the Emperor
at the final and 84th hearing in January 1962
he was acquitted of all charges.
January of 1962
Defendant Yamamoto Shinichi—found innocent!
Cleared of all charges at the 84th and final hearing
Thus, Shinichi’s innocence was upheld,
truth triumphed over deception and intrigue,
and the justness of Soka Gakkai
was made clear to the world.
It was also a victory
in the struggle for human rights—
affirming dignity, freedom, and equality,
and exonerating those falsely accused and oppressed by state power.
Soka Gakkai Headquarters
Today, East and West—most notably the United States and the Soviet Union—
are locked in a race to develop
ever more powerful nuclear weapons,
testing atomic and hydrogen bombs
without restraint.
If we leave things as they are,
the annihilation of Earth and humanity
Soviet Union successfully tests
intercontinental ballistic missiles
by atomic and hydrogen bombs
will become inevitable.
As Buddhists, our mission
is to enforce the abolition
of atomic and hydrogen bombs at all costs.
What's matters is not capitalism or communism—
let's not let ourselves be swayed by their ideology.
The White House
Kremlin
We must reach a shared understanding that atomic and hydrogen bombs
are an “absolute evil” threatening humanity’s very right to survive.
Furthermore, we must reaffirm that those who use atomic and hydrogen bombs—
the demonic creations of human hands—
are themselves no better than devils.
Dr. Linus Pauling's appeal for abolition of nuclear testing
In the name of everything humane,
we must never come to terms with it.
Never!
It is our duty to instill this conviction
in the hearts of people around the world.
I've been feeling rather unwell lately.
Something has changed from before...
My energy feels just as strong as ever,
but I can’t shake the sense that some kind of blockage is building deep within me.
Perhaps this is because life itself senses
that it has little time left to live.
In that case, I must perfect everything
I’m meant to do in this life.
This declaration I will make tomorrow at the Youth Festival to abolish all nuclear weapons
will stand as my ultimate message
to future generations and my foremost legacy.
September 8th—Youth Festival
at Mitsuzawa Stadium
On September 8th, under clear skies after the typhoon,
the Youth Division East Japan Athletic Meet and the Youth Festival
was held at the Yokohama Mitsuzawa Stadium.
Good luck!
This midsummer sun was shining just as brightly
on August 6, 1945, when the world's first atomic bomb was dropped on Hiroshima...
We must break free once and for all
from this demonic claw
that robs us of our very right to survive!
I would like to announce to you all
my first lasting message for future generations.
I will make my position unmistakably clear
on the nuclear and hydrogen bomb tests
that are shaking society today.
A movement calling for a ban
on the testing of nuclear weapons
has arisen around the world.
But I want to expose and rip out
the devil's claws that lie hidden
in the very depths of such weapons.
Because we, the citizens of the world,
have an inviolable right to live.
Anyone who jeopardizes that right
is a devil incarnate, a Satan, a monster.
Even if one country, no matter which one,
wins with an atomic bomb,
I maintain that anyone who ventures
to use these weapons,
should be sentenced to death without exception.
To death?
I see—Sensei seeks to condemn to death
the very evil lurking within life
that drives a wedge into the human heart
and makes justifying the use of nuclear weapons possible!
Even if a country should conquer the world
through the use of nuclear weapons,
the conquerors must be viewed as devils, as evil incarnate.
I believe that it is the mission of every member
of the youth division in Japan
to disseminate this idea throughout the globe.
This historic "Declaration for the Abolition of Nuclear Weapons,"
which sparked the global
Soka Gakkai peace movement,
would become Toda’s foremost message
to the Youth Division.
We must ensure without fail
that Sensei’s instruction is fulfilled.
I will make it my lifelong mission to spread Sensei's teachings throughout the world!
October
RECEPTION ROOM #1
This is Yamamoto.
Oh, Shinichi? Come in.
Sensei has been lying
on the sofa a lot these days ...
Teacher, how are you feeling?
I'm fine.
Just a little tired, that's all.
As long as he still has a lot to do,
a man can't die that easily.
Shinichi, sit down.
I have sacrificed my own life
to the noble cause of the Common Path.
Living for a noble and supreme goal can instill anyone with great strength and determination.
When I became the president,
I vowed to convert 750,000 households.
As long as I live,
I will devote myself to personally spreading the Lotus Sutra to 750,000 households!
It looks like we’re finally about to make it, even though no one took me seriously at the start.
Still, it didn't play out
the way I envisioned it.
Because I wanted to do it on my own.
If you have to rely on others,
you can't fight a real battle.
When you rely on others,
you seek strength in numbers—
that means you've already been defeated in your heart.
I've dedicated my life to paving a broad road
into the future for the Common Path.
But it falls to you guys to give
your grand performance on that stage.
Shinichi,
it falls to you!
Don't let me down, Shinichi.
Yes!
Once the battle for the Common Path begins,
we must win it at all costs.
Nothing brings greater shame to a person
than losing a battle he started!
Shinichi,
do you understand?
Yes!
November 8th—17th Autumn General Meeting (Korakuen Stadium)
A word from president: Toda Josei-sensei!
What I’d like to ask is this:
“What do you believe is the driving force
behind Soka Gakkai’s growth?”
To me, it's clear:
Soka Gakkai has faith.
It has the Lotus Sutra.
This merit of piety is where it all originates!
If you look at things honestly,
it'll become immediately obvious.
But for some reason, scholars, critics,
and journalists refuse to realize this.
Soka Gakkai is formed around faith.
Faith is our lifeblood.
Our purpose is neither to engage in politics
nor to interfere in the economy—
we were not established for such ends.
National Diet
We support our comrades entering politics
to better society
and implement policies
that truly serve the people—
that is the genuine expression of our intent.
The ultimate intention of Soka Gakkai
is to bring happiness to the people of Japan
and the world through the power of faith.
As long as you hold fast to this conviction,
no amount of blatant and outrageous criticism
in the media will be able to discompose you.
If just seeing your faith mentioned in a magazine
leaves you shaken and stammering,
then this faith isn't for you!
This concludes my address.
H-Huh?
There's nothing worth printing here!
Sensei's footing is unsteady.
So he really is unwell...
Toda was already ailing by then.
But in his heart, the flame of determination to push through every obstacle
and take another step forward
still burned brightly.
That same fire also raged in Shinichi's heart.
No matter what happens, I’ll always be there
to lend Toda-sensei my shoulder
and move forward on the Common Path
towards eternity alongside my mentor.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing & Script Kiddie
QC & TS
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr
True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 19
The End