A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day remold
the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 7    Rushing Forward
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
Kamata, Ota Ward, Tokyo
Maybe it's time to put Shin on the front line?
Konishi
January of 1952
The year is 1952. January.
Soka Gakkai members enthusiastically got to work early in the new year
At the Kamata branch, Yamamoto Shinichi, the newly appointed branch secretary,
was about to take charge
of leading the effort
to spread Buddhism to 750,000 households, standing at the forefront of the Common Path.
In his latest announcement, Toda-sensei introduced
Branch - District - Group - Team
a new structure, establishing districts, groups, and teams under the branches.
He also set a clear quota of converting one household per month for each team.
Huh?!
No need to worry.
Toda-sensei says Soka Gakkai already holds enough influence to allow for that.
The key is for us branch executives
to stay confident that we can make it happen.
Yes...
Plus, there's this "detailed strategy." With these two documents, I'm sure we can pull it off.
Yamamoto-kun's strategy this time is actually brilliant.
Let us all proceed with this battle plan.
Okay!
I believe that work in teams will be the key from now on.
First, how do we teach the team leader
to fight this specific battle,
and then, how do we train him?
I think we've reached a point where we need to begin making slow, yet steady steps forward.
Shinichi crafted a detailed strategy
for his branch and boldly set it into motion.
He then personally rushed around everywhere, completely transforming
the atmosphere within the branch.
Soka Gakkai Headquarters
...eventually, they assigned me to a baseball team in Osaka as both an assistant manager
and pitcher,
so I've decided to move there.
Hm, I see. Osaka, then?
Aren't you glad?
Haruki-kun.
Yes?
Haruki Seiichiro, a professional baseball player and star pitcher for a Tokyo-based team,
was also a devout believer and one of the leaders of the Kamata branch.
Soka Gakkai is now poised to launch
a nationwide campaign to promote the Common Path.
Haruki-kun's transfer to Osaka presents a golden opportunity to support our efforts.
So, when are you moving to Osaka?
It's scheduled for the end of the month...
All right. I'll appoint you as the Osaka branch manager starting January 15th.
Huh?
Osaka Station
Head over there and pioneer everything from the ground up.
This was the first stone in creating the history of Osakan Common Path and "Invincible Kansai."
The Youth Division's First Research and Presentation Conference.
February 17: Youth Division's 1st Research & Presentation Conference
Representatives of both sexes discussed the great philosophy of the Buddha Dharma
in relation to life and society.
At that time, Yamamoto Shinichi had been assigned to a crucial role in the Youth Division,
overseeing the design and implementation of plans for all religious activities in February.
Everyone is studying hard in their areas,
and it's great to see.
I look forward to seeing everyone present their reports here next time.
Okay!
The next thing I would like to say is...
Our third president is going to emerge
from the Youth Division.
But only one of your will be fit
to become the president.
By that time, there must be
no disunity between us.
Just like the current Makiguchi disciples are supporting me,
I expect my disciples in the Youth Division
to support the third president.
I sacrificed my life to the cause
of the Common Path.
So, even if my body ends up washed up on the shores of Shinagawa or elsewhere,
as long as we support the third president,
I’m confident that the Common Path
is within our grasp.
Toda's words that day can genuinely be considered his testament.
At that moment, Toda's heart
was clearly filled with various thoughts
aimed at the third president,
to whom he was entrusting his legacy.
In Kamata, Branch Secretary Yamamoto
remained committed to fostering dialogue and offering heartfelt encouragement.
February 29th
February Leaders Meeting
Let me announce this month's
converting results.
Tsurumi branch - 98 households.
Kamata branch - 201 households.
What? 200?!
Is that true?
How is this even possible?!
As expected, everyone was so shocked it felt like their hearts nearly jumped out of their chests.
At the time, each branch's output was capped at about 100 households,
so converting over 200 in a month seemed utterly unimaginable.
All right, my branch will work hard and set a new record at the March meeting!
The determined fighting of the Kamata Branch that brought the dream to life
gave activists in each branch the confidence that "if you work hard enough, anything is possible."
The origins of Soka Gakkai's traditional "February Campaign"
can be traced back to Yamamoto Shinichi's tireless efforts during this period.
Then in March, Soka Gakkai as a whole finally surpassed the long-sought 1,000 mark.
March Leaders Meeting: conversion goal met!
Kamata, Tsurumi, Adachi, and Mukojima branches receive commendations
They successfully spread Buddha's teachings to 1,073 households.
Missionary efforts
were steadily picking up pace,
with all Soka Gakkai members contributing toward Toda Josei's goal of converting
750,000 households in his lifetime.
Meiwa Printing Co., Ltd. Proofreading Office
I know we're all tired,
but we can't ease up just yet.
Just a little more.
With your help, we'll put together a timeless collection of teachings.
Do your best!
Okay.
Start printing!
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
April 24th, Soka Gakkai Headquarters
The complete collection of Nichiren Daishonin's writings,
compiled for the commemorative project
celebrating the 700th anniversary of the sect's founding, was finally complete.
It is now being presented to newcomers to introduce them to Soka Gakkai's core
Common Path, embodying the great aspiration of the compassionate Buddha.
You all did well, sacrificing food and sleep to tackle
the challenging task of printing the complete collection of scriptures.
Please accept my heartfelt gratitude.
Please don't mention it!
It's us who should be the most grateful.
One way or another, I'm glad we did it.
Now, for the first time in 700 years, a complete and correct collection
of Nichiren Daishonin's writings has been published.
Can you imagine how delighted Daishonin would have been?
Just thinking about it makes me feel elated.
Izumida-kun.
Sir.
Thus, Soka Gakkai celebrated the 700th anniversary of the sect's founding
Seki-kun.
Sir!
by publishing the Complete Collection of Nichiren Daishonin's Writings and achieving
Yamadaira-kun.
Sir!
unprecedented dissemination of Buddha Dharma through their efforts toward the Common Path.
May 1st: The first May Day after gaining independence
Coincidentally, the peace treaty
signed in September of the previous year
Maintain the peaceful constitution!
-Central Labor Relations Committee​
also took effect on April 28,
the 700th anniversary of the sect's founding.
Seven years after the war's conclusion,
Japan finally regained her independence.
Immediately after that,
on May 1st, a terrible incident occurred.
The Bloody May Day incident left 2 dead, 1,300 seriously injured, and over 1,200 arrested.
From its very first steps,
independent Japan
was swept up in turmoil and bloodshed.
This incident inadvertently left the question of “what true independence means” unanswered.
It should also be remembered that the Bloody May Day incident led to the creation
of the Subversive Activities Prevention Act.
Hmm...
All the newspapers
claim the protesters turned into a mob and attacked the police... But is that really true?
Subversive Activities Prevention Act
Legislation for the Subversive Activities Prevention Act is currently being heard.
Public opinion is largely against it,
but if it passes, it will be a major game changer.
I can't take my eyes off politics for now.
I have to monitor it closely...
Right, let's make a call.
Yes, Daito Trading.
I knew you'd still be at work, Shin-chan!
Ah... Toda-sensei!
Don’t you have a wedding ceremony tomorrow?
You should head home and start getting ready.
Yes... We're falling behind schedule with laying the groundwork in Joto Ward.
Once I'm done making arrangements, I'll go home.
I see. Go home as soon as you can then, okay?
Yes. I will.
Phew... That was unexpected.
Although I did know sensei is always watching over me.
May 3rd
On a sunny May 3rd,
Yamamoto Shinichi and Haruki Mineko
held their wedding ceremony.
The groom, Shinichi, was 24 years old,
while the bride, Mineko, the second daughter of Haruki Yoji from the Kamata branch,
was a smart and kind-hearted woman
who had just turned 20.
One year ago, on May 3rd, Toda entered the office of the second president.
It was Toda who selected this day
for Shinichi's wedding,
an anniversary that all of Soka Gakkai should celebrate.
It stemmed from Toda's heartfelt desire to do everything he could
to congratulate Shinichi
on his new beginning.
Right... They really do look like a good couple. I'm so happy for them.
I guess all the hard work paid off.
Right, it was back then...
Right after visiting the Haruki family and getting Mineko's parents' consent,
Toda headed to the Yamamoto family...
Yamamoto
Yamamoto-san, would you give Shinichi-kun to me?
You want Shinichi?
That's right.
I ask you to give Shinichi to me.
Mom! Toda-sensei is an amazing person!
He knows everything
and answer any questions I ask!
Is that so?
Is he really that amazing?
He's strict, yet kind. Also strong-willed and esteemed by everyone around!
I've never seen anyone like him!
I've been following Toda-sensei around all the time.
I’m sure I’ll learn a lot from him!
You can have him.
So you agree?
I take full responsibility for Shinichi-kun
from now on and forever.
I won't let you down.
We're counting on you...
By the way, engagement talks are underway for Shinichi-kun.
His party is a wonderful young lady
named Haruki Mineko.
Hmm...
From what I can see, she should be a very good match for him. What do you say?
Oh no, didn't I just say
we're handing Shinichi over to you?
We trust you to do what's best for him.
Oh no, I’m flattered!
Everyone, I'm very happy today.
Not only is Shinichi getting married, but his bride is also a beautiful and dependable woman.
My happiness for him knows no bounds.
I thought of Shinichi as of my child.
But from today onwards
I entrust him to Mineko-san.
Can you do it?
Yes.
My only wish is for both of you to unite and work together
for the Common Path
throughout your long lives.
And I'll always be there
to watch over you two.
I want you both
to proceed with that resolve.
Sensei, thank you for everything.
I will take your words to heart and strive to build a strong family
that can contribute to the Common Path.
Yes. That was my hope.
By the way, Mineko-san,
I have two requests for you.
For the first thing, I'll ask you
to keep a household account book.
A wife who can't manage a household account book can’t build a successful family.
For the second point, even when things aren't going your way,
you should see your husband off and greet him back with a smile every morning and evening.
These are the only two precepts I want you to uphold.
Okay.
A man who finds a good wife and doesn’t have to worry about anything else
can fully dedicate himself to his work.
It all depends on whether or not
you can fulfill my two requests.
Do you understand, Mineko-san?
Yes. I understand very well.
Then I entrust Shinichi to you
with no second thoughts!
Thank you!
In August, the first-ever local conversion campaign was launched on a full scale.
The spread of Buddhism
reached a national scale.
For this task, Toda dispatched a dedicated preaching group to Nagoya, Osaka, and Kyushu,
Nagoya lodging house "Hashimoto Manor"
personally leading the efforts at the forefront.
Traveling across the country,
he delivered his lectures to the masses
with full conviction,
Soka Gakkai
Grand Lecture on the Lotus Sutra
Osaka Otemae Hall
sharing the greatness of Buddhism
and the beauty of faith.
Yame, Fukuoka Prefecture, Kyushu
Yame Public Hall
The Buddha's merit is immense.
No prayer to Buddha goes unanswered.
If you don't find happiness within a year of conversion,
I'll be willing to listen to anything you have to say.
The day that happens,
I'll give up everything—even my life!
There is such wonderful strength and conviction
in the way Toda-sensei speaks!
After two weeks of local conversion work,
the branches in Nagoya, Osaka, and Kyushu
saw their membership double.
This allowed all three of them to rapidly develop as important bases for the Common Path.
Shinichi and Mineko's apartment "Shuzanso"
My lifelong mission
is also your mission.
Do you understand, Shinichi?
That's what sensei requested of me...
But he never gave me any clear instructions on how to advance the Common Path.
At this rate, I won’t be able to realize the grand vision of the Common Path that Sensei laid out.
But I can't accept that.
What should I do now...
I know! I should ask him to train the Youth Division!
This way, we'll all be able
to learn directly from Sensei.
While Shinichi was weighing his options, Toda also...
The Soka Gakkai’s membership continues to grow daily.
The day will surely come when our numbers reach the millions.
To facilitate our progress towards that goal, we need to assign the right people to each section...
Now is the time to start cultivating our youth to become great leaders.
For that...
Yes, that's right.
That special training I once conducted.
We’ll do that and entrust the youth with carrying out the Common Path.
Sensei,
would it be possible to conduct that special training you once provided
to the youth division again?
What?
Sir, I believe we need to strengthen the Youth Division now
if we expect them to lead Soka Gakkai into the future.
I see. Shinichi reached the same conclusion as I did...
Is that everyone's wish?
No, it was my own idea.
I see. In that case, please discuss it with Seki-kun and Yamagiwa-kun
and form a Men's Youth Group
for that purpose.
I'll leave the planning and organization up to you. That should be all.
Thank you!
Several days later
Excuse us!
The Men's Division finally arrived?
Huh?
Never mind that. I’ve decided to provide special training for the Women’s Division as well.
Kayokai
I decided to name it "Kayokai."
Is that so?
So, what should we do about the Men's Department?
Sir, we would like to select the most outstanding members from each branch
Water Margin Volume 1
(New Translation) Suikoden
Sato Haruo
and use Sato Haruo’s "New Translation of Suikoden" as our teaching material.
Hm, Suikoden?
I like that.
And as for the group's name...
Yes, that's right.
How about "Suikokai" to convey that the gathering at Mount Liang is Soka Gakkai?
Mount Liang
=
A place where revolutionaries and heroes gather
Suikokai?
Suikokai
It means "a get-together of brave men concerned about the chaos in this world."
That's a great name!
Do you think so?
Yes!
Then it's settled.
Thus, the special training for the Youth Division began,
with the inauguration ceremony for the Suikokai set for December.
From the start, I won’t be giving any leeway to the Men’s Division. Be prepared for that.
Okay!
October 21st: "Kayokai" inauguration ceremony
Toda christened the women's training group
"Kayokai" with the meaning of
"beautiful like a flower
and proud like the sun."
Their first meeting preceded that of the men's division.
The meeting unfolded informally,
and with the goal of providing the Women’s Division with some social education,
Toda began by instructing them on the Western dining etiquette.
He also answered their questions
and discussed the current state
of the Women’s Division’s mission and faith.
The most important thing for the Women's Division right now is teaching.
We should all take our teaching and learning seriously.
It's the only way for you to keep growing.
Is that clear?
Yes!
Well, let's call it a day now.
For our next meeting, let’s read some world-renowned classics
or historical novels and use them as teaching materials. Does anyone have suggestions?
Yes!
"A Tale of Two Cities!"
"The Little Prince!"
"A Doll's House."
"Little Women."
"Botchan."
Good. We'll look at what everyone wants to read, in that order.
How about we start with Dickens'
A Tale of Two Cities?
A Tale of Two Cities
Please read it for our next Kayokai gathering, everyone.
Anyone who comes without having read it
will be disqualified from Kayokai. Deal?
Yes!
Hey!
Thanks.
Good evening.
December 16th: "Suikokai" inauguration ceremony
Oh... Hey!
Good evening!
Is everyone here?
Yes. All 38 people are present.
No need to look so stiff when it's just us.
Come closer, surround me.
Okay.
Excuse me.
I would like to pass on the guiding principles of the Common Path to all of you now.
I’m sure that later, when you look back, you’ll see what a significant gathering this is.
Sensei really does give it his all.
I can't miss even a single word!
Enough with the preamble,
let's get started on "Suikoden."
Let's ask someone to read the preface first.
Okay!
"Suikoden is an epic saga based on the exploits of Song Jiang, who lived
during the Northern Song Dynasty.
Song Jiang was a real person known as a notorious thief who ran rampant in Shandong
during the final years of the Northern Song Dynasty.
His name appears in various places in the Song Dynasty History..."
Drawing from the Suikoden, Toda's lecture
covered everything from commentary on the story
to reading techniques, character analysis, historical insights, and leadership theory.
Without a doubt, Suikoden tells the story of a great thief.
Thirty-six main characters, including the chieftain Song Jiang, appear in the story.
Since they all valued righteousness over personal gain, society shunned and ostracized them,
forcing them to gather at Mount Liang.
The government at the time was in complete disarray,
with officials involved in all kinds of corruption and crimes.
In short, it’s much like Japan today,
and the public is none too pleased about it.
For that reason, Song Jiang and his merry men turned to large-scale theft,
targeting corrupt officials and villainous local noble families.
But they never exploited or mistreated
the people of those domains.
In other words, what they did was extraordinary and truly noble.
There's something heart-warming about it.
Which is probably why it's been very popular with the Chinese people since ancient times.
So how should we read this novel?
Each of us might have a different take on it,
but presently, I’d like to view it as an exciting novel about revolutionary struggle.
Huh?
This novel has a rich and varied storyline.
Anyone can read it for fun.
However, if you're only captivated by its exciting storyline
and read it carelessly, you'll miss the deeper revolutionary spirit woven into this novel.
Why did I decide to hold this Suikokai meeting today?
It should go without saying
that I did it because I wanted to ensure the accomplishment
of the noble and significant mission of Soka Gakkai.
Common Path
is nothing short of an unprecedented religious revolution.
Religion is the undermost foundation that supports all aspects of human society.
Therefore, religious revolutions
are never limited to politics or economics.
It is unattainable without educational and cultural revolutions to go along with it.
Is that so...?
What I want to say to you now is that, while piety is fundamental,
you must not become so fixated on it
that you blind yourselves to the wider world.
We don’t need to become so-called zealots;
in fact, we must steer clear of that.
I want you to develop into capable members of society
who actively and positively contribute without being hindered by anything,
awakened to the profound philosophy of life known as the Mystic Law.
This is the path to the salvation of the people in the Latter Day of the Law.
Or in other words,
the Common Path.
Who is going to lead us on this great path?
That would be you, gentlemen!
The leaders are not somewhere else.
They're right here, right now!
I now receive the Buddha’s decree,
Which is his vow to save all through the Lotus Path
I stand proudly alone with my head held high—
Friends are hard to come by,
foes are numerous
Toda Josei and Yamamoto Shinichi solemnly pledged to build a peaceful society in the future.
From 1952 to 1953,
an unprecedented new era
of forging the Common Path
was ushered in
through the deep bond of joint struggle
between teacher and disciple.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
Typesetting, QC
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr
Muzussawa, True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 7
The End