A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 15          Leap
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
March of 1956—Soka Gakkai Kansai Headquarters
The year is 1956. March.
Today as well, Yamamoto Shinichi
presses forward from Kansai Headquarters,
commanding the Battle for Osaka.
"Incense and candles are all you need!"
That slogan, coined last month,
is now chanted all across Kansai!
I see.
Once Toda’s words sparked a wildfire
in the hearts of our Kansai comrades,
it became unstoppable.
Exactly!
How are things going in Sakai, Asada-san?
We're observing an enormous religious surge!
First, roundtable attendance exploded—and now people are also bringing their friends along.
Good.
We’ve shifted to conversion,
but the roundtables are picking up too—
everyone’s saying,
“You guys are so jolly, it’s irresistible!”
I see. We played our cards right
and pulled off a smooth opening.
But the real battle starts now.
We can’t afford to let our guard down!
Got it!
Keep up the pace and continue intensive personal and family guidance throughout March.
The fruit of our religious guidance efforts
will be revealed at the Osaka-Sakai Joint General Meeting
at Osaka Baseball Stadium on April 8th.
This is the first time that a baseball stadium will be used for the Kansai general meeting.
I want this general meeting to ignite an explosion that gives us the edge in the Battle for Kansai.
Yes.
Yeah!
But that would require
a great deal of preparation.
Let's all put our minds to work
to make it a great success!
I have to leave for Yame in Kyushu tomorrow,
but please take care of everything in my absence, Branch Chief Haruki.
Yes! Consider it done.
Despite his packed schedule, Shinichi—
now overseeing all of western Japan
from Osaka westward—
carved out time to offer guidance in Kyushu
to secure a sweeping victory in the July battle.
Yame City, Fukuoka Prefecture
Wherever he went, Shinichi went out of his way
to uplift every single member he met,
March 6th—Kyoya Inn
sparking a natural wave
of proselytizing among them.
Back in Osaka, Shinichi was once again
thrust into the thick of routinely fierce battles.
During this period, Shinichi’s early morning scripture lectures became the driving force
that gave a powerful boost to Kansai’s productivity.
Shinichi delivered his fiery lectures
in the third-floor hall of the Kansai Headquarters
right after the 8 a.m. service.
The guidance and content of Shinichi’s lectures
reached the hearts
of other members that very same day,
stirring everyone in the Kansai Branch
to give their all in the fight,
moved by Shinichi’s unwavering commitment to making the impossible possible.
When should I put into practice
what Sensei instructed me to do the other day?
It might just become the key to this battle.
That's what Sensei said...
Shinanomachi—Soka Gakkai Headquarters
Shinichi,
you really managed to get Kansai fired up.
Thank you.
Kansai is a city of merchants,
so once you indicate the few critical points,
you can just step back
and marvel at their inventiveness.
From now on, the key question will be:
"How to make the best use of it?"
Yes. I was pondering that too.
In Kansai, we dedicated January through March
to offering individual guidance,
and now the entire organization
is alive with devotion.
Moreover, your bimonthly advanced lectures
and scripture lectures
instilled our values in people,
giving rise to new Soka Gakkai champions
who breathe fresh life into our activities.
I felt that work in squads
was no longer optimal for us.
So starting in April, we shifted to working in bigger groups,
entrusting immediate on-site decisions to each group leader.
Yes, fine by me.
If we build up the group leaders’ confidence,
it’ll only add fuel to the fire.
Yes, I believe the realization that "We can save people too" will send out powerful ripples.
Yes, that’s absolutely right. Shinichi,
don’t let anyone stand in the way of your vision.
Do me this favor.
All right, I’ll announce the launch of group-based fighting at the group leader meeting on April 1st.
Using the general meeting on the 8th as a springboard,
we’ll unleash a tsunami
of propagation in April and May!
The results of March proselytizing
have been published.
March Conversion Results
Osaka Branch - 5,500 households
Sakai Branch - 759 households
-
The Osaka branch achieved
an unprecedented success of 5,500 households,
ranking first nationwide.
The Sakai branch also did reasonably well,
converting 759 households,
and coming in 9th out of 16 branches.
The spirit of Kansai, poised to reach the heavens,
was finally beginning to show.
Group leaders and their detail
from across the Kansai region
April 1st—Kansai Group Leaders Training Session
came together for an electrifying training session.
With everyone's approval, we're finally switching to group-based work starting today.
Use your wisdom and creativity to host more and more of enjoyable roundtable discussions.
Let us make the next Joint Branch Meeting a great success with our own hands!
Are you with me?
Yes!
Soka Gakkai
Kansai Joint Branch Meeting Venue Floor Plan
I don't like it that there's just one entrance.
If that many people gather there at once,
it could turn into a mess.
We need to make sure
the joint meeting goes off without a hitch.
Hello!
Oya-kun, hello!
Hey boss, the weather is wonderful outside
and sakura is in full bloom.
Why don't we go for a little walk?
Let's see...
It's 2 o'clock.
Oya-kun, how long does it take to get to Nara?
About an hour by express train, I think?
I see...
Okay, let's go!
Mount Wakakusa, Nara
A refreshing atmosphere and bracing breeze...
It's just the oasis of serenity that I needed.
That hits the spot!
I want to be like that cloud—
a man who drifts through life with ease,
no matter what comes his way.
But even that craft can only
be acquired through fighting.
All right.
Let's double back, Oya-kun.
Huh? Already, sir?
I thought we just came!
I already feel fully recharged—now it’s time we spread that sense of lightness to everyone else.
Right...
Let's go now!
April 8th, 1958.
April 8th—Osaka Baseball Stadium
In Osaka, the rain began last night
and hasn’t let up since.
Even sprinkling sand
on the walkways won't do now!
It's so muddy you can't walk on it!
Are you saying we just say,
"Nah, too wet," to the path Sensei chose?
In that case, why don’t we lay down
some tents on the walkways?
Better that than the mud.
Good thinking! All right, let's split and find some tents to borrow!
We're really stripped for time, though.
Do you understand the task?
Understood!
Okay, let's go!
Namba Station—Nankai Electric Railway
Those who are headed
to Osaka Stadium, this way!
It's raining, so please watch your step!
What's up with these guys?
Hey mister, is there anything to see at Osaka Stadium?
Soka Gakkai general meeting!
In this rain?
Yes!
Whew...
Soka Gakkai
Kansai HQ
Yamamoto-kun, it's raining really hard.
Why don't we cancel it?
I considered that too. But our Kansai comrades are full of enthusiasm.
That's true.
If we cancel it now, it'll be a big stink.
What do you mean?
Early this morning,
the group and squad leaders
came to me, eyes blazing—
“Branch chief, we’re doing this, right?”
If we cancel now, we’ll kill the great momentum we’ve built up so far.
Please proceed with the meeting!
I'd also like to ask you to forge ahead.
Our comrades from remote areas such as Shikoku and Okayama already hit the road.
And they can't turn back!
That's what troubles me.
If we order a cancellation now,
chaos will break out.
In any case, let's take a look at the site first.
Soka Gakkai
Kansai HQ
Sensei,
it's pouring rain.
I'm sorry...
Maybe it’s the heavens telling us
that the battle ahead won't be easy.
Yes...
Do you have a plan?
Yes. I’ll head to the site right away to assess the situation and decide whether or not we cancel it.
Please wait until then.
All right.
Please proceed slowly in two lines!
No one seems the least bit bothered by the rain.
It's like there's no downpour at all.
Operation HQ
Good morning!
Ah, Boss!
To you too, Asada-kun. You got the latest estimates on the amount of participants on site?
Yes, we've just broke through the 3,500 mark.
I see. The entryway is in order?
No, we opened the gates a bit earlier—at 9.
Good call. If you hadn’t opened it early,
the walkways would’ve gotten jammed.
Yes!
Mitsui-san, any updates on other prefectures?
Yes.
Charter buses from Kyoto and Wakayama
are already on their way here.
Buses from Okayama, Kurashiki, Kanazawa and Fukui left in the evening.
The ship from Kochi has already docked in Osaka,
so people should be arriving any minute now.
Okay. Got it.
Chief, we're rolling with it, aren't we?
No, we don't know for sure yet...
Everyone is already on their way here.
Of course we should do it!
I’d like to, but I’d rather wait and see
how things play out before deciding.
First, I’ll walk around the venue
and encourage our staff.
Keep up the good work!
Towels for the people?
Yes. We’ll hand them out to everyone arriving,
so they can at least have a dry seat.
I see, so it's for wiping the seats?
Thank you.
Did you borrow these somewhere?
Yes. A member living in the neighborhood lent it to us.
Give them my thanks too later!
Okay!
Even the bleachers are starting to fill up.
Our Kansai comrades
are unfazed by wind and rain.
They’re probably full of confidence,
knowing they successfully fought their way here.
Nothing can stop the momentum we built during the establishment phase any longer.
If we win even under these worst-case conditions, an unshakable conviction in Soka Gakkai
will take root in the hearts of our Kansai members.
All right, let's go ahead.
We're doing it!
And so, by the order
of Kansai Commander-in-Chief Yamamoto Shinichi,
the Joint Osaka–Sakai Branch Meeting began at 1 p.m. amid pouring rain.
Our president, Toda-sensei, often says,
“We must return, in spirit,
to the time of Nichiren Daishonin—
that was the last era in Japan when
the true Buddhist spirit of individual enlightenment was alive.”
With the conviction that our work for the Common Path today
is grounded in the faith that connects us to Nichiren Daishonin’s time,
why don’t we use today’s general meeting as a springboard for the next step
in our fight to save the people?
The rain let up!
It really did!
I am a disciple of Nichiren Daishonin.
And I believe that a disciple of Daishonin
must have in him the unwavering resolve
that the Common Path can be achieved.
You may then ask:
"When will the Common Path be achieved?"
And the answer is now!
It's the present!
When we advance Buddhism through every part of society,
allowing people to see things clearly and correctly through it;
when our contribution to the happiness and peace of all becomes evident to the naked eye,
that’s when we know
the Common Path has been achieved!
Operation HQ
We’ve got the final tally of attendees!
Here!
Oya-kun! Over 20,000 visitors are attending!
Huh? For real?!
Yeah! Isn't it amazing?
We really did it!
Everyone thought it was next to impossible,
but thanks to Chief Yamamoto’s guidance,
we really tore through those numbers!
What great insight he has!
You can't get better than that!
Anyway, if we can match our gear
with the chief, we'll win!
Soka Gakkai exists to spread the Common Path.
You all understand keenly this fundamental truth.
For your own sake and for society,
move forward with full confidence in all you do.
This concludes my today's address.
Inspired by the success of the joint general meeting, Kansai erupted with energy.
A wave of confidence
and joy swept through Kansai,
with group meetings and roundtable discussions
springing up day and night,
reigniting the flame of propagation
all over the place.
What's going on?!
Ever since that general meeting, Chief’s been setting up roundtable discussions nonstop—
I haven’t had a minute to rest!
And it's been like that for days on end!
What do you say? Won't it be your loss if you miss your chance for happiness?
Incense and candles are all you need.
What do you say, my good sir?
I suppose we could try...
What about you, my friend?
Yes, we'll do it.
Congratulations!
Let's do our best together!
Yes, thanks a bunch.
But I still can't quite believe it—
all my friends who tagged along wished to join!
That’s the power of everyone
in the organization—Chief included—
sincerely wishing for our comrades' happiness.
Now all they need is to receive their altar decorations and remember to pray.
Sure!
Early morning scripture lectures,
the rainy general meeting,
and the push for group-level activities
gave the Kansai Branch new momentum,
driving a major leap forward
in the ongoing fight for propagation.
But in the midst of it all, the evil that breaks the unity of comrades was secretly creeping in,
and no one was there to notice it approaching.
Mitsui-san,
let's give the squad chief another scolding.
Tell him his numbers are insufficient.
Sir... I’ve already encouraged
him and told him to give it his all more than once.
I don’t think I should push him any more.
Mitsui-san, once you take the lead in battle,
you’ve got to launch a full-on attack.
If we miss this chance,
we won't be able to do any fighting.
Yeah, but still...
This guy thinks he knows best
just 'cause they sent him from Tokyo...
But only an Osakan truly knows
what’s best for him!
What do you say, friends?
He'd never realize it if we keep silent!
Tsuchida-san, what do you think?
Don't you agree?
I think... Group Leader is still learning the ropes,
so we shouldn't flog him too much.
What did you say?!
Tomii-san,
we Osakans don't like being pressured.
The overall numbers are coming along,
so let's not push our luck.
Just as the perfect chance presented itself...
Can't believe those Osakans
willingly chose to be clueless!
I try to teach them to fight,
but they won't even listen!
The clash between them seems to come from differences in how they carry out their activities.
At this point, it’s best to let each one share his view and work things out through discussion.
We don't need any tension in our ranks.
Being proactive and being complacent
aren't the same thing!
Don't you understand the dangers
of letting one run wild wherever they want
if you don't hold the reins tightly?!
That's what reporting in advance is for.
But don’t you get that sometimes
we need to hold a roundtable on short notice for newcomers?
So what of it?
How's that not obvious? We need to make
the reporting system more lenient!
Anyone would get fed up
if you're watching his every move!
Friends! This isn’t a productive discussion—
it’s just an emotional back-and-forth!
Tomii-kun, who do you think the enemy is?
Are our local leaders friends or foes?
Friends, sir...
Then why should we have
to fight and quarrel with our friends?
Sharing opinions is healthy,
but clashing emotions is just a petty squabble!
If anything, it undermines
the fighting power of your allies!
Tomii-kun, that was really unsightly of you.
Poison of Pride
When did you embrace this poison of pride?
You see the slightest sign of progress
and already let it go to your head?
You've let the demon of vanity
and lust for recognition take over.
You’ve let the worst in you show itself.
Do you understand my chagrin for pledging my full trust to you?
I'm sorry.
I'm really guilty before you!
I was foolish.
Please accept my apology!
I will never let this transpire again!
Chief is right—it wasn’t an exchange of opinions, just me losing my cool.
Tomii-san got carried away giving orders,
so I snapped, "Don’t you know how tough it is for those of us on the ground?!"
To me, that seemed like he was being arrogant...
It's me who needs to be reprimanded!
You just saw me giving quite a scolding to our comrade I brought from Tokyo.
Do you know why I did that?
There are demons standing in our way to victory,
and they’re who I’m fighting!
You guys get so proud of yourselves
just because we had a decent start to our plan.
It’s unbelievable!
Demon of Pride
No one noticed that you let
the Demon of Pride pull you around!
It made you get emotional over small things,
forgetting our enemy
and turning on each other with criticism and ripostes!
How did you allow this to happen?
Aren't we all here the only friends we have?
Where else do we have any friends?
All the criticism and slander aimed at tearing apart our unity is the demons' scheme!
I see... So it was the demons' doing?
I gotta be more careful.
Without the unity of dispatched and local leaders, we have no chance of winning this battle!
What matters is how we achieve this unity.
The scripture on the unity of minds says,
"When your minds are united,
you can achieve anything,
but if you’re divided,
nothing will come to fruition."
Daishonin told us, "The key to victory in battle lies in whether or not we are united in spirit."
Nothing is more important
for us right now than that unity of spirit!
Only defeat awaits those who enter that battle
with a divided spirit!
Whether we win or lose,
it all comes down to our shared goal.
We need to realize that even the slightest friction between dispatched and local leaders
can completely shatter our unity!
This issue can't be overlooked!
So? Tomii-kun, Mitsui-san,
do you understand?
Yes! It's clear to me now.
I'm the only one
who should be apologizing here.
I’m counting on you two to lead the 1st District
to glorious victory from here on out.
Don't let the petty conflicts tear you apart again.
We won't! Thank you!
Soka
Gakkai
Forgive me for repeating myself,
but we won’t win this battle unless we make
deepening our faith our top priority.
Some of you might feel the results are lacking
and progress is hard to see.
But no power in the world is more fearsome
than steady progress grounded in faith.
How can we be sure of that?
Well, that's where your fight
as the leaders comes into play.
Sawada-kun, I get that the Tokyo Branch is focusing on roundtable discussions—
but isn't it at the expense of propagation?
Y-Yes... But everyone
is fighting with all they've got.
Why can't you produce good results, then?
Maybe it's because there's no unity of faith?
Y-Yes...
Tokyo is the city of boatmen.
That's why you must be
an epitome of piety yourself.
Only then the unity will be born.
Y-Yes!
The Tokyo developments are worrying...
But I don't think I can offer any support to them right now.
If we don’t give our all to the Battle for Kansai,
Sensei’s vision will stay just a pipe dream.
I can only pray for Tokyo's
great struggle and great victory.
April 25th—Ichigaya Office
Chief!
Daito
Trading
We’re just about to hit this month’s sales target.
What worries me is this final step.
Can we really make it?
Yes, I'm sure of it!
Good luck, then.
Yes, Yamamoto here.
Oh, it's you, Sei-chan?
Wait, what? 9,002 households for Osaka Branch,
1,111 households for Sakai Branch?
You did it, Sei-chan!
Please give my heartfelt congratulations to the Asada Branch Chief.
I'll be in touch soon.
So Osaka made that last push
and racked up 9,002 households?
Yes.
That's an unprecedented number
if I ever seen one!
So it seems.
Kamata Branch reported in yesterday
with 3,401 households.
Which makes them #2 this month.
Lately, the Osaka Branch
has held tight to that #1 spot.
Yeah, we can’t just sit back
and take it easy now, Sei-chan.
Finding a way to sustain that joy
will be the key to winning in May.
Yeah, so after talking it over with everyone,
we decided to hold
a branch execs' meeting on the 29th.
Branch execs' meeting?
For that...
I'll need to make three round trips
between Tokyo and Osaka in one week.
Yes, got it.
Let's go with 27th.
Night train out, night train back...
But I can’t let the fire of motivation
burn out in Kansai.
It's not the time to worry about my health.
On April 29th,
the Osaka Branch Execs' Meeting was held
April 29th—Osaka Execs's Meeting (Community Hall)
at the Community Hall
in Kita Ward of Osaka City.
Our district set a goal
of 800 household converted in May.
Everyone in our district
will work as one to achieve that goal!
We’re set on making it the top in our branch!
Everyone, please watch
our district's selfless fighting in May.
Our goal is 500 household conversions,
but easing even one more person’s suffering
would mean just as much to us all!
Their drive is incredible.
I want to keep this irresistible momentum rolling
not just through May, but all the way to July.
Life is like a theater drama.
When we live by the mission
of spreading the Common Path,
striving for both others' and our own happiness,
we’re also playing out the drama of life.
I’m sure you all know the famous Napoleon,
who played the role of a great hero
in 18th-century Europe.
When he invaded Russia, he commanded, "Advance!" and marched straight for Moscow.
Then, when he escaped from the Isle of Elba,
he commanded, "Advance!"
and marched on Paris.
Napoleon wasn't familiar with the Lotus Sutra.
I’m convinced that we, who’ve embraced
that highest philosophy of life,
and taken up the cause of the Common Path,
a global peace movement,
are a hundred million times greater than Napoleon.
So, friends, let’s make
"Advance and advance again!" our motto
and win in May with flying colors!
Let's do it!
We'll totally win!
In early May, the Abeno District
led all 34 districts of the Osaka Branch
and held a convention
at Nakanoshima Public Hall,
May 2nd—Abeno District Convention at Nakanoshima Hall
rallying 3,000 branch members and friends.
This turnout is truly impressive.
To think that a single district
could fill this large public hall...
This will boost the spirits
of the following districts.
The lion's awake at last!
Yeah, that's right!
Exactly!
Now that the lion is awake,
I truly hope everyone,
with the district chief at the helm,
unites to win every battle ahead
and rise as the most devoted district in Osaka.
The great success of the Abeno district rally
set fire to all the other districts in Osaka.
The battle for propagation
is sure to take a great leap forward now.
But we can't be all happy about it.
We've experienced explosive growth
over this March and April.
Sure enough, that gave
the demons plenty to feed on—
they’ll be showing up before long.
The scriptures teach that when your faith deepens, the three obstacles
The three obstacles and four demons
will appear, each scrambling
to throw you off course.
and four demons will inevitably appear,
each scrambling to throw you off course.
With the battle reaching this stage,
the three obstacles and four demons
will soon come knocking.
I know they will!
And I need to sound the alarm now so that
no one is caught by surprise when they do.
I will include that in my talk
at tomorrow's HQ meeting.
The further Soka Gakkai advances the Common Path,
the more likely power-hungry
demons are to surface to take advantage of them.
Back then, only Yamamoto Shinichi had an inkling that his prediction
would come true all too precisely in May.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr, Muzussawa,
True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 1
The End