A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 1           Dawn
The Fall of the Mariana Islands
Death before Surrender on Iwo Jima
There is nothing more inhumane than war.
The Fall of Okinawa
There is nothing more tragic than war.
However, that war is not over yet.
Great Tokyo Air Raid
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
Toyotama Prison, July 3, 1945
Dear...
Dear!
Oh, Ikue?
You came to pick me up?
Is the house safe?
Yes. Everyone is in good health.
I see. I'm glad, so glad.
I've caused you so much trouble,
but worry no more.
So, shall we go now?
This yukata-clad man
would later come to be known as Toda Josei,
the great commander and guide of the people.
However, at that time,
Toda's name was barely known to anyone.
He was only known to the authorities
as a criminal offender, charged with violating
the Peace Preservation Law and lèse-majesté
for refusing to worship a Shinto amulet
and for staying faithful to Buddha.
So it was this bad?
And what about Morimoto's place?
Burned down in an air raid,
so they moved to the country.
Then what about Kondo?
Their house as well.
Such a destructive endeavor.
Yet they're looking to prolong it?
Has this war made anyone happier?
Peace and happiness are supposed to be
the shared aspirations of humanity.
But instead, once every ten years or so, we find ourselves
plunged into a war
where the nation's survival is at stake.
Whatever it takes, we must steer Japan
away from this path.
If anything, the Americans got some fine iron
in their firebomb shells!
Yeah. That iron is top-notch!
I even made a shovel with it once,
and it worked wonders!
If you need a kitchen knife,
you can make five or six from a single shell!
Why be so stingy?
You can get away with ten!
The people remain resilient,
no matter the times they're facing.
Harajuku! Harajuku!
I see. The Meiji Shrine.
What foolish thinking.
Without revering the true Buddha's ways,
they expect a divine protection from every deity.
Ignorance about religion
was the faulty notion
that propelled Japan into this reckless war in the preceding years.
And because of that, President Makiguchi...
Imprisoned on the same ideological offense charges as Toda, President Makiguchi
Tsunesaburo Makiguchi
Founder of Soka Gakkai
was subjected to harsh interrogations and malnutrition.
And on November 18, 1944,
he passed away in his prison cell.
He was 73 years old.
Makiguchi-sensei, you can trust me to make every effort.
This is the only part of town
that survived the fires somehow.
I'm glad it did.
I still have a home to go back to.
Dear, please watch your step.
Dear!
Toda
O Great Buddha,
I have finally returned.
He's so emaciated.
Nam Myoho Renge Kyo...
But at least, he managed
to return home safely.
O Great Buddha, thank you so much.
Dear, the air-raid alert is on.
Well, well.
Just when I get home, there's an air raid?
Dear, let's go to the shelter.
No, I'm staying here.
It's out of the question!
What if a bomb lands right here?
Come on, dear, hurry now!
I'll stay here to protect the Great Buddha.
Huh?
Ikue, make haste and leave.
The darker the night gets,
the closer the dawn must be.
O Great Buddha, Daishonin-sama,
I will disseminate the laws of righteousness
and bring the salvation to the people,
to ensure that the Common Path is achieved.
If we want to pursue the Common Path,
Soka Kyoiku Gakkai has to be rebuilt.
"The first step toward that would be
the creation of an economic base."
With that thought, Toda immediately directed
his efforts toward rebuilding his business.
And that is the financial statement
of the business you've entrusted us with.
Is this bottom number
written in black? Or is it...
It's in red.
Having learned that the business
he used to run
had collapsed entirely during his two-year imprisonment,
Toda decided to start his correspondence course business anew,
and preparations were set in motion.
That brings me to...
Would it be possible for us to receive a small loan
with this fire insurance
certificate as collateral?
Sure. Fine by me.
Thank you.
I am truly grateful!
Toda set up a print shop
and procured paper for it
with money raised from his old friend.
At last, his business was
almost ready to be reopened.
August 6, Hiroshima
August 9, Nagasaki
After pondering deeply
the general trends of the world
and the actual conditions obtaining to our empire today,
August 15, 1945: End of the War
we have decided to effect a settlement of the present situation
Japan unconditionally surrenders
to the Allied Forces, ending World War II
by resorting to an extraordinary measure...
"In their present existence,
the clergy of Japan, as well as the laity revering them, are transforming this country.
In addition to agonies unknown in previous ages,
we will be swarmed by a foreign power.
This is due solely
to the workings of deities like Brahma, Shakra, and the gods of the Sun and Moon."
Nichiren Daishonin's prophecy
has come true all too precisely.
By oppressing those
who believe in true Buddhism
and imposing a faulty national Shintoism upon the people,
they brought about the ruin of our country.
But who could've seen this coming?
More than ever,
the time has come for Nichiren Daishonin's
great Dharma to start shining.
Except at this moment, the Common Path
won't have a chance to take off ever again.
By any means, we must not
let this chance slip!
The Allied Occupation Forces
were promptly deployed to Japan.
General MacArthur
Supreme Commander of the Allied Forces
All political, economic, educational, and other internal functions of a defeated Japan
Hibiya GHQ
(General Headquarters of the Allied Powers)
were placed under strict supervision of GHQ.
Kamiosaki, Shinagawa Ward, Tokyo
Nihon Shogakkan Publishing Office
NIHON SHOGAKKAN
Watch your back!
Ah! It's here, here!
NIHON SHOGAKKAN
Now, this is when things finally get busy.
Okumura-kun!
Is everything ready?
Yes!
All right! There it is!
Yes. You've reached Nihon Shogakkan.
You'd like to place an order?
A mere five days after the end of the war,
Toda's correspondence course business started.
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
They're here!
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
English / Mathematics / Physics
Nihon Shogakkan
Nihon Shoggakan
So many!
It's only natural! We put an ad
in a nationwide newspaper.
Good. Let's divvy those up
and process them.
Okay!
Besides the correspondence courses
in mathematics and physics,
aimed at young men and women,
they anticipated an "English boom"
and were among the first to publish
a well-received academic course for English.
The business took off steadily.
Kanda Ward (now Chiyoda Ward)
Nishi-Kanda
And then, in October, Toda moved
into the citadel of the publishing world,
Kanda Ward. There, inside
a three-story building in Nishi-Kanda,
NIHON SHOGAKKAN
the office of the Nihon Shogakkan
publishing company officially opened.
Tell you what, Sensei.
That's one fine lot you've found.
One can only ascribe it to a divine grace.
Oh? Yam today as well?
Well, I'd like to say so too,
but I can't really call yam a divine grace.
Ah? Thank you.
However, we cannot doubt that this building
was a gift from Buddha himself.
For my devotion to the Lotus Sutra,
I was thrown into prison for two years.
I spent the time fighting in deadly agony,
hence this divine reward.
I don't know how this building will serve us in the future,
but I'm sure only good things
will come from it.
Let's all take good care of it.
Okay!
Okay.
Right, thank you for stopping by.
Well, please do your best now.
Yes, I won't let you down.
Thank you very much.
The office of Nihon Shogakkan
in Nishi-Kanda
became the main operational base for Soka Gakkai.
When they learned that
Chairman Toda was alive,
many pre-war members gradually began flocking there.
NIHON SHOGAKKAN
Toda-sensei!
Sensei!
If it isn't Yamadaira-kun!
Yamadaira Chuhei... has just returned!
How wonderful that you've returned alive!
I'm glad! Really glad!
It must've been awfully hard for you!
Yamadaira Chuhei went to war as a mobilized student but managed to return safely.
Thus, one after another, men sent
to the battlefield came trickling back to Toda.
I see. He's five already?
So? Did you like it?
Yeah.
No need to be shy about it.
We still have plenty more.
Feel free to take some home.
Okay.
Now, day after day,
all I think about is death!
I should probably take this child with me.
What's this nonsense you're saying?
How will your death help things?
"Human life is far more precious and important
than all the treasures in the universe."
That's what Daishonin taught us.
It would be inexcusable
to take that life for granted.
After this war, countless people, including Society members,
dwelt in the depths of despair after losing their husbands or families to fires during the air raids.
However...
Listen. Your suffering might seem never-ending now,
but as long as you carry on with your faith,
you'll have brighter days ahead.
You shouldn't think you're alone in this.
This kid's future life and happiness
also hinges on your faith.
What do you say?
Can you persevere a bit longer?
Ah... Yes! I'll do it.
I'm counting on you.
If you find yourself in dire straits again,
come see me anytime.
Okay! Thank you ever so much!
Cheer up, will you?
Nakano Station
Today must be the day I take the first step
towards inheriting my late mentor's mantle.
First step.
The year when the war ended,
November 18th.
November 18, 1945
Memorial service for the first anniversary
of Makiguchi Tsunesaburo's death
A memorial service was held for Makiguchi Tsunesaburo, the founder of Soka Kyoiku Gakkai,
on the first anniversary of his death.
Sensei, I still remember
that day in June of 1943.
Summoned by the Religious Affairs Council,
we hurriedly followed Makiguchi-sensei uphill to the Taisekiji Temple.
At that time, the sect feared oppression from the military.
To placate the authorities,
the prayer book text was altered.
We erased some important verses from the scriptures,
thus committing an act of blasphemy against Daishonin's teachings.
And on top of that, something even darker...
Head Temple Taisekiji
So I hope you understand
why the military is so nervous about this.
If you keep slandering our divine amulets,
you might just end up pouring oil on the fire.
Therefore, Makiguchi-san, how about you and your Society revere our amulets, for now?
We will never revere your amulets!
It's not the ruin of a single sect that I lament.
It's the utter destruction of an entire nation.
I grieve for the sorrow inflicted on Daishonin,
the founder of our sect.
More than ever, the time has come
to try and rectify the leaders' ways.
What in the world are we afraid of, then?
Toda-kun, what are your thoughts?
Sensei, I will fight for this cause like my life depends on it.
Come what may, I'll be by your side in everything you do.
After that, the authorities began oppressing us in earnest.
Sensei was arrested in Shimoda, Izu on the same day, July 6.
I was arrested as well,
at my home in Shirokanedai,
on charges of violating the Peace Preservation Law and lèse-majesté.
That was the last time I saw Sensei.
September, 1943
Metropolitan Police Dept, Internal Detention Center
Come out. You're to be interrogated.
Is that you, Makiguchi-sensei?
It is you, isn't it?
Makiguchi-sensei!
Toda-kun?
Move it! Who said you could stop?!
Ah, Makiguchi-sensei!
Asshole!
Start walking!
Sensei!
Please! Don't be harsh on him!
January, 1945
Sugamo, Tokyo Detention Center, Interrogation Room
Toda-san, it's time
you come clean about your guilt.
Even if you tell me to "come clean,"
I haven't done anything wrong, so I can't "come clean."
Second verse same as the first, huh?
All your other buddies
have pleaded guilty already,
sworn to convert, and been released long ago.
You're the last one left.
That's not true.
Makiguchi-sensei also persists.
Makiguchi is dead.
What?!
S-Sensei...
Sensei!
Makiguchi-sensei!
A great many yielded to the pressure
and disavowed our cause.
But President Makiguchi never retreated.
He was martyred for his unbending fight against the militaristic authorities.
He sacrificed even his precious life
to spread the Lotus Sutra Path.
Sensei only passed through
the prison gates after he died.
While I, his unworthy disciple,
made it out alive.
Thus, I must do one important thing next,
and it is self-evident.
I'm going to say it loud and clear now!
Even if the entire world renounces the Common Path,
I, Toda Josei, will keep professing it,
no matter what!
My sincere devotion to our cause
wasn't shared by a single person there.
Will I really be able use
the Common Path to save the people?
A lion roars alone.
That's right. I have to become a lion.
The Common Path best befits a lion!
Even when I stand alone, I must inspire unquestioning confidence in people!
I now receive the Buddha’s decree
His vow to save all through the Lotus Path
I proudly stand alone
with my head held high
Friends are hard to come by,
foes are numerous
At the start of 1946,
Toda truncated the Society's previous name
of Soka Kyoiku Gakkai to just Soka Gakkai.
Soka Gakkai Headquarters
The new signboard was put up at the Nihon Shogakkan office.
Sensei, it's a great thing!
I feel like my body and mind have been
refreshed and tightened up from this!
Yes. It's finally getting a fresh start.
The Society's goals do not need
to be limited to education alone.
Politics, economy, culture, and so on...
In the various fields constituting life,
we must become an omnipresent force
that invigorates the people.
From this base, we need to start sending
countless promising men out into the world,
armed with the great ideal of the Lotus Sutra.
Otherwise, we can't hope to save this country.
And those capable, promising men...
Right. The young. It can only be the young.
Mishima-kun.
So? Are you finding that Editor-in-Chief's desk comfortable?
Yes. Thank you for your continued support.
I'm counting on you for our next project.
Okay!
Is this book performing well?
Yes. It gained enormous traction. We're barely managing to keep up with the demand.
So I thought. These days, all and sundry,
young men in particular,
are jumping ecstatically into the feast
of democracy they've never tasted before.
But let me tell you,
this is not what true democracy looks like.
Philosophy & History
Nihon Shogakkan
Huh?
Democracy in the true sense of the word
cannot be achieved just by replacing the ruling party and reforming societal structures.
It must first establish itself in people's minds.
That's the starting point,
the foundation of democracy.
So? Do you follow?
Establish itself in the minds of individuals
by means of the Human Revolution!
Kiyohara-san.
Yes?
Listen. This is your own Human Revolution.
I have mine.
And Yamadaira-kun has his! All must undergo their individual Human Revolution.
That's where democracy is born,
and that's what it boils down to.
It's never just about institutions and policies.
It's about people!
It's about lighting the way for people!
It's these people,
suffering greatly from defeat in this war,
who need someone to light the way for them!
The young are earnestly pursuing the Buddha Dharma.
I must do my utmost to teach these young people
the greatness of the Buddha Dharma.
Maybe now is my best chance.
All right. Let's go for it!
Yamadaira-kun, Kiyohara-san, I'm doing it!
A course of lectures on the Lotus Sutra.
Toda-sensei is finally starting
to lecture on the Lotus Sutra.
I've never been this happy!
I should probably also tell Izumida-san
and gather as many people as I can!
Huh? Toda-sensei is giving lectures? That's just amazing!
Hayashiso
Let's split the work and send express mail
to everyone whose addresses we know!
But many evacuated because their homes
burned down during the war.
Will they receive it?
No point worrying about that right now!
For the time being,
let's just do whatever we can!
Agreed! Let's do that!
Kiyohara Katsu, an elementary school teacher,
led the Society's female division.
Izumida Tame was the wife of a soldier
deployed in the South, who was still considered missing in action.
Both used to be Makiguchi's disciples
and managed to maintain a pure faith.
Oh? Isn't that Kiyohara-san?
My, Konishi-san!
Huh? Chairman Toda?
Yes. His company is located in Nishi-Kanda,
and the new headquarters are there too.
He's rebuilding the Society brick by brick.
I had no idea!
Boy, did I miss him!
Ah! And next Monday, Sensei will
be giving a lecture on the Lotus Sutra!
Are you coming?
Yes! I would absolutely love to join!
Seki-kun, who is an elementary school teacher just like us,
also works in Kamata, so I'll bring him along!
Really? Wow, I'm so glad.
Soka Gakkai made a new start
toward the Common Path.
At his new headquarters,
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
in the same building as Nihon Shogakkan, Toda began lecturing on the Lotus Sutra.
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
Nichiren.................
Daishonin's........
Scriptures
In short, my lecture on the Lotus Sutra boils down to this:
What exactly is Daishonin's
"Nam Myoho Renge Kyo" about?
That's really all you need to know.
We start with the basics. First, what does "Nam"
stand for in "Nam Myoho Renge Kyo?"
Sadly, it has nothing to do with ham.
"Nam" is a word from Sanskrit
and translates to "devotion to Buddha."
Devote: literally, "dedicate by a vow."
Are you following?
Yes!
Therefore, when we say "Nam,"
it means we believe in Buddha
and offer our bodies and souls together to him.
As for "Myoho Renge Kyo," it refers to the 28 chapters of Gautama Buddha's Lotus Sutra.
In the present Latter Day of the Law,
Daishonin's Buddhism
was mainly defined
by Nam Myoho Renge Kyo.
The line we must draw clearly and firmly here is this.
If we don't uphold Daishonin's Buddhism,
the living creatures of the Latter Day of the Law cannot be saved.
In the next lecture...
Next would be Seki-kun's part.
Read it for us, will you?
Okay.
"Siddhartha became Buddha.
And by extension, various Buddhas
of ten directions and three times.
Particularly, his true form..."
Their drive to seek the truth becomes stronger and stronger.
Furthermore, in the next lecture...
With every session, the number of listeners increased.
The air was thick in Nihon Shogakkan hall,
heated by both the passion of the lecturer
and by the intent listeners,
trying not to miss a word.
Then, Sensei, if we are also tasked with the noble mission of saving the people,
does that make us
the Bodhisattvas of the Earth?
Of course it does. No doubt about it.
What do you all think? Can you feel that you are the Bodhisattvas of the Earth?
No, not really.
Yes. It's a bit hard to tell on your own.
But as Daishonin-sama once put it,
"If it wasn't for the Bodhisattvas of the Earth,
this chant would have disappeared."
By saying so, he decreed it sternly:
In the Latter Day of the Law,
only those who chant "Nam Myoho Renge Kyo"
get to become Bodhisattvas of the Earth.
That's something to be proud of!
We, my friends, are the Bodhisattvas of the Earth.
Wearing some rags, with a constantly growling stomach...
Konishi-kun,
Seki-kun,
Kiyohara-san as well.
I have not the slightest doubt
that you are the Bodhisattvas of the Earth.
That's something I want each of you
to realize clearly today.
Can you do that, friends?
Yes!
Chairman! Thank you so much.
Don't mention it.
Actually, I'd like to organize a roundtable discussion.
So I was wondering
if I could get you to join us.
Oh? A roundtable discussion?
Good, I like it! When?
This coming Sunday night.
Konishi's house in Kamata
Oh? I see this place was spared the ravages of war.
Yes. The Great Buddha was kind enough to protect it.
My, it's truly been a long time.
Has everyone been okay?
Yes! We're all fine!
We're ready for action again!
I see, I see. Good to know.
Thus, the first roundtable meeting after
the restart of the Society was held in Kamata.
The roundtable activities that had been a tradition since the times
of the first president, Makiguchi, were revived.
Young men from the local community gathered at a house
in Morigasaki, near the venue that Toda was attending.
They were the members
of the Reading Circle.
As the established system
of values collapsed
due to defeat in the war, people searched earnestly for a way to live now.
They actively sought
to absorb new knowledge.
Iwanami Bunko
Representative Men of Japan
Among them was a young man at the front,
listening quietly to his friends.
Iwanami Bunko
Representative Men of Japan
The young man seemed to be deep in contemplation, searching intently for something.
We've had quite the productive reading session today.
I feel that I have something in common with the life of Uchimura Kanzo,
who became a Christian.
Oh? You've started reading it already?
Miki Kiyoshi's Notes on the Theory of Life.
It looks awfully difficult.
Yeah. I'm having a hard time reading this.
I'm a bit of a slow reader,
so I can only manage about one book a month.
They call you Bookworm Yamamoto-kun,
so you probably read like five or six, right?
No, I wouldn't say...
The youngest of the group,
this teenager's name was Yamamoto Shinichi.
By day, he toiled for a tiny printing company,
and by night, he attended Oriental
Commerce School in Kanda-Misakicho.
How's your health?
I seem to get a bit of a fever
in the evenings, but I'll be fine.
Don't push yourself.
Yeah.
Yamamoto already had a chest ailment.
He became ill while working
at a munitions factory in Kamata.
Presently, he takes medications from the hospital to stave off the progression of the disease.
The doctors' diagnosis was that
he probably wouldn't even live to 26.
Yamamoto and his friends often strolled along Morigasaki Beach,
talking literature and arguing philosophy.
They held endless discussions on issues like, "What is a patriot in this day and age?
What are the criteria for good and bad?"
Finally, "What is the true and righteous life?"
They couldn't find
a spiritual foothold anywhere.
In the end, I've decided to try Christianity.
Would you join me?
No. Honestly, I don't feel
drawn to Christianity.
I will still try to pursue my own path
in my own unique way.
With my friend by the shore, Morigasaki
Pungent seaside smell, waves withdrawing
Nineteen-year-old boys,
struggling to choose a path
Philosophy talk as the hours go by
Always troubled being poor, my friend utters:
"I will follow the way of Christ"
Eyes flashing keen in the moonlight
To that firm heartbeat, the waves roll in...
Thus, Yamamoto Shinichi continued his deep contemplation.
But before long, he would find himself overwhelmed, when the time came
for his fateful encounter with Toda Josei.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing & Typesetting
Editing
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Collectr
Paul Geromini
Muzussawa, True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 1
The End