A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 1
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
The year is 1956. January 4th.
January 4th, 1956
Early into the new year, Yamamoto Shinichi is traveling to Osaka on the Tsubame express train.
Toda-sensei said, "What Kansai needs right now
is to be reminded of the basics of faith.
If we don't stick closely to its sobering principle,
we risk turning into a mindless mob."
I'll start with a thorough lecture
on Buddhism for all branch members.
During January and February,
all Kansai executives
will be proactively providing
individual religious guidance.
We'll use that to strengthen the members' faith
and help them find joy in believing.
Then they'll channel that joy
into their conversion efforts.
That way, we can revitalize the organization
and make this energy self-sustainable.
This trip to Osaka will decide everything.
As one Western philosopher once said,
"First, be bold; second, be bold; third, be bold."
It's not the time to be afraid!
Soka Gakkai Kansai Headquarters
So this is our Kansai headquarters? It's huge!
It might even be bigger
than our Tokyo headquarters.
Our Kansai comrades must be happy to have such a splendid base of operations built for them.
Reception
Good evening!
We've been expecting you!
Sei-chan!
Impressive stronghold you got here.
Yeah! It's our treasure!
Now you'll have all the support in the world.
Yes.
But to be honest, I was worried sick
about what would happen to me here.
That's true.
October 14th last year at Shinichi Yamamoto's house
Yamamoto
Good evening...
Hey, it's Sei-chan!
Come on in.
I'm telling you, it's a big deal for me!
They told me to run
for the House of Councillors next year.
But I don't have the confidence
to take on such a big role.
Really, I'm at a loss...
I was also just recently
put in charge of the Kansai region.
It's the first time for both of us.
I know it won't be easy, but you're fighting
to realize Sensei's vision, isn't that good enough?
It's more than enough, but it doesn't help
the fact that I have no idea what to do.
He—the unstoppable pitcher—became so timid when the time has come to win some election!
I'd rather be on the mound right now...
But alas, I suppose campaigning
is a far cry from pitching.
You can't make your dreams come true
if you're timid, Sei-chan.
We'll go in with full determination, we'll do our best, and leave the rest in Buddha's hands.
Welcome, Seichiro-san!
Sorry for barging in.
Are you parents doing all well?
Yes. My mother and father spend their days
buzzing around like busy bees.
Since it seems like we can't win either way,
let's not lose sleep over it and just do
what we have to, as best we can.
Sei-chan, our battle is finally here.
Hang on tight now!
Right. The district executives
are waiting for you, Department Head.
Okay.
Good evening.
Good evening!
I'm counting on your cooperation, friends!
Okay!
At that time the World-Honored One
calmly arose from his samadhi...
Studying the Lotus Sutra
is also the military science.
Offering a prayer to the Lotus Sutra is a fundamental tactics for winning every battle.
Nam Myoho Renge Kyo...
This service feels so fresh
with the Department Head around!
I'll be coming to every service from now on!
This service really cleanses the mind!
Yes. Everyone is breathing in sync.
We can definitely do it!
I'll take charge of this upcoming battle
on behalf of President Toda!
Fight with confidence—
your back is covered.
January 5th—Kansai District Directors' Meeting
Right now, our greatest hope and goal
is to win the upcoming July battle.
But let me be blunt with you, top executives:
with our current influence in Kansai,
victory is out of reach.
Our Osaka converts make up less than a third
of the households converted in Tokyo.
Anyone can tell you that, with these odds,
victory is all but impossible.
You're probably thinking the same yourselves.
But let's not forget that our branch
received a special Lotus Sutra scroll.
The Wish for Prosperity Dharma
has the power to make possible what conventional wisdom would consider impossible.
Therefore, this battle will begin
with each and every Kansai member
demonstrating strong, prayerful devotion.
When everyone chants in unison
to the Lotus Sutra,
the path to achieving the impossible
unfolds before our eyes.
Yeah!
That's right!
It's as he says!
Yeah!
Followers in every district must have unwavering trust in you, the district chief, and your staff.
Please extend your utmost solicitude to these people.
Meet with the followers in your district individually and listen to what they have to say.
Make sure to convey to them that faith can resolve the worries and troubles they're facing.
Speak with integrity and conviction.
Okay!
Never give in to panic.
There is not the slightest need
to talk to anyone about the July battle.
I ask you now to extend a guiding hand
to every single follower
in every corner of the Kansai region.
It's essential to rekindle your own faith
in order to inspire faith in others.
What do you say, friends?
Can you do it?
Yes, we can!
Will you do it for me?
Yes, we'll do it!
There's still a bit of time left.
Everyone, let's sing Kuroda Bushi together!
Huh?
You know it, right? The famous folk song from Chikuzen Province, Kuroda Bushi.
So let's sing!
All right, guess I'll do it.
Sake, you drink it, drink it!
If you drink it,
Rising Sun's
Best lance, this,
You will get it;
If you can drink it all,
You'd be the best of
Kuroda's bushi!
Awesome!
That felt great!
When it's time to charge into battle,
we'll do it like this—singing and dancing.
Let us advance with joy, everyone!
Osaka Station
The 10 p.m. Moonlight overnight train
rocked Shinichi in its stiff seats
on his way back to Tokyo.
Travel between Tokyo and Osaka
took 8 hours by express like the Tsubame,
and 11 by night train.
It would arrive at Tokyo Station
tomorrow at 9 a.m.
Constant trips between east and west
were wearing down Shinichi,
whose health was never strong to begin with.
I'm tired...
But at the very least, we managed
to complete the first phase of our plan.
All that remains is to stick to the schedule
and tread carefully.
All right, let's write a postcard for everyone!
Shinichi sent postcards of encouragement to Tatsuoka Gan and Mitsui Katsutoshi,
the Osaka Branch Coordinators,
as well Asada Katsumi and Oya Yoshihiko
the local Youth Division members,
whom he depended on to lead
Soka Gakkai's future in Osaka.
Yamamoto
So, how about another serving?
Oh no, I'm full! This sukiyaki tasted great after all this time.
Glad to know.
I'll make some tea now.
Yes, please do.
I wish you luck with your work this year.
Thanks!
As you probably know, I've been put in charge of the Osaka branch,
so I likely won't be able
to run the company myself as much as I'd like to.
Which means I'll need to count on you all to step up and help run the business for now.
It'll be fine! Don't worry
and put all your energy into campaigning.
Thank you.
But chief...
I've heard some executives say that you got the short end of the stick. You really don't mind that?
Let them say whatever they want.
You won't know the outcome
of a battle until it's over.
I'll do whatever it takes
to live up to Sensei's expectations.
On January 14th, Shinichi boarded
the 12:30 p.m. Hato express to Osaka,
where he devoted himself to a study session for prospective Kansai Headquarters teaching staff,
whose appointment exams were scheduled for the next day.
Whew... People in Kansai
have so much resolve. Impressive!
At 1:00 p.m. on the 15th,
the first written portion of the appointment exam
began in classrooms
at a nearby middle school.
The applicants came from all over the Kansai region,
including some from as far away as Shikoku and Chugoku, totaling 423.
Everyone takes this test very seriously.
Where else in the world would you find
ordinary people study the Buddhist philosophy so profoundly?
It is fair to say that the spirit of seeking the truth has rooted itself firmly in the Kansai region.
The first round of interviews on this day and the second round on January 29th
resulted in 229 people passing.
The number of Education Department staff
in Kansai more than doubled: from 150 to 379.
So first, I'd like to ask you about the battles you have been fighting over the past 10 days.
Tatsuoka-san, how was it?
I was surprised by how many of our members
can't even perform a basic service.
If you don't practice the basics of faith,
you can't possibly manifest any merit.
I think we should begin with daily home visits
to help members master the service.
What does the women's division have to say?
Hirosaka-san from Sakai Branch?
Since most of our followers are facing financial hardship or health issues,
the best we can do is listen with care
and offer encouragement.
I realized we need to elevate the role of chanting
and energize the members
to ensure the success of individual guidance.
Shinichi wanted to see how well his earlier policy—
"thorough individual guidance for members,"
proposed at the district chiefs' meeting—
was being put into action.
Understood. Thank you.
Ladies and gentlemen, let's redouble our efforts
in the individual guidance program.
By the way, what's the situation
on the Buddhist councils and officials
attending Sensei's lecture tomorrow?
I know Oya-kun is tasked with organizing it.
Shinichi meticulously prepared for the lectures on the Lotus Sutra and sacred scriptures,
to be delivered by President Toda
on the 16th and 17th.
Yes, looks good to me.
By the way, how many of our Kansai members
have access to the scriptures?
People who have
the scriptures on their hands...
No one comes to mind.
All right, let's quickly have
the teaching materials mimeographed.
We must make sure everyone
fully understands Sensei's lecture.
This is the first time I've seen someone go to such lengths to properly welcome Toda-sensei...
The Nakanoshima Central Public Hall
was packed to capacity with 6,000 people
Nakanoshima—Osaka City Central Public Hall
gathered for Toda's lecture.
Still, more than 1,000 people
overflowed into the street.
Toda's first beginner-level lecture in Kansai on the Lotus Sutra's Expedient Means chapter
began on schedule at 6:30 p.m.
I've come here to give this lecture because I wish to see Osaka free from sickness and poverty.
That is my only desire.
Sensei is amazing!
In an instant, he won over
the hearts and minds of our Kansai followers.
His lectures are sure to drive the wedge of faith
even deeper into their hearts.
With this, our takeoff in Kansai is assured!
First, I'd like to explain the meaning of the Expedient Means Chapter,
which you recite each morning and evening.
Toda's first ever lecture on the Expedient Means Chapter in Osaka took place at the Kyoya Inn
on February 1st, 1953.
On that occasion,
the Osaka branch flag was presented,
February 1953—Osaka Branch Flag Presentation Ceremony
though fewer than 100 members attended.
Three years later, 6,000 members packed the Central Public Hall
while 1,000 more stood outside in the cold wind,
straining to catch every word from the speakers and refusing to leave until the very end.
What do you think,
ladies and gentlemen?
Isn't it our duty to share the joy of attending
Sensei's inspiring lectures—
and the joy of faith—with others?
Let's come together and achieve the remarkable results we hoped to present to Sensei
when he returns next month.
On January 20, the Supreme Council met at Soka Gakkai Headquarters
Shinanomachi, Tokyo—Soka Gakkai Headquarters
and approved Education Department Head
Yamadaira Chuuhei as an additional candidate for the national House of Councillors election.
As I've said before,
we need every Soka Gakkai member
to stand united and rise to battle to win.
However, the true unity rooted in faith
is in fact hard to achieve.
For example,
let's say we have a bottle of sake.
One of you men would say "Bottoms up!"
and the next moment
you are all united in that drive.
That's a sake bottle unity.
If this were a women's division meeting—
say, with a decorated cake in front of us—
one would say "Let's eat it!" and we'd instantly
be united in the joy of eating it.
But once the drinks are gone
and the cake's been eaten,
that sense of unity fades,
and we go back to minding our own business.
It's easy to come together over drinks and sweets,
but not so easy to unite for the battle ahead.
We each have our own personalities, habits,
ways of doing things, and ways of thinking—
so how do we bring them into harmony?
I'm sure you can think of all sorts
of worldly strategies for campaigning,
but to me, they're just unimportant particulars.
They're not the driving force
that will determine our ultimate victory.
Our unity comes from diverse individuals
sharing a single purpose.
Diverse individuals
sharing a single purpose
Nothing we do will truly matter until we place the Lotus Sutra firmly at the center.
Only then the true unity of faith
is born for the first time.
It's not about the technicalities
of running an organization.
It's about devotion in everything we do.
Therefore, if we foster the understanding of faith through personal guidance,
people will eagerly jump on board to help our cause.
And that takes time
and a great deal of patience.
Never forget—even in your sleep—that unlike unities built on alcohol, sweets, or money,
no bond in this world is as strong, unwavering, and beautiful
as the one formed by our common faith.
I came to Osaka at Sensei's request,
not knowing our strategy for the Kansai Battle
had been right all along.
Many local leaders
took Toda's guidance that day
merely as an advice on strategy
in their personal struggles.
It is easy to follow your master's lead,
but it's hard to accept your master's
convictions as your own.
Yamamoto Shinichi was different, though.
The basis of Shinichi's strategy
was exactly the same as that outlined by Toda—
they were totally on the same page.
...Such is the situation in Osaka.
Start by preparing for a battle
that far exceeds any expectations.
Tomii-kun, Ueda-kun.
Yes?
I know this six-month assignment
won't be easy on you,
but I need you to become my hands and feet
and move freely within Osaka.
And your reward will be the glorious memory
of a once-in-a-lifetime struggle—
fighting to make the impossible possible.
Both Tomii Rinsaku and Ueda Tojiro
were up-and-coming district chiefs.
The two were selected as leaders of the team
sent from Tokyo to assist
in the upcoming Battle for Osaka.
I believe Osaka Prefecture can be divided into five districts, as I've done here with the red lines.
Yes, I see.
Osaka City can be divided
into two blocks for north and south.
And the remaining three blocks
follow the old division of the provinces of Settsu, Kawachi, and Izumi.
This division is well thought-through.
Let's go with this.
As for the assignments...
All right, Tomii-kun, let's put you
in charge of the first precinct.
Okay. I got you covered.
Ueda-kun, can you take on
the second precinct?
Yes. I'll be glad to.
I doubt we'd find a better match
to partner with you among our Osaka executives
than Mitsui Katsutoshi-san.
Huh? That overly cautious guy
who's twenty years my senior?
For Ueda-kun, the energetic
Tatsuoka Gan-kun would be a good match.
Huh? That fireplug with assertiveness of a tank?
Tomii-kun, you're smart and ballsy.
But if you get carried away, there's a risk
your youth will lead you down a reckless path.
So if you pair up with the seasoned and cool-headed Mitsui-san,
the two of you will form
a stable and active duo.
Ueda-kun, you are mild-mannered,
but that slow pace is your weakness.
So if we balance it
with Tatsuoka's aggressiveness,
you'll offset each other's weaknesses
and make your campaigning steady and effective.
In other words, we want to create a perfect combination of conservative and innovative.
It's not just a whim.
I have come this far after undergoing rigorous training under Toda-sensei.
He taught me everything he knows about managing human resources.
Chief really thought everything through
before deciding on a course of action...
All right! Now that this is settled,
I'm ready to fight to the death in Osaka!
Ichigaya Office
Daito
Trading
Also, Sei-chan,
are personal guidance interviews
and home visits progressing as planned?
Okay, good to know.
Keep up the good work.
I'll be there two days before the joint meeting
of the two branches on the 19th.
Till then.
We can use this joint meeting as a springboard to let the wave of individual guidance
now emerging across Japan
sweep through all of Kansai.
Eventually, this driving force will form
the impenetrable fortress of Common Path...
That's it! I should turn these feelings into a song
and dedicate it to Sensei on his birthday.
Soka
Gakkai
Sensei, congratulations on your birthday.
Though it's nothing grand,
February 11th—Toda Josei's birthday
please accept this token of good wishes
from the Daito Trading employees.
Oh, thank you!
And also this—an embodiment
of my current feelings.
Please accept it.
Jinzhou Castle
now being built in Kansai
will be eternally imperishable,
subduing all devilish forces.
Is he referring to the legendary
Jinzhou City Fortress in Liaoning Province, China,
famed in history as impregnable?
Yes, Shinichi is definitely capable of building it.
What a joy it is to gaze upon Jinzhou Castle,
built by Shinichi...
What joy to behold
the Jinzhou Castle
my disciple is building
through propagation!
Thank you!
The kickoff rallies
for the Osaka and Sakai branches
were held on February 19th
at the Central Public Hall in Nakanoshima.
February 19th—Joint Osaka-Sakai Branch Rally
With such a magnificent battle formation,
let us extend the grace
of the Lotus Sutra to all of Kansai
and fulfill President Toda's design!
That is our declaration!
Following Branch Chief Mitsui's
declaration of struggle,
it was Yamamoto Shinichi's turn to speak.
The upcoming Battle for Kansai
will be a full-scale religious revolution.
When we hear the word "revolution," we often picture violent uprisings and bloodshed—
The Bloody Russian Revolution
but the revolution brought about through Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism
is one that'll save humanity
without spilling a single drop of blood.
This religious revolution begins with a personal human revolution within each of us—
a transformation of our own lives.
Our missionary work
isn't for the benefit of Soka Gakkai,
nor is it for the sake
of the Osaka and Sakai branches.
Not long ago, our lives were steeped in misery and despair, trapped by a misguided faith—
but now, through the power of Lotus Sutra,
we're rising to transform our destiny,
awaken happiness from within,
and shine that light into the lives of others.
That's right!
Well then, everyone!
Let us intensify our individual guidance efforts
throughout February and March
to bring happiness
to as many followers as possible—
and beyond that, let us boldly expand our propagation and educational work
with the passionate spirit
of revealing the profound greatness
of this Dharma to the people of Osaka!
Just as Tokyo is the political and cultural center,
Osaka is the economic center of Japan.
Osaka—the Capital of Commerce
Therefore, it's safe to say that Osaka residents should be more business-savvy than Tokyoites.
Dotonbori Area
They would never do
anything wasteful or unprofitable.
It's clear that people in Osaka are hardworking
and always open for business.
This holds true for both business and faith.
Think about it: the five morning services
take at least 30 minutes,
plus 20 more minutes
for the three evening services.
You'll also need candles, incense,
and potted star anise.
And then you also have to attend roundtable discussions and find time to preach.
All this for no personal gain or profit whatsoever.
What do you think?
Isn't it a waste of everyone's time?
People often say, "faith that doesn't reward
its followers is useless," and I agree.
By believing in this Dharma and chanting before the altar,
we draw closer to the Buddha—
we step into his shoes.
No Buddha has ever lived in poverty—
and I've never heard of one
wasting away in bed with tuberculosis.
No one's ever seen a Buddha
chased down by debt collectors!
Isn't that right, friends?
You embraced this faith to find happiness—
so chant before the altar as you should,
and let the Buddha's grace flow into your life.
30 minutes in the morning and
20 in the evening is enough.
Candles and incense
are all the inventory you'll need.
When you're asked
to take on a conversion task,
don't just say “I'll do my best”
simply out of sense of duty.
Once you're truly blessed,
you'll be eager to convert others yourself,
then your energy for the conversion work
becomes nearly infinite.
I will continue to come to Osaka
twice a month to give lectures.
The reason I'm doing this
is because I want everyone to be free of illness
and break free from poverty as soon as possible.
Hold fast to your faith and be well—so that you thrive in business and become well-to-do!
The Osaka branch went into overdrive.
It wasn't just the members sent from Tokyo—
Osaka's entire leadership united
in stepping up their home visit efforts.
With individual guidance
more intense than ever,
the phrase
"Candles and incense are all you need"
became the campaign's motto, spreading through Osaka like wildfire.
The launch of the home guidance program everywhere at once
was quickly reflected
in the roundtable discussions.
The number of participants surged,
and new faces began joining every roundtable,
injecting fresh energy into the discussions.
Many members had only recently joined
and their faith was still growing,
but the roundtable discussions let them hear the guidance of seniors and the experiences of peers,
helping them understand the great merits of the Lotus Dharma and strengthen their devotion.
The members who emerged
from these roundtable discussions
eagerly stood up and took on the conversion and educational work of their own accord.
Although the Kansai Branch had focused
on intensifying individual guidance this month,
the conversion results in February—
3,986 households in the Osaka Branch
February Conversion Results
Osaka Branch - 3,986 households
Sakai Branch - 697 households
—
and 697 in the Sakai Branch—
far exceeded January's numbers.
It's safe to say that Yamamoto Shinichi's determination to make the impossible possible
was now resonating in the hearts
of all the members in Kansai.
That's a magnificent castle.
Shin-chan, the Jinzhou Castle
you're already building in your imagination
is probably just as magnificent,
beautiful, and sturdy.
Yes!
I see.
The castle of victory for the Common Path.
The castle of diverse individuals sharing a single purpose.
A people's castle of happiness and peace.
This is where you'll build it,
your Jinzhou Castle...
Still invisible to others,
but visible to me.
It shines in golden colors,
the Castle of Common Path.
There is no castle in the world
more exalted than this!
I can't wait to see that castle materialize, while I'm still in good health...
Now we absolutely
have to win the Battle of Osaka!
The impregnable Jinzhou Castle
can only emerge from a victorious battle.
Sensei, just watch it unfold.
We will definitely win this!
The castle of the people's victory—
the Jinzhou Castle—we'll build it no matter what!
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr, Muzussawa,
True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 1
The End