The great human revolution, occurring in one -
before long, it'll define the fate of the nation.
Furthermore, it could one day remold
the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 3          Rebirth
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
The macrocosm operates with a certain law and rhythm.
There floats a planet called Earth.
On it, in the corner of an island nation called Japan, there is me... But for what purpose?
To fight the battle for the Common Path
and bring happiness and peace to people
It is a battle against the demons
that destroy the rhythm of life
and prevent us from living a healthy life.
A battle against the evil that does not show itself, not even for a moment.
I am declaring a battle on demons that pervade society on this earth.
One we can't afford to lose.
One we must win at all costs!
Nam Myoho Renge Kyo...
New Year's Day, 1948.
New Year's Day, 1948
Soka Gakkai Headquarters
Toda and a few other executives conducted the first service
at the new Soka Gakkai headquarters,
Nihon Shogakkan office in Nishi-Kanda.
Offering Sake
Happy New Year.
Happy New Year!
Happy New Year, Sensei. I hope we'll keep doing what we're doing this year as well.
Hello. Congratulations.
However, we'll be in trouble if we just keep doing our usual things this year. Isn't that right?
By sticking to the same work as last year,
we'll just stifle the Common Path.
Do you mean to say you'll keep fidgeting during lectures this year, Harayama-kun?
Mishima-kun will keep grunting,
Konishi-kun will keep sulking,
Seki-kun will keep
looking pale and thoughtful.
But that's what worries me the most.
The reconstruction of the Society
turns three this year.
I hope that you will make full use of your strengths,
and fulfill your missionary mission wonderfully with a strong and staunch faith.
That's what we need this year.
We'll all have to undergo a drastic change.
I'm sure you all think that you've done well in your endeavors last year.
But really, our activity
was mostly inertia-driven.
For me, it was giving lectures
and going to roundtable discussions.
But outside that, little to no educational work was undertaken.
When an organization becomes more orderly, inertia among executives inevitably begins.
But can't notice it ourselves. We just think that we're still doing a good job, like before.
We settle for this "like before" as "good enough."
That's the root of stagnation.
Please forgive my slip-up earlier, Sensei.
I look forward to evolving with you this year,
and welcome any change.
Do you understand now?
Yes. I understand it very well.
Does everyone else understand it too?
Yes!
My oh my. I'm sorry for talking to you
so sternly on the New Year's Day.
The beginning of the year is supposed to be a joyous occasion.
Let's get straight to the festivities.
Kiyohara-san, will you do us the honor?
Yes.
Offering Sake
The country of Japan is now taking the first step towards its rebirth.
It means the academia will be reborn as well.
That is not to say we must branch out into some new field.
Roundtable discussions and lectures are the root of knowledge.
By carrying out these two activities
systematically and methodically,
we build the foundations for a new Japan
that'll change this society one day
and allow us to create a peaceful world.
In that sense, rather than trivializing one theory by repeating it a million times,
a single roundtable discussion is way more expedient
for releasing the energy needed for the dissemination of the Common Path.
Let's make this year a year of training and development of human resources
through roundtable discussions.
Yes!
Sensei,
everything's ready.
Oh! Now, everyone, grab yourself a cup,
this is a top-class sake.
Let's raise a toast now.
Cheers!
Cheers! To you!
Izu-Shimoda Pass
Early in January, after attending roundtable discussions in various locations,
Toda headed to Shimoda in Izu
to preach in the countryside.
Sensei, whenever I come to Shimoda,
I can't help thinking about Makiguchi-sensei...
Yes. Me too.
It's here in Shimoda, where Makiguchi-sensei was apprehended by the police.
He was already 72 years old,
so we all tried to stop him.
And yet, he insisted on attending
the roundtable discussion in Shimoda.
He was an honorable, dignified, and honest teacher with a strong sense of justice.
The first time I met him was in the spring of 1920, when I moved to Tokyo from Hokkaido.
I was 20 years old.
A month or so before that...
Yes, I was still in Yubari district.
In that snowy coal-mining town of Mayachi.
Hokkaido, Yubari
Mayachi Coal Mine
While I was there,
I worked as an elementary school teacher
for about a year and a half.
Mayachi Elementary School
Essay
Subject: "My Hometown"
How is it going, everyone?
Are you done writing?
Yes!
Teacher...
What is it?
What was your own hometown like?
The Atsuta Village.
Please tell us.
I haven't told you yet, right?
Well, listen. The Atsuta Village
is a small fishing village, facing the Sea of Japan
in the northern part of the Ishikari Plain.
Atsuta Village
Atsuta River
There's nothing there
but untouched nature and beautiful scenery.
Roulan Coast
During the herring fishing season, the population swells to three times its normal size.
The rows and rows of fishermen's huts along the beach
are a spectacular sight.
When I had just graduated from Atsuta Elementary School,
I dreamed of pursuing higher education.
The house where Toda spent his childhood
But my family was in a tight spot,
so I gave up on it and moved to Sapporo
Walking around Sapporo selling miscellaneous goods
to work as an indentured servant
at a general merchandise store.
While working there, I studied independently and passed the teacher's exam,
becoming a licensed substitute teacher
at this elementary school. And that's how...
I've come to study with you guys.
But soon after,
young Toda had to leave Mayuchi.
The year he turned 20...
You were all good, honest kids.
I have no choice but to leave you.
Forgive me...
Thus, young Toda resigned his position as an elementary school teacher and set out for Tokyo.
March 1920
Ueno Station
His first order of business was to earn a living,
Mejiro, Takada Ward
so young Toda made rounds of several job agencies, looking for a job.
But with the slumping economy
and recession raging,
he wasn't able to land a job anywhere.
And so, when his hope was already waning...
Makiguchi's house
Letter of introduction
While working at Mayachi Elementary School,
I wrote a petition to the Minister of Education
that if we are to think about the future of Japan, we must value educators in remote areas more.
But I never got an answer.
I felt that I cannot be heard
if I stay in the countryside
and that I have no choice
but to go to work in the capital.
Considering your deep ties to Hokkaido,
I've decided to stop by here as well.
Did you bring your resume?
Yes, I have it here.
Please take a chance on me, sensei.
I can turn even the worst performing students
into honor students.
I guarantee you won't regret hiring me later.
I see...
Sensei, you are my last hope.
All right, I'll help you.
Soon after, on the recommendation of Makiguchi, the school's principal,
Toda was hired as a teacher
at Nishimachi Elementary School in Shitaya.
From then on,
Toda would look up to Makiguchi
as his "mentor in life"
and serve him for the rest of his life.
For the next 23 years, I have served Makiguchi-sensei and fought alongside him
for the cause of Common Path,
right up until his arrest here in Shimoda.
July 6th, 1943
Suzaki, Shimoda
Makiguchi-sensei was the embodiment of the lion spirit that day.
Is anyone home?
Shimoda Police Station.
We'd like to ask Makiguchi Tsunesaburo, who's staying here, to follow us to the station.
What do you mean?
What is it you want from Sensei?
I could understand it if it was Tokyo,
but we're in Shimoda!
What could the rural police
possibly want with Sensei?
I am Makiguchi.
How can I help you?
You are charged with lese-majesty
and violation of the Peace Preservation Law.
You'll know all the details at the station.
Please follow us.
Right now?
Correct.
Please give me a minute,
I'll gather my things.
Makiguchi had been in Izu since July 2nd,
he held a roundtable discussion at Rendaiji Temple in Shimoda,
before arriving here in Suzaki on the 5th.
Although he could feel
the authorities breathing down his neck,
Makiguchi, who had devoted his life to the Common Path, refused to let it frighten him
or bog him down in his fight.
Thank you for your patience.
I can't repay your kindness.
Sensei, I'm so sorry...
What for?
As soon as I brought you all the way to Suzaki, this happens...
There's nothing to worry about.
My time has come.
Your time...?
When you return to Tokyo,
give my regards to Toda-kun.
The military government,
wanting to wage war unimpeded,
Makiguchi is taken to Shimoda Police Station
on charges of violating the Peace Preservation Law.
saw Soka Gakkai, who rejected to worship Shinto amulets and accept State Shintoism,
as an anti-national organization and an eyesore,
so they cracked down on it.
Those who truly loved their country
and wished sincerely for the happiness and peace of their people,
were labeled as national dissenters.
It was a truly deranged time,
filled with irrationality and contradiction.
Toda-kun and the other executives
are probably going to be arrested too.
The time has come.
The time has come to fight for our lives!
This battle, which forced a direct confrontation
with state power, would probably be remembered as my last remaining example
of admonition to the state.
The time for it has come.
And then, Makiguchi-sensei passed away in prison.
Kowtowing is just another word
for "death of human soul."
In that sense, Sensei had won the ultimate fight for his religious freedom.
He spoke about the theory of goodness
on his pretrial hearing,
he preached Buddha Dharma to the guards.
He kept chanting Nam Myoho Renge Kyo
until his last moments...
Shimomitsukuri
In January of the previous year,
Toda went to Shimoda
to preach to the local community.
Here, here!
In just a year, the number of affiliated households had increased to 80.
Oh, Honda-san?
One by one, the wedges Toda drove into their souls
blossomed into merit and virtue, applied in their everyday lives.
Sensei,
it's all turned out just as you said!
My health has become much stronger.
I can peddle my wares again
almost as well as when I was young!
Good.
And with the increase in sales,
I've even been able to start saving.
I owe it all to your religious guidance.
You have my deepest gratitude!
Oh no, you shouldn't thank me.
It's because of your admirable piety
that Buddha bestowed you with strength.
I'm happy for you, Honda-san.
11 bank employees poisoned
GHQ public health official sent to Teikoku Bank
Left the vault open and escaped
Japan's economy was in its third year since the end of the war,
The new budget will hurt the households
Sake costs 800 yen per sho
but with inflation running rampant
and prices skyrocketing,
The bonito supply is running dry
the economic crisis had become chronic.
100 million people were still struggling to make ends meet.
Thanks to your hard work,
we have managed to make it this far.
But when I think about the future,
I realize we've reached a point where we have to take some action.
Therefore, I want to start publishing a monthly magazine.
What?
Huh?
A magazine for boys, to be precise.
A magazine for boys?
For Japan's recovery, education must take precedence over everything else.
To which end, I believe it to be our mission to provide good books for children to read.
Nihon Shogakkan also takes its root
in educational courses for children.
I think we can inject that traditional spirit into our editing.
What do you think?
All right!
We can do it.
Okay, let's do it!
Adventure Boy
Thus was born the boys' magazine "Adventure Boy."
The "Adventure Boy" quickly became a hit among children
for its imaginative science stories
and adventures in the uncharted lands
that connected to children's dreams.
Toda devoted himself to the management of the Nihon Shogakkan,
while at the same time training and fostering
new leaders who would handle the missionary work in various regions.
New young talents emerged one after another,
and the banner of Lotus Sutra flew vigorously in all kinds of places.
Starting with Kamata Ward in Tokyo,
Tsurumi in Kanagawa,
Tsurumi, Kanagawa Prefecture
Urayasu in Chiba,
Urayasu, Chiba Prefecture
finally, in the faraway Sendai,
up-and-coming leaders were actively engaged
in spreading the word of Common Path.
Many young talents
sprouted up in Soka Gakkai.
And I'm sure even more talented young people will start flocking to it from now on.
I believe so.
Yamadaira-kun, do you happen to know
if Yamamoto-kun, who joined
last year at Mikawa's place in Kamata,
doing well these days?
Huh? You mean that Yamamoto-kun
who had recited the impromptu poem?
That's right. Yamamoto Shinichi-kun.
Yes. I see him at roundtable talks every now and then.
But he doesn't seem to be
in a very good health.
I see.
For some reason,
I can't forget that young man.
Kamata Station (Keihin Line) neighborhood
At the time, Yamamoto Shinichi worked
as an accountant for the Jonan Kogyokai in Kamata, a private organization
that subsidizes small and medium-sized enterprises.
Yamamoto-kun, it's time to go to school!
Yeah... Got it!
Well, if you excuse me now...
Boy, we sure are lucky
to have you, Yamamoto-kun.
Thanks to you, our paperwork is always well organized and our books are in perfect order.
What would we do without you?
Oh no, I don't deserve such praise.
Well, if you excuse me leaving now.
Sure.
He's doing a great job hiding his condition.
I really wish he could get better.
Taisei Academy (now Fuji Junior College),
Political Science and Economics Dept., Night Classes
Eager to learn more and deepen his knowledge,
the studious and diligent young Yamamoto
graduated from Oriental Commerce School in March
and in April, he entered the evening class of the Political Science and Economics Department
of Daisei Academy,
where he attended classes diligently.
In addition to pushing himself to the limit,
he was anxious about his health,
but the joy of learning outweighed it.
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
Yamamoto made it his daily routine
to pray to Buddha and chant the sutra.
And whenever he was called for a roundtable discussion,
he would try to attend on Sundays
as much as possible.
He devoted as much time
as he could to chanting.
As he earnestly offered the prayer,
he could feel his vitality building up.
He felt amazed at how fatigue in his body and the congestion in his chest disappeared naturally.
But at the same time, in his heart of hearts, he was hesitant as to whether or not
he should commit to this faith and wed his life to Soka Gakkai.
Toda-sensei is a wonderful man,
and I admire him with all my heart.
But the question is whether I am ready to devote my entire life to Soka Gakkai.
If I do, that would mean my future is going to be filled with hardships,
due to how great the cause of the Common Path is.
Will I really be able to persevere through it?
Hey.
Hello. How are you?
Good.
Please come in.
It's a nice day, Yamamoto-kun.
Why don't we go outside?
We're currently recruiting students
for the 7th Lotus Sutra course of lectures.
Why don't you join, Yamamoto-kun?
I'll give you a recommendation.
Is it Toda-sensei
who's giving this lecture?
Yes, that's right.
Sensei's lecture...
I'd like to hear that.
Investigation into Showa Denko
A major scandal has erupted
involving Showa Denko, a key player in the chemical fertilizer industry,
Scandal reaches new stage as Vice President is accused of bribery and loan fraud
with charges of bribery
leveled against the entire political, business, and government establishment.
It revealed how corrupt and debased
the top-level politicians
and officials who should be leading Japan were.
The people, who had high hopes for postwar democratic politics,
were overcome with indignation and helplessness.
Prime Minister's Residence
In the wake of this incident,
the cabinet resigned.
Furthermore, the former Prime Minister Ashida himself was arrested.
Cabinet resigns today, next administration to be elected by Democratic Party of Japan
Appointed at the company's request
Sensei, you taught us that the root of all evil is false religion.
But how can we eradicate the kind of evil
like in the Showa Denko incident?
7th Lotus Sutra Lecture
That's an interesting question.
Let's ponder it together tonight.
What do you guys think we should do?
Toda's course of lectures on the Lotus Sutra
consisted of nine sessions,
but it was this seventh lecture that was the most lively and garnered the most attention.
On this day, the lecture ended early
and a questions session began.
Any ideas, Yoshikawa-kun?
Yes. I believe, we have no choice but to spread the Common Path.
In any case, this time
the whole thing is just too inexcusable.
They take us all for fools!
And even if we are fighting now to eradicate these social evils...
I can't help but think that this is the same as waiting for the cows to come home.
"Waiting for the cows to come home?"
Are you saying that the grazing cows have no hope of ever finding their way home?
Yoshikawa-kun, are you saying
that all hope is lost?
Because as for me,
I will never stop hoping.
They secretly give or receive bribes in the form of money or goods
to benefit themselves and only themselves.
Social evils like this one, the bribery,
have been going on for thousands of years,
pretty much for as long
as the human society exists.
Edo Castle
Many a good-hearted, righteous people made determined attempts to eradicate this evil
The "Kyoho Reforms" by the eighth shogun, Tokugawa Yoshimune, during the Edo period
by imposing legal sanctions, providing moral education, and even reforming
The Tenpo Reforms by Senior Councilor Mizuno Tadakuni
the established social and political structures.
But as the recent incident shows,
the effect of all those precedents had been null.
Between then and now,
nothing had changed in people's minds.
But why is it so?
Why doesn't anything seem to work?
Can anyone tell us?
He's here too.
It appears nobody is ready
to answer that yet.
Let me tell you, then.
The reason for that is because the human greed is limitless,
and it only ever keeps growing deeper and bigger, like an insatiable whirlpool.
Materialistic desires,
desire for power,
desire to dominate.
At the same time, we are also becoming more and more indiscriminate
in choosing the means for obtaining our goals.
After all, be it society or politics,
it's just ordinary people who serve as its gears.
So what do you think happens when a human being,
ruled by desire,
sits at the center of all this?
Nothing good, that's for sure.
Anyone can lament that society is bad,
politics are bad, the list goes on.
But we won't do that!
Instead, we must always think ahead - what can we do to eliminate and rectify these evils?
Here's what I want to tell you:
Society, politics, and so forth
all originate from the human soul.
If it emanates from life, then it's the man himself who must change first.
Instead of letting your desires drag you down,
learning to exert control over them
is what we must aspire for.
It's about making it our heart's desire
to work and serve the people in good faith.
It's about reforming our view of life.
From a revolution of thought to human revolution. And we can do that!
It is only possible through Nichiren Daishonin's great philosophy of life.
Right now, there are people in Japan
who are calling for a political revolution, and a social revolution. But as you know,
French Revolution
in the French Revolution,
Russian Revolution,
Russian Revolution
or even our homegrown Meiji Restoration,
Meiji Restoration Reforms
weren't they all bloody revolutions,
in which millions of precious lives were sacrificed to the millstone of civil strife?
What we need now is a religious revolution.
Namely, a bloodless, peaceful revolution, grounded in hearing and being heard,
which places the sanctity of life above all,
as taught by the Buddha Dharma.
And the foundation for that religious revolution is the human revolution.
The transformation of life itself
within a single human being.
In other words, it's a human revolution
that happens in each and every one of you here.
It's part and parcel of religious revolution,
and it's where everything starts.
A human revolution
in each and every one...
I see!
That's the end of my indecision.
Toda-sensei is inseparable from Soka Gakkai.
I'll follow him decisively,
no matter where he leads us.
For my own human revolution...
On this night, Yamamoto Shinichi wrote the following in his diary
Ah... I have encountered the profound and infinite truth of the Lotus Sutra, and now I know that I am blessed.
Toda-sensei truly is the teacher of mankind.
A world in turmoil.
Who will absolve society and people?
The mission of Soka Gakkai is crucial.
Only if Soka Gakkai makes steady progress, will it succeed.
Young man, proceed with great compassion.
Young man, arm yourself with the great philosophy.
I, at the tender age of twenty, have discovered the way to spend your youth most gloriously.
Yamamoto Shinichi was still just an nameless member of the Young Men's Division,
who hadn't had a chance to speak directly with Toda ever since he decided to join last summer.
However, Toda's aspirations took root in Yamamoto Shinichi's mind
and blossomed into a force of their own.
Yamamoto
Two months later
How is it looking for your health these days?
Save for the occasional congestion,
I'm feeling good lately.
Even working is a lot easier for me now.
That's great to hear!
So, remember I mentioned to you that we're looking for an editor the other day?
To tell you the truth, it was for Toda-sensei's Nihon Shogakkan.
Huh? Toda-sensei's magazine?
Yes. He said you should write your resume
and come in for an interview.
How's that sound?
All right. I don't know if I'm the kind of person Toda-sensei is looking for,
but I should at least
take a shot at this interview.
The doctor said I won't even live to 26,
so I might not have all that much time left...
The Great Buddha,
please allow me to live this life
as fully as a human being can, even if it's just for a short while.
The next day, after the Lotus Sutra lecture was over...
Well done!
Well, keep up the good work.
I will. Thank you very much.
Sensei.
Oh!
I brought Yamamoto-kun.
I'm Yamamoto Shinichi.
My resume.
Sit there.
Okay.
So, wanna do some good?
Yes! You can count on me.
I've finally crossed the Rubicon.
However,
I am prepared to give it my all
and never regret it!
That was a moment of sheer determination.
He felt like Caesar, who crossed the Rubicon and conquered Rome with a cry "The die is cast!"
Yamamoto Shinichi had also just crossed into a fateful moment
that would decide
the course of his entire life.
Twenty years old, huh?
I was also this age
when I first met Makiguchi-sensei.
Whenever I see this young man,
I'm reminded vividly of Makiguchi-sensei.
It's strange...
I wonder if we are both on a mission
to carry on Makiguchi-sensei's legacy.
I'd like you to leave your current position
and come work for me.
Yes, sir!
The people were entering the fourth year of their lives after the war had ended,
but under the iron boot of the occupying forces,
they were still forced to endure a life of destitution.
New Year's Eve
Looking back at the past year of fighting through it all, Toda had no regrets.
Instead, in this moment of peace, he was looking forward to the start of the new year.
At the same time...
Today, this year ends.
A lot has happened.
Next year, I will finally be working at Toda-sensei's magazine. I must do my best!
At daybreak on January 3rd, 1949...
January 3rd, 1949
Suidobashi Station
That's it.
Today is my first day at work.
I will work under Toda-sensei
for the rest of my life with no regrets.
To do that, I need to live each day to the fullest, as if I could drop dead the very next moment.
All right...
Let's do it!
And now, allow me to introduce Yamamoto-kun, who will be working here with us from today on.
Yamamoto-kun, please come forth.
Okay.
Yamamoto-kun is going to be editing "Adventure Boy" for us.
Sato-kun, can I trust you with taking good care of him?
Sure!
Now, time for self-introduction,
Yamamoto-kun.
Good morning!
I'm Yamamoto Shinichi.
I'll be working with you from today onwards.
I have no experience editing magazines, so I'm very anxious.
But I promise to do my best
learning from all of you.
Please take care of me!
Thus, a day after his 21st birthday,
Yamamoto Shinichi put his entire life on the line,
both publicly and privately,
to forge ahead
towards the accomplishment of Common Path
in unison with Josei Toda,
determined to persevere through
all the hardships that may lie ahead...
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing & Typesetting
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Collectr
Muzussawa, True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 3
The End