A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 12      Expansion
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
New Year's Day, 1955—Shinanomachi, Soka Gakkai Headquarters
Happy new year.
Happy new year!
On New Year's Day in 1955, district chiefs and higher-ranking members assembled
at the Soka Gakkai Headquarters for the year's first service, led by President Toda Josei,
to launch the organization's activities for the new year.
Will you, Kiyohara-san?
Yes.
Ladies and gentlemen, Toda-sensei presented us with a New Year's poem.
I'd like to share it.
Long is the journey of the Common Path
Let us support and encourage each other on it
I'm sure this year will be even more eventful.
However, I want to believe that we'll continue on the long journey of the Common Path,
in good fellowship and unity,
without letting anyone fall behind.
I wrote that Waka poem
with such feelings in mind.
Otaru City, February 25th
Good evening!
Omori-san, you said
you've given up on believing—
did you really mean that?
It hurts me to tell you this,
but our circumstances mean our path
and the path of faith won't align much longer.
The Omori couple from Minobu Nichiren Temple in Otaru joined the Soka Gakkai on February 3rd.
It's been less than three weeks.
Then suddenly, they said,
"We'd like to refuse your faith."
Concerned, Azuma,
the head of the Otaru Group,
Narakawa Group's head,
and Kutani Group's head—who introduced the Omori couple to Soka Gakkai—
rushed over to find out why.
Please tell us, Omori-san.
You were revealed the great truth to kick-start your precious new life, so why refuse it now?
What's the reason?
No particular reason—
I was never that religious to begin with.
But Kutani-san was so enthusiastic
that I got caught up in it.
Doesn't matter!
I said I don't want it, and I mean it!
Good evening!
Aren't these the monks of Myoryu Temple?
The older one is the abbot, Muraki Keizan.
The younger one must be Deguchi Keinoshin,
who came to Minobu for ascetic practices.
I see—so the Minobu Temple monks
worked behind our backs
to shake the Omori couple's faith.
They're the real reason
they want to refuse our Buddha's law now!
All right, now that it’s come to this,
we can’t back down an inch!
Who are the ladies here tonight?
Well, they're...
They're from the Otaru Group of Soka Gakkai.
I see. Just as I thought.
We meet here—what a peculiar coincidence.
Now then, why are you lot
trying to encroach on our parish?
And on top of that, you push your own
"Buddha’s laws" on them.
You're being a nuisance
to both us and the Omoris.
Push it on them?
Ridiculous!
The Omoris joined Soka Gakkai with full understanding
and were revealed the correct faith—
so what’s wrong with that?
You’re the ones pulling strings behind the scenes,
meddling with their faith.
Please stop the underhanded tactics!
You're a resolute bunch, aren't you?
You just said "correct faith"—
how do you know it's correct?
That's what I'd like to know.
Azuma was a novice group leader,
having taken the position just six months ago.
She had only a fragmented knowledge of Nichiren's teachings, yet she didn't flinch one bit.
You must know that Nichiren Daishonin
discovered the Three Great Secret Laws.
You in Minobu Temple do not uphold these fundamentals of correct faith.
Soka Gakkai aims to spread the Common Path,
believing in these three laws as the root of all things, as taught by Daishonin.
You still haven't produced any proof
why only your faith is correct!
You keep saying "correct faith," but where exactly is the Documentary Proof of that?
Documentary Proof = written evidence such as sutras and treatises that record the teachings of Buddha and the saints
Well? What's wrong?
I know!
I can't answer that yet,
but I'll have that documentary proof for you
on the 10th of the next month. Can you wait?
On the 10th?
Why so specifically?
On the 10th of next month, the head priest
of the sect, Mizutani Nissho, will come to Otaru.
And on the 11th, there'll be a sermon and scriptures study session.
The head priest of Myosho Temple,
Kawabe, told me.
They'll bring along many monks, and they'll have your Documentary Proof for sure.
When they come, they'll tell me about it.
That's why I'm asking you to wait until then.
Oh, I see. And when that happens, we'll have another doctrinal discussion, won't we?
Yes! We absolutely will be here.
This would later give rise
to the historical Otaru Debate.
NICHIREN SHOSHU
MYOSHO TEMPLE
After visiting Myosho Temple
of the Nichiren Shoshu Branch, Azuma
and the other group leaders pledged with Abbot Muraki Keizan to hold a religious debate,
then sent a letter to Soka Gakkai headquarters detailing the events that led to this situation.
Soka Gakkai
March 4th
Reception room #1
What is it about today?
Have you heard that the Otaru Group of Soka Gakkai
agreed to a religious debate with the
Minobu School of the Nichiren Shoshu Branch?
No, it's my first time hearing of it.
That’s odd—we just heard from Myosho Temple in Otaru that both sides
agreed to send representatives to debate
at Otaru City Public Hall on March 11th,
during our scripture study session.
I haven't been informed
of anything of the kind yet.
Maybe the news travel slow
because of the snow.
So what would the subject be?
The Otaru Group needed someone
to represent Nichiren Shoshu,
so they naturally named me, Hayase—
the head of the teaching department—
and the Venerable Kakinuma
to be the debaters for Soka Gakkai.
Oh? But how would someone
from the Otaru Group know your names?
The head priest of Myosho Temple,
Kawabe, just pulled our names
from the lecturers' list without asking—
but we’re hardly prepared to represent the entire sect.
I see...
The signed pledges suggest that our local community,
feeling the urgency of the situation,
was in a panic.
But we haven't the slightest idea
of the scale of the incident.
It seems like a fairly minor altercation,
but when it requires representatives,
it becomes quite serious...
All right. I will take care of that debate myself.
Please proceed to give your lectures
without worrying.
Is that so?
We definitely appreciate that!
The sect's executives later rescheduled the head priest Nissho's scriptures study session in Otaru.
The original March 11 date
was moved up to the 10th,
with a scriptures study session
in Sapporo added on the 11th.
Second President's Office
All Nichiren Shoshu priests in the sect
were avoiding the debates
with the Minobu School from the start
and had no desire to engage.
I see.
This express mail from the Otaru Group
helped shed light on the situation.
But this alone doesn't give us full picture.
I think a personal site visit would be in order.
Yes, let's do that. Make haste
and send someone there at once.
March 5th—Otaru Station
Shinichi sent the Men's Division
executives to the site,
where they met up with Sawada and Sumida.
Azuma Group Leader's House
As soon as they arrived in Otaru,
they began investigating.
Nichiren
Shu
Myoryu
Temple
We know it now!
We know who'll represent the Minobu School.
Really?
They wrote it here.
Great! Now we know his name.
Minobu School
Tokyo representative
Taiseki School
Head Priest Munakata Mokumyo
Osanai Myogi, Myoken Temple
Kakinuma Hirosumi
Hayase, Head of the Education Department
On the morning of March 8, a strategy meeting
March 8th
on Otaru Debate was held
at the Soka Gakkai headquarters.
Second President's Office
Setting aside that Munakata Mokumyo,
the head priest of Minobu
and the sect’s top debater is going to take part,
it’s surprising that Osanai Myogi of the Kempon Hokke sect—long at odds with Minobu—
is making an appearance.
He may have just become Minobu’s hired gun,
but it’s likely that various Nichiren sects
have finally united to take on Soka Gakkai.
Strategy-wise, we must now prepare appropriate measures for every conceivable eventuality.
This battle can be won by us here and now.
Sensei's eagerness is on a whole different level right now.
He really bets everything on this one battle.
Now then, as for the Soka Gakkai debaters...
Education Department Head Yamadaira,
Youth Division Chief Seki,
can you do it?
Yes!
Yamadaira should focus on studying the Mount Minobu Chronicles to strengthen our defenses
and counter all attacks with precise, clear answers.
The others will use those answers
to refute Minobu’s false teachings.
Understood.
Seki will thoroughly scrutinize Minobu’s principal image and expose its flaws from start to finish.
Okay.
We should center the Q&A session on whether Minobu Dharma slanders Buddhism at any point.
The simpler the attack,
the sharper the cut.
Relax, gentlemen.
I'm familiar with the doctrines of Minobu
are they are shallow and childish at heart.
Sensei, who should be the emcee?
I can't think of a better emcee than Shinichi.
Both sides send emcees
to judge the winner of the religious debate—
and who but Shinichi could take on
such a crucial role?
It's up to the emcee to deliver the final blow!
Shinichi, the head of the public relations office,
is in charge of this emergency headquarters.
Keep that in mind.
Seikan Ferry
Following the strategy meeting,
it was decided to send an advance party
Hakodate Port
to Otaru, Hakodate, Sapporo, and Asahikawa.
Led by Akizuki and 11 other Youth Division executives,
they would negotiate with the Minobu side
and rally participants on the day of the debate.
Hanazono Public Hall, Otaru City March 10th
Negotiators from Soka Gakkai
and Minobu sides met in Otaru City.
Concerned with preserving the dignity
of its ordained priests,
the Minobu side insisted this was a clash
between fellow sects—Minobu and Shoshu—
and refused to engage in a religious debate
with Soka Gakkai, a lay organization.
March 11th—Waiting Room of Otaru City Public Hall
In the second round of negotiations,
the Soka Gakkai side
proposed removing the condition
that participants represent a single sect,
instead making it a debate between Nichiren Shu School and Soka Gakkai's Education Department.
This led to Minobu side finally agreeing
to engage in a religious debate.
Those conditions seem acceptable, I suppose.
March 11th, 4pm—Ikariya Inn
It's 4 p.m. on the day of the debate.
The main force of Toda, Yamamoto, Yamadaira, and Seki had arrived
at the emergency headquarters at the Ikariya Inn.
At last, all that remained was to wait
for the debates to begin.
It's the final stretch.
Don't let your guard down until the end.
March 11th, 7 p.m.—Otaru City Public Hall
Soka Gakkai—Nichiren Shoshu
All right, here goes nothing!
As Nichiren Daishonin taught us, we must fight with the spirit of a lion, the king of all beasts.
We have gathered here today for a historic
conference to discuss and resolve
the doctrinal differences between Nichiren Shu lecturers
and the Soka Gakkai Education Department.
He called this religious debate
a simple "academic conference."
How cowardly—to downplay Soka Gakkai
and make us look like a mere study group!
We are not concerned
with determining an ultimate winner or loser,
but if a debater from either side fails to come up
with a response within two minutes,
it may be considered a loss.
My name is Shinichi Yamamoto,
I will be the emcee for the Soka Gakkai side.
Today, we aim to strengthen the conviction that the Soka Gakkai doctrine is correct
for the tens of thousands of Nichiren Shu
Minobu Sect followers nationwide
who have already joined Soka Gakkai!
That's right!
The public views Mount Minobu
as the rightful heir to Nichiren’s teachings,
but there is a stark contrast between Soka Gakkai,
which faithfully conveys the essence of Nichiren Daishonin’s Buddhism,
and the Minobu sect,
which distorts his Dharma.
I am confident that today's debate will make it clear to you all what is right and wrong!
Good, good.
Yamamoto Shinichi's fiery opening speech as emcee
delivered a scathing attack
on the Minobu School.
Though brief, it struck fear into the Minobu debaters and their supporters in the audience,
becoming the lion’s roar that ultimately decided the debate’s outcome.
We now welcome Nichiren Shu debater
Osanai Myogi to the stage.
Let us look at the March 4th
evening edition of the Yomiuri Shimbun.
That’s the article they published, titled
The Ruinous Zealotry.
Osanai, reputed as the Kempon Hokke Sect’s expert debater,
was expected to openly argue
the merits and flaws of the opposing teachings.
Instead, he resorted to slyly citing reader-submitted newspaper articles
that slandered and criticized Soka Gakkai.
That was his sole argument.
Now, Seki Hisao-sensei of Soka Gakkai
will take the podium!
Just now, we heard Osanai-sensei
deliver a lengthy critique of Soka Gakkai,
but without any proof
to support the claims of that article,
it's nothing more than baseless slander.
The centerpiece of any religion
is the object of worship.
It's what we put in the center of our faith,
what we revere and strive to.
However, Nichiren Daishonin’s scriptures
reveal that when asked,
“What should unenlightened people
in this eternal age of evil Dharma choose
They need only revere the chanting of the Lotus Sutra
as their object of worship?” he replied,
“They need only revere
the chanting of the Lotus Sutra.”
However, when I went to Mt. Minobu
the other day, I was caught by surprise—
naturally, there's a statue of Buddha,
but also a statue of Nichiren Daishonin himself!
If you go to Mt. Shichimen, you will find
a shrine called Shichimen Daimyojin,
where dogs, snakes, and other mysterious creatures are enshrined.
In other places, they also enshrine Kishimojin,
alongside Daikokuten and even Shinto deities.
That's the reality of Minobu doctrine,
where they simply don't care what to worship.
This goes against the precepts
of Nichiren Daishonin, the founder of our sect,
who proclaimed, “They need only revere
the chanting of the Lotus Sutra!”
Yeah! That's right!
Mt. Minobu is imbued
with Nichiren Daishonin's spirit of the truth.
For nine years, he read sutras,
chanted Nam Myoho Renge Kyo,
and prayed for the country
and all sentient beings at this mountain.
No matter how the world and Japan
may turn, no matter if they burn,
Mt. Minobu will never fall.
Mt. Minobu will never burn.
We already know that, you nutjob!
Although Taiseki Temple claims
that nothing is sacred on Mt. Minobu
and that it lacks a universal object of worship,
Daishonin’s spirit and ashes
are safely enshrined there.
Whose ashes again?!
Whose ashes you say...
You doubt that these are his ashes
only because Taiseki Temple
also claims to have them!
That's just...
Th-That... J-Just...
Quick, quick!
One minute left!
All right, time's up!
Next, we would like to introduce professor Yamadaira Chuuhei, a debater for Soka Gakkai.
It is an undeniable historical fact
that Nikko Shonin inherited the correct Dharma
of Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism.
Why, then, did Nikko Shonin
abandon Minobu and move to Taiseki Temple?
I would like to talk a bit about Nikko Shonin's
departure from Mt. Minobu Temple.
Yamadaira then elaborated
on the circumstances,
reasons, and emotions
of Nichiren’s senior disciple,
Nikko Shonin, when he left Mount Minobu,
drawing from concrete records
in the Sacred Scriptures,
such as Things the Fuji Isseki Follower Would Know and Reply to Lord Hara.
The Lord of Minobu Province, Hakiri Sanenaga,
was swayed by Minbu Niko,
another of the Six Elder Disciples,
to commit a series of slanderous acts
that Daishonin had forbidden,
such as erecting Buddha statues,
making pilgrimages to Shinto shrines,
and holding services for Buddha.
Nikko Shonin admonished him severely for this,
but Hakiri made no attempt to change his ways.
When matters reached this point,
Nikko Shonin, following Daishonin’s decree
His soul would not reside on a mountain
ruled by one who strayed from Lotus Dharma
that his soul would not reside on a mountain
ruled by one who strayed from Lotus Dharma,
relocated to Oishigahara on Mount Fuji,
taking with him all the treasured artifacts,
including Daishonin’s ashes,
the sacred scroll, and important documents.
Therefore, nothing sacred
remains on Mt. Minobu—it's empty!
Eh? Really?
Earlier, we heard Professor Munakata claim,
"Mt. Minobu is imbued with Daishonin's soul,"
but where in the scriptures
is there any written evidence to support this?
Nowhere!
That's right.
You won't find it anywhere!
Daishonin simply presented to the world
the Nam Myoho Renge Kyo scroll,
written with his soul poured into the ink,
as the true purpose of his appearance
in this Latter Day of the Law.
It is the sole item that allows us,
the sentient beings of the Latter Day of the Law,
to attain Buddhahood in this lifetime.
Yeah!
Yes, that's good.
We've got this debate in the bag now.
The subsequent debate consisted
of supplementary arguments, a Q&A session,
and a final confrontation between the debaters,
focusing on theories
regarding the principal religious image and what you can consider the embodiment of Buddha.
While Yamadaira and Seki launched
sharp attacks backed by documentary evidence,
the Minobu side could only respond with unprovable reasoning and emotional appeals.
With Minobu debaters
often left speechless or unable to respond,
the debate ended in a landslide victory for Soka Gakkai.
It's time, ladies and gentlemen!
This concludes today's debate.
We sincerely appreciate the debaters for their insightful lectures! Thank you all for attending.
Wait, just a minute.
That's all for today, but we have
the entire debate on tape recorder.
Based on today's confrontation results,
it is clear to all who listened or watched
that Soka Gakkai is unequivocally right in its convictions.
I would like to thank everyone
for their hard work.
Yes, Shin-chan.
Good job to you too.
It was a great victory for Soka Gakkai.
This Otaru debate inadvertently made it abundantly clear
that Soka Gakkai's principles will always go hand in hand with Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism.
Especially in contrast to the Minobu sect,
which seeks only to keep its laity dependent
through the authority of its priests.
The Shohondo Hall, destroyed by High Priest Nikken in 1998
It is also evident today that the spirit of Daishonin has been trampled upon
by the present-day Nichiren Shoshu sect under the leadership of High Priest Nikken,
"Kawabe Memo," disclosing Nikken's suspicion that the sacred scroll is counterfeit
which has itself become a slanderous sect.
A meeting of the Suikokai,
an elite group within the Men's Division,
Suikokai Meeting
was held at the Soka Gakkai headquarters.
Sensei, we know that several Cultural Club members will run in the upcoming local elections.
Chairman Konishi and others running for office
How should we interpret this?
I get what you mean.
This thing called politics is an unfortunate byproduct of human progress.
Once in political power, a person
is apt to succumb to its lurking demons
that parasitize on the general public.
That becomes clear if you look at history.
That's why I always tell you: "Young men,
keep an eye on politics, but exercise caution."
Surely enough, some Cultural Club members among you will run in the local elections.
I expect to be seeing more and more of them
in the second and third waves.
I have this to say to them: Strive to become virtuous, capable men who rejected self-interest.
Live among the people, fight for them,
and spend your final days by their side.
I trust you all with all my heart.
Most of all, try to put up a splendid fight.
Okay!
Prefectural assembly elections announced today
On April 3rd, parliamentary elections for 46 prefectures and five major cities were announced,
marking the start of the unified local elections.
Kamata, Ota Ward
Soka Gakkai members
enthusiastically supported Konishi
in the Tokyo Metropolitan Assembly election,
but their inexperience in campaigning
led to a sense of disarray.
Their activities lacked enthusiasm,
which was evident.
Haruki
Both Konishi, the candidate,
and we, his supporters,
are just ordinary people
with little experience in politics.
We have no social status,
no fame, no name, no bottomless coffer.
So what will it take for us to fight and win?
What do you think?
What will win it for us?
U-Unity! Unity with our comrades.
That's right, unity!
Nothing else would work.
It is the unity of spirit and faith
that brings together
Unity of spirit
all those diverse people
in spreading the Common Path,
making the impossible possible and leading us to victory in all endeavors.
So what on earth can we possibly achieve
if we forget the origins of this faith?
The heavy, gloomy atmosphere in Ota Ward
shifted in a heartbeat.
Konishi's campaign gained momentum
with each passing day
as the local Soka Gakkai members,
energized by the solidarity based on their shared faith,
immediately rose to the occasion
to rally everyone behind him.
On April 23, voting day arrived,
April 23rd—voting day
and the results were announced—
Konishi and Morikawa,
once overlooked as fringe candidates,
secured top spots.
They won seats in the Tokyo Metropolitan Assembly and Yokohama City Assembly.
They were the first ever local councilors
nominated by Soka Gakkai.
Konishi and
Morikawa's
landslide
victory
In the second wave of unified local elections,
Soka Gakkai made a stunning political debut
as 51 candidates defied expectations
and secured top positions
in Tokyo ward-specific assemblyman races,
as well as general
city council elections nationwide.
International Stadium in Ryogoku
Following the Otaru debate triumph,
the unified local election victory lifted members' morale nationwide,
May 3rd—12th HQ General Meeting
making the May 3rd headquarters general meeting a resounding success.
We have engaged in countless discussions,
formulated strategies, and conducted research
across politics, the economy,
education, and science,
all in pursuit of national peace and the people's happiness, but we're yet to realize any of it.
I solemnly declare to all of Japan
that true peace and happiness cannot be achieved unless a correct and true religion
serves as the foundation
of human life and all our activities.
The only path to saving the people
and building a peaceful society
is through the propagation
of Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism—
the Common Path for all of Japan—
by our own hands, the Soka Gakkai!
Toda Josei's declaration
was not a directive for the members
but a statement to society at large, clarifying the Soka Gakkai's existence and purpose
while affirming his own resolve to steer the spread of the Common Path in this direction.
His disciple, Yamamoto Shinichi,
also stood by the same determination
as his mentor and made a solemn vow
to fight with him to the bitter end.
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr, Muzussawa,
True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 12
The End