A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day remold
the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 8         Flight
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
January of 1953
New Year of 1953.
On January 2nd, his 25th birthday,
Yamamoto Shinichi was officially named the 1st Chief of the Men's Youth Division.
Shinichi wrote thus in his diary
about his resolve on that day:
This New Year marks the first step in our fight, and it seems to symbolize the year ahead.
As strong men, let us stand up and guide the youth boldly, unafraid of anything.
January 4th
Shinichi's "Shuzanso" apartment
"The sorrowful autumn wind blows from Mt. Ch'i.
Clouded battleground of Wunchang Plain.
Frequent are tear-stained reports of defeat.
The steeds fattened, fed on withered grasses..."
Good evening!
Yes?
Is Shinichi home?
Yes.
I'll bring him now.
Oh! Welcome!
Congratulations!
Thanks. Well, come on in now!
I hope we didn't bother you.
Sorry for imposing.
Sorry to trouble you at this hour.
Welcome.
We're sorry to barge in so suddenly...
Don't mention it.
Please take your time.
Thank you, missus.
Have you had your dinner yet?
I'll get you some right away.
Huh? But that's...
Well, why not?
Let's all eat some sukiyaki.
Yes, as long as you don't mind!
I believe I saw you
reading something earlier...
Doi Bansui's poems?
Yes.
I was reading "Stars Fall on Wuzhang Plains in the Autumn Wind."
"Stars Fall on Wuzhang Plains in the Autumn Wind"
That's quite the title...
But it's actually great.
Set in the Three Kingdoms era,
it vividly captures the emotions of Zhuge Liang.
Zhuge Liang, Prime Minister of Shu Han during the Three Kingdoms period in China
I feel he shares a spiritual kinship with Toda-sensei,
who stood firmly alone in his pursuit
of the Common Path.
Actually, Group Leader Yamamoto,
this poem was set to music and named
"Song of Wuzhang Plains."
Huh! Really?
Do you know it?
Yeah.
In that case, let’s all learn the song now
and perform it for President Toda at tomorrow’s New Year’s party.
I'm sure he'll be pleased!
He's good!
Did you like it?
Is it our turn?
Okay...
We'll sing!
The sorrowful autumn wind
blows from Mt. Ch'i.
Clouded battleground
of Wunchang Plain.
Frequent are tear-stained
reports of defeat.
The steeds fattened, fed on withered grasses,
The banners of the Shu army
have lost their luster.
Drums and horns now fell silent.
The Regent is deathly ill.
The Regent is deathly ill...
This poem, "Song of the Wuzhang Plains,"
expresses Zhuge Liang's anguish as he neared death.
Yet, I can't help but hear Zhuge Liang's bitter voice in it,
crying out to the heavens and lamenting upon the earth.
It must have been agonizing...
However, it's not this sentimentality in Zhuge Liang's emotions that truly resonates with me.
It's the duty and the pain of those who are aware of their mission and stand firm in it.
Zhuge Liang had a mission
that he had to accomplish no matter what.
The tears I just shed unintentionally came because Zhuge Liang's unwavering resolve
to fulfill his mission
struck a deep chord within me.
What does it mean to be a Prime Minister?
It means dedicating your life to your mission,
even in your sleep,
just as we do in fulfilling Daishonin's will.
In other words,
if the main trunk were to fall,
what would become
of Nichiren Daishonin's Buddhism?
I'm flesh and blood too.
Now, after being confined
in that harsh prison for two years,
my body is beginning to ache
in all sorts of places.
If I was to fall now,
what would become of the Common Path?
But I can't fall just yet!
I can't take a break even if I wanted to!
In the dead of autumn night
on Wuzhang Plain,
The wind howls and the dew weeps.
Limpid is the Milky Way,
high are the stars,
Enveloped with mystic hues.
Heaven and earth glimmering,
Myriad thoughts fill our hearts.
Thousand years fill our hearts,
Yet remains high the renown
of Zhuge Liang.
of Zhuge Liang...
It is at this last passage
that Zhuge Liang finally meets his death.
Sadly, this poem sings about the failure of a mission.
Zhuge Liang's name will undoubtedly be remembered for thousands of years to come.
But a failure is a failure.
While we may forgive Zhuge Liang for the failure of his mission,
I cannot extend the same grace to myself.
If the great cause of the Common Path fails,
humanity's future will be shrouded in darkness!
Regardless of how difficult or painful it becomes, or what others may say,
I must dedicate my life solely
to the mission of the Common Path.
Now, let's sing it once more!
January 6th
Youth Division Chiefs Inauguration Ceremony
The flag is awarded to the 1st Men's Youth Division Chief,
Yamamoto Shinichi!
Okay!
Take good care of it!
I will!
As the group closest to President Toda-sensei,
it's our responsibility
to act directly under his orders.
That's the Youth Division's mission.
Shinichi is finally leading
the Men’s Youth Division himself...
The time to keep him close to me is over.
Apparently, Daito Trading also stands firmly on its feet now.
The time has come to let Shinichi
work for Soka Gakkai to his heart's content.
It was Shinichi
who propped our business up
until it was back on its feet.
And he handled it splendidly.
This time, I'm sending him to shoulder the weight of the entire Common Path cause.
No matter the challenges ahead, we are committed to standing by President Toda's side
in unwavering faith and unity
until the day Common Path is realized!
Without a bearer of the Dharma around,
any mystic law is just a lifeless matter.
The realization of the Common Path
isn't some abstract event of a distant future;
it’s shaped at this very moment
by the strength of our determination!
I hope and trust that each one of you
will rise to the occasion
and soar high into the limitless future
of the Common Path!
Thus, Toda let go of Yamamoto Shinichi,
allowing him to step into the forefront of the Common Path.
With the ideal of building a peaceful society in his heart,
Shinichi soared into the boundless sky.
In February, NHK launched its television broadcasting on a full scale.
The age of television had begun.
Next, commercial broadcasters began to emerge, starting with Nippon TV.
The television experienced a boom in popularity, riding on the wave of the pro-wrestling craze.
Also in February, Prime Minister Yoshida made the "stupid idiot" remark in the Diet.
Prime Minister's responds: "stupid idiot"
Three factions suddenly solidify, demanding a punishment for prime minister
A motion to censure the Prime Minister arose,
and due to factional infighting within the Liberal Party,
an unexpected vote of no confidence
in the cabinet passed;
Motion of no confidence finally passed with 229 votes against 111 votes
the House of Representatives was dissolved.
The world, too, was undergoing significant upheavals.
In March, Soviet Supreme Chairman Stalin dies.
Stalin finally dies
3:50 in the morning, Japan time
In his inaugural address, Stalin's successor
Malenkov declares to the world
Malenkov on the Red Throne
Stalin's successor chosen
that "the Soviet Union seeks peace."
Leaders of the United States and other Western nations
The U.S. prepares for contingencies
Continuing rearmament plans is inevitable
were unable to verify the true intent of this statement and viewed it with a grain of salt.
Men's Division 1st Leaders Meeting
Shinichi, who had earned his teacher's trust and leaped to the forefront of the Common Path,
Group leader's home visit
worked day and night to bolster his group and promote the spread of the teachings.
Koiwa Branch Leaders Meeting
Until, eventually, he became the driving force behind the division, amplifying its activities.
Lecture on Scriptures in Kawagoe, Saitama
March Men's Youth Division Meeting
And now...
I will announce the conversion results
for each group from the Men’s Youth Division.
Group 1 - 55 households.
Group 2 - 27 households.
Group 3 - 19 households.
Group 4 - 20 households.
Yamamoto Shinichi lived up to his mentor's expectations, with his group's conversion efforts
yielding far more results than those of the other four groups in the Men's Division.
In early April,
Taoka Haruko, a female branch chief of the Bunkyo Branch,
Soka Gakkai Ichigaya Office
visited Toda at his Ichigaya office to seek guidance.
The Bunkyo Branch had been struggling with conversions over the past few months.
It was the lowest-ranked branch in terms of performance out of the sixteen.
I have long aspired to contribute to the cause of the Common Path.
But no matter what I do...
We simply can't make it work.
When I reflect on it, all I can think about
is my own lack of ability to blame.
I'm just a hindrance to the Bunkyo Branch!
All right. No need to cry any more.
I want to support Bunkyo,
but I can't go to Bunkyo all the time.
Instead, why don't I send my trusted confidant,
Yamamoto Shinichi, to assist you?
How does that sound?
If only it's possible...
Do you really want me to do it?
Absolutely! If only possible...
But what kind of person is Yamamoto going to be?
I've heard of Youth Division Chief Seki and Men's Youth Division Chief Yamagiwa, but not him...
Shinichi turns 25 this year, and for someone his age, he's frighteningly impressive.
He can be trusted without question.
Got it.
He's a man quite unlike
anyone you've ever met.
Because a part of him
will always remain in my heart.
If it's someone whom Sensei trusts so deeply at just 25 years old...
By the way, how’s your husband doing?
Has his business picked up?
Yeah... He's hanging in there
and giving it his all...
If only my husband had supported me,
this wouldn't have happened.
Even now, he won't do anything for Soka Gakkai beyond chanting the prayer three times a day...
Please be at ease, Taoka-san. We'll have it all figured out by the end of this month.
Yes... Got it!
Thank you so much!
Kanda Education Hall
Education Hall
April 19: 1st General Meeting of the Men's Youth Division
A year and a half has passed since the inaugural general meeting of the Men's Youth Division.
Initially formed with only 160 members,
it now expanded to 2,000 members.
The elite 700 of them gathered
for the general meeting on this day.
After several young people presented their research on social problems and contradictions...
The ongoing debate of capitalism versus communism touches on politics,
as well as the economy,
and your standing in society.
From my point of view,
you are free to go either way.
The Buddhist philosophy of life that we study
isn't simply another ideology like communism or capitalism.
Those are the most profound philosophies that drive the world's ideas and science forward,
paving the way
for a brighter future.
Therefore, you, my friends,
are already the world leaders!
I want you to remember that at all times!
The next day, on April 20th,
it was announced that Seki, Yamagiwa, and other Youth Division Leaders
would be reassigned to the Kamata Branch,
with Yamamoto Shinichi
assuming the role of deputy chief of the Bunkyo Branch.
This time, I will serve
as the acting branch chief...
All according to my New Year's resolve
to spend this year fighting.
I must keep moving forward!
Zoshigaya, Bunkyo Ward
Taoka
Bunkyo Branch Group Leaders Meeting
Good evening!
Pardon the intrusion!
Sorry! I ended up going around in circles.
I thought I'm looking for a big house.
But your house was way in the back.
Finding it was no easy task.
Nam-Myoho-Renge-Kyo...
The voices are out of sync, reflecting the lack of unity within the Bunkyo Branch.
The key to any battle is making sure everyone is breathing in harmony.
Victory or defeat may be just a chant away.
Only when everyone’s breaths are in sync
does your collective strength
become greater than the sum of its parts.
It can become a formidable force,
one you never realized you had within you.
Let's start by converting 200 households in Bunkyo.
Huh! 200 households?
Yes. 200 households.
How on earth can we do that when the highest we’ve ever reached is 80 households in a month?
Don't you worry. Just follow my lead,
and we'll do it in no time.
Let's approach this with a light heart
and a smile on our faces.
The key to everything is taking it easy.
First, allow me to introduce myself.
And then I'd like to talk to each of you individually.
Nice to meet you.
I'm Yamamoto Shinichi,
a 25-year-old from Omori in Ota Ward.
I joined on August 24, 1947, and I’ve been with the organization for five and a half years.
Huh?
I currently hold the position of the 1st Director of the Men's Youth Group
and serve as an Assistant Professor in the Education Department.
My primary occupation
is Sales Manager at Daito Trading.
But I'm still young,
so I hope to learn from you.
Yes! Certainly!
This man... Is unlike all the previous managers they sent!
He's so remarkably polite...
To think Soka Gakkai had someone like him!
The branch chief is Taoka Haruko-san...
Married to Kinichi-san,
the group leader,
who also runs a rice store?
Is he present today?
Y-Yes, it's me.
So you were Taoka-san's husband?
I apologize for not greeting you earlier.
I also believe I'll be bothering you again soon,
so thank you for your understanding.
S-Sure...
The branch Women's Division Chief
is Matsui Tokiko-san?
Yes, it's me.
Nice to meet you.
Your branch is in better shape
than I anticipated.
With so many people, there's no way
we fail to reach our target.
I have full confidence.
From now on, we must tackle our conversion activities with a fundamental
and serious approach,
Branch Chief Taoka.
Got it.
Then, let's get the next month's activities plan out of the way first.
Have you held the branch executive meeting yet?
No, I was planning to schedule it today.
I see. The branch executive meeting is perfect for getting everyone's breathing in sync.
Our work cannot progress
until we deal with that.
How about we hold branch executive meetings
twice a month for a while
to help the branch pick up pace?
All right.
No objections, everyone?
Yes!
Good! It's settled, then!
When should we do it?
How about the 16th? It's Saturday,
so it'll be easier for everyone to get together.
Is everyone fine with that?
Yes!
Shinichi is always quick to jump into action.
The date, venue, and even the themes for the conference were all settled in the blink of an eye.
Everyone found him
very easy to get along with,
and a wave of unprecedented motivation washed over the entire branch...
It's just as Toda-sensei said,
he's a marvelous young man!
The Group Leaders' faces
are now radiating happiness.
We'll do as Sensei said
and will follow him unquestioningly!
The Suikokai, the Youth Division's human resource development group, continued to hold
regular meetings
as its membership steadily grew.
They've also finally reached
the part in Suikoden
where Song Jiang is chosen
as the leader of the Mount Liang band.
How did Song Jiang, a man who began his career as a low-ranking local official,
end up being recognized as the leader of their group?
Can anyone explain that to us?
Yes, sir. Song Jiang
is a man of spotless integrity.
That earned him the trust of his peers
and in due course—the promotion to the top...
Hold up, isn't he the ringleader of the thieves?
How odd of them to revere one for his integrity.
I'd like to hear different takes on it today.
Please speak your mind freely.
Sir, the Mount Liang band was strong in arms,
but their wisdom is actually quite simple.
So perhaps Song Jiang's
superior wisdom was indispensable to their communal life?
Song Jiang
Among all the heroes in Suikoden,
Song Jiang is the one most temperate.
I think it's only natural that in a group
where everyone is extreme,
a more temperate person would earn trust.
Good, I think I got the idea of what you guys think. May I now tell you what I think too?
Song Jiang was an ordinary man of average height and had a dark complexion.
Why was Song Jiang, who seemed unremarkable on the surface,
so highly admired by his contemporaries,
the fellow Chinese heroes?
Well, while we may chalk it up to their quirks,
without grasping this, you can't say
you fully understand Song Jiang's character.
Song Jiang might have been unremarkable in looks,
but he had one extraordinary gift:
the ability to see straight into people's hearts.
"Extraordinary gift
to see straight into hearts?"
He had a keen eye for talent,
no matter who crossed his path.
He also knew how to love and appreciate that talent.
When it came to grasping the depth of something, Song Jiang was unmatched.
That's right! I was so caught up in Song Jiang's complex relationships with others
that I completely overlooked
the essence of who he truly was!
So, as I often say...
It all boils down to "a samurai will lay down his life for the one who truly understands him."
In other words, nothing brings more joy or fulfillment to a hero
than encountering the one who understands him best.
Being able to fully see and understand both a person's strengths and weaknesses
is not a skill just anyone possesses.
But Song Jiang had this ability, and that's what made him the general of generals.
You can command someone's loyalty with power, wealth, status, or knowledge,
but that merely makes you
the "general of soldiers."
General of soldiers
If, however, you can understand people and see through them
well enough to meet their needs without error, they'll view you as the "general of generals."
General of generals
Sensei is showing us the ropes on how to be a true general!
It's safe to say that I know you all
better than anyone else.
So, you can give it your all without a worry.
Isn't that right?
If I died and there was no one to look after you,
wouldn't that be terrible?
"A samurai will die for the one
who truly understands him."
A samurai will die for the one who truly understands him
That's right!
Toda-sensei knows me better than anyone else on earth!
On a sunny day on May 3rd, 5500 representatives from across the country
Chuo University Auditorium, Ochanomizu
May 3rd
8th General Meeting
gathered for the 8th General Meeting held at the Chuo University Auditorium in Surugadai.
As usual, the general meeting flowed from the morning into the afternoon,
and the main presentation was deeply moving, with 15 members
sharing their happy personal stories
of how faith turned the tide of their fates
and transformed their lives for the better.
That's quite the momentum we got going.
A newfound conviction
is coursing through everyone.
Right now, Soka Gakkai
is beginning its ascent.
Once you've taken flight,
you can't turn back.
There is no other option but to keep revving our engines, adjusting our course as needed.
Until we reach our destination—
the realization of the Common Path—
we must continue flying onward.
A word from the president,
Toda Josei-sensei!
Today, I want to speak to you all
as if we were having a heart-to-heart.
What I wish for now...
is for you to find happiness soon.
And of course, for everyone in your family to stay in good health.
I hope you won’t take away my joy of hearing,
“Sensei, I’m so much happier now!”
On the flip side, hearing, "I’m still in pain,
I can’t take it," feels like a dagger to my heart.
Let me share a genuine way to receive Buddha's grace.
To believe means
to allow the Buddha inside you.
Like planting seeds in a field.
Field of the heart.
That's where you plant the seeds
of becoming a Buddha in this life.
The seed germinates, and the tree rises;
branches extend, leaves unfurl,
flowers blossom, and fruit develops.
That's what the path
to Buddhahood looks like.
But we're yet to see whether or not
the buds will sprout in you.
If the buds are devoured by insects,
nothing will grow from it.
If you neglect them in the overgrown grass,
the buds will decay.
That's why it's essential to clear the weeds from your field of the heart.
You do that with Buddhist dialog.
By chanting every morning and evening,
you fertilize your field.
Those who neither pull out the weeds
nor fertilize it will not receive the Buddha's grace.
You all have already sown the seeds
in your field of the heart.
Remember to fertilize it,
pull out weeds, and be happy.
Real results take time to materialize—
five to seven years, perhaps—
because Buddhism emphasizes reason.
In due course, a sapling
will grow into a big tree.
In about five years, you should see
things clearly turning for the better.
Take your time, stay patient,
and focus on deepening your devotion.
For the district general meeting, I'll take charge of the Hashimoto district in Sagamihara.
I appreciate it greatly.
We are all very excited to have you
as our Acting Branch Chief.
Ah, Taoka-san!
Shucks, he noticed me...
Yes... Good evening.
Taoka-san, won't you join us?
Okay...
Forgive me for bothering you.
And thank you for always working so hard to help your wife!
Ah... No, it's okay...
Taoka-san, I'll need to count on your help and support
for several matters over the next few days...
Yeah...
I can't run away anymore...
All right!
I'll help in any way I can.
That's great!
Thank you very much.
My husband is helping
with the conversion work...!
Bunkyo Branch Hashimoto District General Meeting
By implementing Shinichi's detailed plan, the branch managed
to ramp up its activities drastically.
Conversion results improved each month,
and by September, they finally hit the much-anticipated milestone of 200 households.
In December, they reached new highs
by converting 400 households.
It wouldn't take long for the Bunkyo branch to be recognized as a model branch,
ranking among the best in Japan.
I was in Hashimoto yesterday, today I’m heading to the Musashino District General Meeting.
With so many talented people, Soka Gakkai is bound to experience explosive growth.
I'm looking forward to it.
Tomorrow is the Suikokai meeting. I wonder
what kind of lecture will Sensei deliver...
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
Typesetting, QC
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr
Muzussawa, True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 8
The End