A human revolution within one person
will ultimately decide the nation's fate.
Furthermore, it could one day
remold the fate of the human race.
The Human Revolution
Episode 13           Surge
Original Work
Daisaku Ikeda
May 1955—Ichigaya Building
Daito
Trading
Co., Ltd.
This morning, before work started
at the Daito Trading office, Toda Josei
was giving a lecture
on political science for about an hour.
At Toda University—a comprehensive university without a physical campus—
Yamamoto Shinichi studied
a broad range of subjects under his master.
Introduction to Economics
Selected Bibliography
of Japanese History
Okay, let's wrap it up for today.
Shin-chan, are you reading anything right now?
Yes, I'm reading Whitman's poetry collection
and Tao Yuanming's Chinese poetry.
I see. It's because you're a poet in spirit.
What about everyone else?
Just because you've gained Buddhist wisdom
doesn't mean your education ends there.
You need to keep studying all academic fields,
including literature, and to learn
from the ideas and insights of great thinkers.
At least because it lets you better understand the profundity of the Buddha Dharma.
Never slack off on your reading, gentlemen.
Okay!
I'll be returning to the headquarters now,
have a good day.
We will, thank you very much.
I'll also be at the headquarters in the afternoon.
Shinanomachi Soka Gakkai Headquarters
Sensei, good morning!
Oh, if it isn't Osabe-kun? How is your diner enterprise in Niigata doing? All good?
Yes, I found a great place to start from.
Second President's Office
It's a little far from the downtown area,
but it's on the main street,
and it's the perfect place for a diner.
I see. Good for you.
Thank you once again
for your help all those times.
One month ago
What? You want to move to Niigata?
That's so out of blue...
Does it have something to do with your factory?
Yes, my parents' company
went bankrupt after a fire earlier this year.
I did my best to find new suppliers,
but this recession has everyone at their wit's end.
I've been backed into a corner where shutting down the factory is my only option.
So what’s your plan if you go to Niigata?
Do you have a life set up there?
To be honest, I’d like to use this chance to start fresh and rebuild both my faith and my life
in Niigata from scratch.
With the funds I have right now,
I could set up a modest diner at best.
But if I use my experience as a chef
and run it solo, without hiring anyone,
I believe I can at least feed my family.
I can assure you it won't interfere
with my work for Soka Gakkai.
The area that I am now in charge of
is centered around Niigata,
so I'm sure it'll also be instrumental
in spreading the Common Path there.
So, do you plan to stay in Niigata for good,
or are you just going there to test the waters?
I won't know until I go there...
Osabe-kun,
you're at liberty to go wherever you want
and do whatever you want for a living.
But when you say, "Since I'm going to keep helping the cause of the Common Path in Niigata,
the Buddha will naturally look after me,"
doesn’t that sound selfish and irresponsible?
At least, that’s how it seems to me.
Believing you’ll get by just because you have faith is a distortion of what faith truly means.
Only by racking your brain
and working through sweat and tears
will you make the impossible possible.
Only then will the Buddha's grace manifest itself
in one form or another without fail.
If you go to Niigata with the mindset that things will work out somehow, you should give up on it.
If you go, you have to be ready
to lay down your life.
Without that resolve,
what can you possibly accomplish?
Don't you agree, Osabe-kun?
All right, I'll lay down my life in Niigata, if needed.
Only then will that yield any results!
It's the choice of a lifetime for me!
Are you resolved now?
Yes!
Good. But let's not be hasty.
You need to get your feet wet first.
And if you're still unable to make it work after that, then come see me again.
We'll try to think of a better solution together.
I'll be watching over you.
Even sensei is ready to watch over me,
a spineless weakling.
I feel guilty. I have to give it my all,
no matter what...
Second President's Office
So I bought the place
and decided to run a diner there.
I see. Good for you.
So when are you moving in?
May 26th.
There's not much time left.
All right, let’s establish a new
Niigata Division in the Mukojima Branch
and make you the District Chief!
Your wife can be the district chairwoman.
Can you do it?
Yes, gladly!
Bandai Bridge, Niigata City
Thus, the newly appointed District Chief Osabe moved to Niigata, resolved to lay down his life.
Sanpei Diner
His newly opened diner
gained a solid reputation for its food,
and the number of regular customers steadily grew.
The proselytizing work in the area
also picked up speed,
with nearly 200 households converting each month.
By August, they were ready to invite President Toda to lead the first district general meeting.
Niigata Station
Oh, Osabe-kun? How do you do?
I’m good, Sensei. The Niigata district
has now reached over 600 households.
We’re just short of the 800-household goal you set for us.
I see. Isn't it great?
I expected nothing less.
Here in Niigata, thanks to Toda's stern,
fatherly guidance and encouragement,
one member was able
to transform his life in a remarkable way.
Soka Gakkai
Second President's Office
That said, these next few weeks
look really busy for you, Shin-chan.
The 2nd Hongo Branch general meeting
at the Chuo University Auditorium on the 22nd.
May 31st-Headquarters Executive Meeting
at Toshima Public Hall.
June 3rd-Women's Executive Meeting
at Shibuya Public Hall.
The 4th General Meeting of the Adachi Branch
on the 5th, among other things.
And then a Men's Division executive meeting on the 7th, right?
Yes.
You'll have to fly across the country
more than ever before.
Can you handle it, Shin-chan?
I'll do it!
This intense effort from Toda and Shinichi
sparked an unprecedented surge
in the popularity of the Common Path.
About that—you must all view yourselves
as upstanding citizens, not just pious believers.
Suikokai Meeting
Any country can be saved with 100,000
upstanding citizens gaining influence in it.
100,000 Upstanding Citizens
100,000 upstanding citizens?
Sensei, when you say upstanding citizens,
are you saying we should all become politicians?
That's not what I mean.
Of course, some of you
will find success as politicians.
But we can all be outstanding persons
in our own unique way,
whether as economists,
educators, scientists or artists.
The upstanding citizens I’m referring to
are revolutionaries guided by the Mystic Law—
individuals who, despite their different paths,
are attuned to the state of the nation
and the people’s suffering,
acting with sincere concern and selflessness.
On June 11th, the second
Suikokai outdoor training was held
for two days and one night on the shores
of Lake Kawaguchi, one of the Fuji Five Lakes.
Lake Kawaguchi
Lake View
Hotel
There are no campsite facilities...
Lake View Hotel
Are we staying there this time?
Yes.
So even Suikokai is showing cracks now?
I apologize deeply!
C-Crud!
Should we have stayed in a bungalow
or a tent, as Yamamoto-kun suggested?
Now, for the next question...
Yes, Fujikawa-kun.
Sensei, we often hear you say
"Return home in glory,"
but how should we interpret it
from our perspective?
There are many different ways
to live a human life.
Leaving your hometown, working hard, achieving success, and returning to hear people say,
"That snot-nosed kid from our town
has grown into an outstanding young man,"
must indeed be one of a man's
greatest desires in this life.
The real question is,
"What do you consider true glory?"
That is the fundamental question of your lives.
Does anyone here know what this glory is?
Becoming the top executive of a leading company or a government minister
may seem glorious to society,
but that kind of glory
is fleeting—it comes and goes.
Fujikawa's parents must be very happy
that he became a ward assemblyman.
People back home may be amazed and say,
"Wow, you’ve brought glory to our hometown!"
but that isn’t true glory.
Even Fujikawa's glory is not in that.
Fujikawa,
you're a ward assemblyman, but above all,
you're an honorable Soka Gakkai executive!
If that is not glory, then what is?!
As my disciple, and a Common Path devotee,
you'll set foot in your hometown
with the radiance of the highest and most enduring honor—that of a Soka Gakkai leader!
It's the ultimate glory
that never fades or diminishes!
Do you get me, everyone?
Yes!
Ueno Station
The traditional summer regional guidance was conducted for ten days from August 15th,
with 632 high-ranking members from Tokyo
sent to 45 cities across the country.
Adachi
Branch
Sapporo City
Marushin Inn
Led by Yamamoto Shinichi,
the eleven-member team in Sapporo
began each day with a 6 a.m. service
at their headquarters in Marushin Inn,
followed by guidance and strategy meetings
and a full day of conversion and preaching activities.
In particular, Shinichi’s spirited lecture
on the scriptures at the guidance meeting
was promptly relayed to the local cells gathered at each base of operations around 8 a.m.,
reinvigorating them
with the energy to keep fighting.
Sapporo city was split into five regions,
with roundtable discussions held
in each region in the day and evening.
Districts          1           2            3           4            5
Sapporo Summer Regional Conversion Results
Many newcomers attended and there was a steady stream of people wanting to join.
As the battle raged on,
Shinichi communicated via telegraph with all the chiefs of the Sapporo Cell
and had one of the group leaders
drive him around the city on his scooter
to encourage their comrades at each base.
Good evening!
Oh!
We were expecting you!
At the end of this ten-day battle,
the Sapporo delegation
successfully converted 838 households,
far surpassing their initial goal of 300,
388 households converted to Lotus Dharma
and ranked first out of the 46 delegations.
This year marked the end
of the nationwide regional guidance trips,
but the success of the Sapporo Summer Campaign,
which achieved unprecedented results
under Shinichi’s direction,
would serve as a model for the following year’s
1956 Battle of the Osaka Branch,
setting an immortal milestone
in the history of Soka Gakkai.
Hm, Kansai...
What do we do about Kansai?
This summer, the Osaka Branch
converted 4,200 households.
The Sakai Group in particular spread
the Common Path to 436 households.
Osaka is growing so fast that it is likely to overtake the oldest branch, Kamata.
To make Kansai a major base,
we must establish an assembly hall to serve as the headquarters for the Kansai Branch in Osaka.
Then there's only one thing to do...
Should we take the plunge and run our own candidate in the Osaka district elections?
If it's a hopeless battle, the only way to win is with a surprise attack.
The key is selecting the right leader
to carry out the surprise attack.
If anyone can be trusted
with this surprise attack,
it’s Shinichi, who will lead us to victory
in line with my vision.
At this point, we might as well let Shinichi
walk the tough road of pioneering the Common Path in the region,
regardless of whether he wins or loses.
To test Shinichi's admirable courage
and brimming potential,
there is no choice but to entrust him
with the vast future of the Common Path...
All right, I'll take this gamble.
We've decided to send representatives from the ranks of our cultural club
to the House of Councillors election
to be held next spring.
The selected candidates are
Chief Superintendent Harayama Koichi,
Chief Instructor Kiyohara Katsu,
Youth Division Chief Seki Hisao.
Yessir!
Cultural Affairs Advisor Jujo Shunzo,
as well as the head of the Osaka Branch,
Haruki Seiichiro—five people in total.
Huh? In Osaka too?
Aren't we getting ahead of ourselves?
Yes, I know you’re all thinking it’s a risky venture.
In fact, I’m not sure myself if it’s even achievable.
Wh-Why are we doing it, then?
When Sensei attempts something
that seems impossible,
there must be some hidden meaning to it.
Yes, you could call it a gamble,
but the reason I’m taking that risk is because
Kansai shows incredible promise.
So far this year, Kansai has surpassed Soka Gakkai’s most distinguished branch, Kamata,
in conversion rate multiple times.
Kansai is where the surge is starting for us.
In Osaka, a city of the common people
in the Kansai region,
I want to start a peaceful revolution that will return politics to the hands of the people.
What do you think? Are you with me?
Yes!
Now then, the officer-in-chief, the one
we’ll trust to secure victory in this election...
Yamamoto-kun, it's you!
Yes. Affirmative.
They put him in charge
knowing damn sure they can't win...
I hope, the Branch Chief
understands the challenge here.
Sensei trusts me to make
the impossible possible.
I should be grateful and fight hard
to live up to his expectations.
Let me tell you something.
As you probably know, our political philosophy doesn’t align with either capitalism or socialism.
Instead, it is a centrist humanism
grounded in the precepts of Buddhism.
To apply these ideals to people-oriented politics, we must enter the Diet,
the nation’s highest decision-making body,
and reform the political world from within to abolish politics driven by internal party agendas.
Japanese politics is currently
in a state of disarray that cannot be ignored.
That's why we must make haste.
That's what I'm saying.
House in Kobayashicho, where Shinichi moved in June
Yamamoto
We have to win no matter what...
But how can we win this?
In the fog of the impossible, there must be a path somewhere that leads to victory...
Clang-clang...
All right, it's done.
Let's have a dinner now.
Dear, dinner is ready!
Household
account
book
Yes.
A great general is the soul of his army
If the general shows fear, the infantry will falter
That's right!
You cannot win a battle if you,
the one in command, are scared!
More important than any military strategy,
you should follow the strategy of the Lotus Sutra
It's not a strategy or a method,
it's faith and a prayer to the Lotus Sutra!
Just as you can make fire from wet wood
or water from dry earth,
proceed with great determination
Be it a hundred or a thousand people, if they are single-minded in their wish,
they will surely accomplish it
Yes... This is it!
The key to making the impossible possible
is beautifully taught right here in the scriptures!
Just like the battle in Sapporo,
if we keep studying the scriptures together,
chanting the Sutra, and encouraging each other,
we can make it in Osaka too!
I only have the Lotus Sutra
and the scriptures to rely upon right now!
During this time, Shinichi was responsible for lecturing in the Kansai region
and made several trips to Osaka each month.
He began his preparatory work
by encouraging his fellow believers in Kansai to study the scriptures.
Yuhigaoka Hall
Some of you may find
the sacred scriptures hard to grasp,
Lecture on the scriptures in Osaka Branch
but they are meant to be read repeatedly and reflected upon.
Without that, you can never learn anything.
You have to put in effort.
The year 1955 marked a major turning point
in Japan's postwar politics.
Headline: Unified Socialist Party launched today,
becoming the second largest party
In October, the divided Socialist Party of Japan, once split into left and right wings, unified.
Headline: The Liberal Democratic Party is founded
In response, the Liberal Party and the Democratic Party
Party Founding Convention
merged to form
the Liberal Democratic Party in November.
The year 55 system
This marked the establishment of the so-called "55 System,"
Party Founding Convention
Socialist Party Unification Convention
and a political system
with two opposing parties—
the LDP and the Socialist Party—
continued thereafter.
Around this time, Soka Gakkai members
were increasingly making inroads into society,
and with that, the slander and libel
against Soka Gakkai in the media
Golden
October issue
Monks across the country are alarmed
Religious
Partisans
Nichiren Shoshu
and Soka Gakkai
rampaging
grew more intense and insidious.
Surprising the Nichiren Underground
A new religion
flying military flags
Naturally, the articles were malicious hoaxes,
based solely on the reporters' speculations
without any fact-checking.
All this negative press
has created a false impression
of Soka Gakkai in the minds of the people.
Culminating in a singular incident...
What?
"The Public Security Agency will monitor Soka Gakkai under the Subversive Activities Act"?
It's inconceivable that Soka Gakkai's proselytizing would violate the Subversive Activities Act.
How could a movement to bring people happiness
fall into the same legal category
as a revolutionary organization?
This is just unnatural...
This is a statement that we in Soka Gakkai
absolutely cannot let slide.
Yes. Yamamoto speaking.
Y-Yes. I've read it.
If this is true, we're in serious trouble.
Understood. I'll verify its authenticity.
We'll take action right away.
As always, I'm amazed
at how quickly Sensei reacted to it.
If I hadn't read through that newspaper,
he'd have admonished me again.
We must be ready at all times
to take immediate action...
Soka Gakkai
First, lawyer Ozawa will meet
with the Director-General of the Agency
to verify whether he actually said that.
When we find that out,
we'll contact the newspaper companies.
Good. So when will that meeting take place?
They promised to meet us as soon as possible, but since the Director-General is very busy,
the date has yet to be decided.
Too passive!
It was the Director-General himself who made such an outrageous remark.
Are we just going to let him get away with it?!
Reading this article, it's clear
he made that overbearing statement without any real understanding of Soka Gakkai's true nature.
If we don’t take a firm stand and refute it now,
this nonsense will take root in the public’s mind.
It doesn’t bother or sting me personally,
but I feel sorry for our comrades.
I'm deeply sorry.
Toshima Town Hall
The Subversive Activities Prevention Act, originally passed in 1952,
November Headquarters Executive Meeting
sparked uproar and confusion in the Diet.
Will the Chairman use his authority to push
the Subversive Activities Act through?
It narrowly passed after a clause was added stipulating that it could only be enforced
against violent groups that undermined national institutions or disrupted public order.
1952 Bloody May Day
What I'm saying is,
when and where has our Soka Gakkai
ever challenged national institutions?
When have we ever disrupted public order?
Religious partisans
Newspapers and magazines,
unwilling to make the proper effort
A new religion flying military flags
Religious partisans
to understand the nature of Soka Gakkai,
are only interested in publishing one-sided and baseless articles,
like "new militant religion" or "they vandalized Shinto shrines and Buddhist altars."
Soka Gakkai rejects violence, especially
as a means of carrying out its missionary work!
I'm sure all of you
already know that well enough.
Soka
Gakkai
Good job out there.
So how did it go?
I realized something incredible.
Huh?
The Director-General said, "I have never specifically mentioned Soka Gakkai.
If I did, bring it to me on tape or something."
But then...
Yes. This article is a complete fabrication
from start to finish.
Well then, would it be all right for us to ask
the newspaper for an apology and a correction?
Certainly.
We must take decisive action.
If they decide to fight back,
we might as well subpoena the Director-General to let him clear his name.
I understand. I'll take action
and get in touch with the newspaper at once.
Newspaper office
I thought it was the duty
of newspapers to report the truth.
Our lawyer contacted the Director-General directly and requested confirmation.
He said, "I have never specifically mentioned Soka Gakkai.
If I did, bring it to me on tape or something."
In that case, what was the basis
for this article from Chiba?
That's what I'd like to hear.
Hey, what happened?
Is it as he says?
The Director-General assured us we're in the clear.
So why does your article clearly state that Soka Gakkai "violates the Subversive Activities Law"?
Isn't this a blatant fabrication?
Yes, if that's all true, you're quite right.
Are you sure you heard the Director-General say it?
If you stay silent, we'll never
get to the truth! Speak up!
Is it really all as he says—
you made it all up?!
It seems everything is as you say.
It was a fabrication.
Then publish a correction in the next issue,
stating that the article was unfounded.
W-Well, we...
Why are you backing down now?
You caused a lot of trouble to Soka Gakkai by publishing material that is contrary to the truth.
Isn't this the natural
course of action for a newspaper?
Well, that is a company decision,
so it's not up to me...
Then consult with your higher-ups right now, please.
Kansai Headquarters Opening
December 13th
While Shinichi was engaged in heated negotiations as the head of public relations,
Opening Ceremony (Tennoji Ward, Osaka City)
Toda was in Osaka, attending the induction ceremony for the Kansai Headquarters.
The headquarters building was a three-story structure,
Soka Gakkai
purchased from the Osaka Music School, renovated, and refurbished.
With a new base of operations acquired,
the excitement of the Kansai members
reached new heights.
It is now up to you to protect our foothold in Osaka.
For that, I am truly grateful to all of you.
Please honor the Dharma
of the Wish for the Prosperity of the Great Law,
enshrined in this headquarters,
and may it bless you in return.
May all of you find fulfillment
and happiness in your faith.
That is my wish for you.
In the following year of 1956, this stronghold of the Common Path in Western Japan
would become the headquarters from which Yamamoto Shinichi
would lead the great breakthrough in the Battle for Kansai.
As I reported over the phone earlier,
the newspaper has finally admitted their mistake and published a correction on December 14th.
Yes, well done. But we can definitely expect more of these to pop up from now on.
The bigger Soka Gakkai gets, the more malicious the libel we'll face will become.
But we can't take a single step back.
Okay.
December HQ Meeting (Toshima Hall)
On December 23rd, as the year drew to a close,
the last headquarters executive meeting of the year was held.
Through everyone's combined efforts,
we have managed to spread the Lotus Sutra to 194,000 households over the past year.
The nationwide target of 300,000 households
has been achieved with ease.
This provides a solid foundation
for our next goal of 750,000 households.
We aim to reach 500,000 next year
and hope you will make it your goal as well.
Can you do it, friends?
Total households target for the next year: 500,000
How should we proceed
with next year's Battle for Osaka?
The combined Osaka and Sakai branch currently boasts 54,000 households,
making it the largest
regional branch of Soka Gakkai.
However, within Osaka Prefecture alone,
only 31,000 households have been converted.
As arrayed the current battle
is not in our favor.
We need at least twice
that number of households,
and then we also need to gather
50,000 motivated followers somewhere...
It's the basic condition for winning.
And for that...
Sensei, are you okay?
Did you catch a cold?
Don't mind me.
It's nothing serious.
But you look really worn out...
Don't worry, I'm not the type
to go down so easily.
Shinichi, life is full of worry.
You only understand faith
when you start worrying.
But that's how you pave your way
to greatness, Shinichi.
Okay.
Sensei has such keen insight into life.
What a blessing...
My life only feels so meaningful
thanks to I him looking after me.
We have a tough battle ahead, Shin.
But don’t lose heart—keep fighting!
Yes, I will!
Raw provider
Encoding & QC
Translation
Editing
QC
WOWmd
Bananas in Pyjamas
Perevodildo
Paul Geromini
Collectr, Muzussawa,
True Noobow Gamer
The Human Revolution
Episode 13
The End